<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="1042" name="RaDromotic" prototype="Page" created="1270757178775" lastModified="1270757365654">
  <hop:parent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <pname>RaDromotic</pname>
    <registrant>pvalera.myopenid.com</registrant>
    <http_language>es-ES,es;q=0.8</http_language>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US) AppleWebKit/532.5 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/4.1.249.1045 Safari/532.5</http_browser>
    <uri>RaDromotic</uri>
    <time type="date">08.04.2010 15:09:25 CDT</time>
    <updatetime type="date">08.04.2010 15:06:18 CDT</updatetime>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.201.230.240.wy84mutta7tn</hopsession>
    <body>
 &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Addapt a library/driver for SMS, like gnokki, to work with Beaggleboard.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a web interface to control the system through the Internet with user and password.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop all the scripts to control the usb or the serial port in order to open/close the electric circuit&apos;s relays.&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I will use S-video, USB, Serial and Ethernet Port. I&apos;ll also use the Stereo Out to announce with a speaker what action the beagleboard is going to do after it received one SMS.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I will addapt linux library/driver for SMS to work with Beaggleboard. I will develop a web interface to control the system vía the Internet with users and passwords. I will develop all the scripts to control the usb or the serial port in order to open/close the electric circuit&apos;s relays. I can extend functionality with a command line sofphone like &quot;pjsua&quot; to call trought Asterisk the home&apos;s owner whenever an action pre-defined has taken placed.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I&apos;m making this project to home users that want to have an inexpensive smart house. They will need it because it will be inexpensive (beagleboard is $149 in http://beagleboard.org/) and practical (download the sourcecode from internet). Users requiring doors opened with passwords throught SMS&apos;s or another device also will be able to implement this solutions with Beagleboard.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I will be using C/C++ and bash for all the scripts and secure PHP programming language for the web interface. The web server will be Apache with PHP 5 and the OS/kernel will be Linux.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <rssfeed></rssfeed>
    <homepage>http://code.google.com/p/radromotic/</homepage>
    <render_skin>project</render_skin>
    <edit_skin>edit_project</edit_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/project/RaDromotic/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <errmsg></errmsg>
    <shortdesc>The project is about to use the BeagleBoard as a interface to control home electric devices like spotlights, doors, shades, movement sensors, extensible to others (like web cams) via Short Message Service (SMS).
</shortdesc>
    <user>pvalera.myopenid.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
