<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="1105" name="BeagleTick" prototype="Page" created="1275104634127" lastModified="1275104634127">
  <hop:parent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <edit_skin>edit_project</edit_skin>
    <updatetime type="date">28.05.2010 22:43:54 CDT</updatetime>
    <uri>BeagleTick</uri>
    <time type="date">28.05.2010 22:43:54 CDT</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <registrant>voidxar.myopenid.com</registrant>
    <pname>BeagleTick</pname>
    <user>voidxar.myopenid.com</user>
    <body>A accurate clock is very important for many tasks, NTP servers are used to allow computers on the network to set the correct time.

WWVB time signals are broadcast from Fort Collins CO, the frequency used is 60khz, there are other VLF time signals around the  world such as DCF in Germany.

The BeagleTick will control a LF receiver the frequency is adjustable from 40khz to 80khz, which covers the major Time signal broadcast from around the world. 

JJY - 40khz - Japan
WWVB - 60khz - USA
DCF - 77.5 KHZ - Germany
RBU- 66.66khz Russia
BPC - 68.5 - China

Once the signal is received the device will demodulate the signal  the corrected time is sent to the NTP or SNTP  software that is running on the BeagleBoad.

All user settings are controlled from a web interface. Signal strength other variables such as TCXO temp are also stored on a flash card for later analysis.

The remote display is a full color graphic lch which shows the current time, TCXO  state, system temp, uptime, current ip address.

If the radio clock fails for any reason the unit will try and sync to a public NTP server. This unit also has 1pps output for syncing other devices which is locked to the TCXO.</body>
    <errmsg></errmsg>
    <homepage></homepage>
    <render_skin>project</render_skin>
    <shortdesc>The BeagleTick is a stand alone NTP time server that demodulates radio time signals that are broadcast from many locations.</shortdesc>
    <rssfeed></rssfeed>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
