<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="1438" name="autoNurse" prototype="Page" created="1300111529033" lastModified="1300111529034">
  <hop:parent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <edit_skin>edit_project</edit_skin>
    <updatetime type="date">14.03.2011 09:05:29 CDT</updatetime>
    <uri>autoNurse</uri>
    <time type="date">14.03.2011 09:05:29 CDT</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <registrant>revisore61790.myopenid.com</registrant>
    <pname>Auto-Nurse (Speech-Driven Manual Assistant)</pname>
    <user>revisore61790.myopenid.com</user>
    <body>
Project
Develop an intelligent device that assists a human who is performing a complex but well-known 
procedure. The prototype device will integrate speech recognition, video analytics, robotic control 
and perhaps text-to-speech to manipulate objects at the command of the user. I envision a 
scenario in which different shaped objects are placed on a table; for example a square, star, circle 
and triangle shape.  The user gives a command, such as, “Put the star in my left hand.”  The 
device moves into a position that allows it to identify the different shaped objects, selects the star 
shaped object, turns toward the user, identifies the user’s left hand, and places the object in the 
user’s hand. The prototype could be quite simple, in which the geometry of the problem is 
constrained for ease of implementation.
Applications
This device can have applications in medical, industrial manufacturing, educational, and 
rehabilitative applications. An example medical application is providing surgical instruments to a 
doctor in an operating room. An industrial manufacturing example is handing parts or tools to an 
assembler upon request. Educational or rehabilitative applications may allow a user to instigate 
the action, for example “give me the ball”, or the machine may reverse the roles and instigate the 
action saying “roll the ball to me”</body>
    <errmsg></errmsg>
    <homepage></homepage>
    <render_skin>project</render_skin>
    <shortdesc>Develop an intelligent device that assists a human who is performing a complex but well-known 
procedure. The prototype device will integrate speech recognition, video analytics, robotic control 
and perhaps text-to-speech to manipulate objects at the command of the use</shortdesc>
    <rssfeed></rssfeed>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
