<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="1645" name="Page" prototype="Page" created="1314993934058" lastModified="1314996986651">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10.5; rv:7.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/7.0</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>bone</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">02.09.2011 15:56:26 CDT</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.99.150.132.14vdf5qexn091</hopsession>
    <user>blog.hangerhead.com</user>
    <body>
 &lt;h2&gt;What is the BeagleBoard Bone?&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The BeagleBoard Bone is the low-cost, high-expansion hardware-hacker focused BeagleBoard.  It is a bare-bones BeagleBoard that acts as a USB or Ethernet connected expansion companion for your current BeagleBoard and BeagleBoard-xM or works stand-alone.  It is small!  With the high-performance ARM capabilities you expect from a BeagleBoard, the BeagleBoard Bone&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;What is the BeagleBoard Bone capable of doing?&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;At over 1.5 billion Dhrystone operations per second, the BeagleBoard Bone is capable of not just interfacing to all of your robotics motor drivers, location or pressure sensors and 2D or 3D cameras, but also running OpenCV, OpenNI and other image collection and analysis software to recognize the objects around your robot and the gestures you might make to control it.  Through HDMI, VGA or LCD expansion boards, it is capable of decoding and displaying high-definition 720p video utilizing a completely open source software stack and synchronizing playback over Ethernet or USB with other BeagleBoards to create massive video walls.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;How does the BeagleBoard Bone compare to the current BeagleBoard or BeagleBoard-xM?&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The BeagleBoard-xM is still the extra MIPS and extra memory BeagleBoard with the greatest USB host expansion capabilities.  If the original BeagleBoard has all the horsepower and USB host capabilities you need, but what you really want is easier and more extensive expansion, on-chip Ethernet, analog-to-digital data conversion and a lower cost, then the BeagleBoard Bone is the BeagleBoard for you.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;What does this mean for the future of the BeagleBoard and the BeagleBoard-xM?&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The BeagleBoard and BeagleBoard-xM will continue to be manufactured and available for purchase for several years to come (no end of life in sight).  We can be confident of this thanks to TI&apos;s commitment to having parts availability for 10+ years for the key components.  There have been instances where we&apos;ve needed to update non-TI components on the BeagleBoard, such as the recent upgrade from 256MB of NAND flash on the BeagleBoard to 512MB due to the end-of-life of the memory device.  We believe the upgrade shows our commitment to continued production and support of the existing platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;When will the BeagleBoard Bone be available?&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This depends on a lot of factors, but it is expected to be broadly available in the fourth quarter of 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Some early samples will be provided to active community members in exchange for improving the software base or available expansion boards for the entire community.  If you believe this applies to you, please contact jkridner on http://beagleboard.org/chat for approval and provide your contact information on http://tinyurl.com/givebb.  Do not private message me on IRC.  Simply include &apos;jkridner&apos; in your comment on the channel.  Also, this will be a pre-release version, so you are still expected to order a final version when it becomes available to ensure compatibility with your product.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;How much will the BeagleBoard Bone cost?&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This has not been announced yet and is up to distributors.  The suggested retail price will be below the $149 suggested retail price of the BeagleBoard-xM and the $125 suggested retail price of the BeagleBoard.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;Is this just a TI marketing gimmick?&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Several semiconductor manufacturers are attempting to duplicate the community building success of the BeagleBoard and have cut the price on their development tools, even to the point of giving away chips and subsidizing the cost of other components on the board.  Ultimately, I think this is a good thing for developers who are aware of this by lowering the cost of evaluating processor technology.  However, for those of us who feel personally responsible for the BeagleBoard, we feel it is different than virtually all of those other efforts and that it must stand on the quality of the technology and our commitment to be a part of the BeagleBoard community, actively supporting newcomers who seek to take ownership of the direction of the project.  We are personally excited about what we can do with the BeagleBoard and would do it even if TI didn&apos;t pay us for it (and not all of us are paid by TI, even though I am).&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The current open hardware movement is much akin to early computer and radio hobbyist activities in its highly collaborative nature.  We aren&apos;t anti-competitive or looking to use our admittedly unfair advantage of working closely with TI.  Arduinos are great for what they do, as are any number of ARM and non-ARM based embedded development systems.  To that end, we won&apos;t accept subsidies from TI on chips, though we do get volume pricing that other solutions selling the volume of the BeagleBoard and fostering open development would be able to get.  We have had challenges with some small groups trying to get similar pricing, but believe we have resolved this at every turn.  We are committed to advancing open hardware for the benefit of all and are seeking to enable new things with the BeagleBoard and BeagleBoard Bone, not degrade or discount the great contributions to open hardware that have come before or will come after.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;Why aren&apos;t the BeagleBoard Bone expansion headers compatible with the Arduino?&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We set out to enable something different than the Arduino, though certainly having the breadth of add-on boards available to the Arduino is in our goals.  While it would have been possible to make this happen and it is still possible to make an add-on board that would adapt to that interface, the performance and cost of interfacing to Arduino shields as-is would under-utilize the capabilities of the underlying Linux-based system and compete in places where an Arduino is really the right solution.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;We are anxious to work with open hardware partners looking to&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
    <http_language>en-us,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/bone/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
