<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="1651" name="BeagleScanSpec" prototype="Page" created="1315489408526" lastModified="1315490821688">
  <hop:parent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <pname>BeagleScanSpec</pname>
    <registrant>donlewis.myopenid.com</registrant>
    <http_language>en-us,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (X11; U; Linux x86_64; en-US; rv:1.9.2.21) Gecko/20110830 Ultimate Edition/2.8 (maverick) Firefox/3.6.21</http_browser>
    <uri>BeagleScanSpec</uri>
    <time type="date">08.09.2011 09:07:01 CDT</time>
    <updatetime type="date">08.09.2011 08:43:28 CDT</updatetime>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.75.15.64.4fvd1kq0ttgg</hopsession>
    <body>
 This project satisfies several goals.
 &lt;p&gt;A personal multi-band radio frequencies receiver for enjoying tuning in many varied signals&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A wide coverage Spectrum Analyser on the cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;And a POES NOAA weather satellite image receiver.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;My development Hardware includes:&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;BeagleBoard revC2&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;TinCanTools Trainer board (1.8vDC to 5vDC voltage translation)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Phillips FM1236F H-3 digital tuner ( easy to get, cheap)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;SoftRock 6m/4m/2m RX Ensemble Receiver Kit (excellent intro to Software Defined Radio SDR, low cost)&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Interfacing to the various receivers is done with I2C and USB.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;I2C interfacing can be easily done with 1.8vDC to 5vDC voltage translators.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Some additional circuitry will provide wideband and narrowband reception for two purposes.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;NOAA POES weather satellite reception in the 137.00 - 138.00 MHz band requires a 35 KHz audio bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A interface to the digital tuner is made off the spare IF out port. A SA605 receiver IC with a PLL VCO and band pass filters picks off the second IF signal pin of the tuner and converts to the 35kHZ wide audio spectrum for recording.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This satellite signal is saved as a .wav file for later decoding.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;A wider bandwidth output range will provide a RF spectrum analyser. The digital tuner 45.75 mHZ output is down converted to a 455 kHZ signal for display with the BeagleBoard. The PLL VCO mentioned will provide center frequency selection.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;This project includes a Software Defined Radio (SDR) that covers the frequency range  1.8 MHz through 30 MHz. Coverage is selected in one of four bands.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;1. Band 0: 160m - Continuous coverage from 1.8 to 2.0 MHz&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;2. Band 1: 80m and 40m - Continuous coverage from 3.5 to 7.3 MHz
   3. Band 2: 30m, 20m, and 17m - Continuous coverage from 10.1 to 18.168 MHz
   4. Band 3: 15m, 12m, and 10m - Continuous coverage from 21.0 to 29.7 MHz

This receiver implements a quadrature sampling detector to produce low frequency I and Q signals for connection to the stereo line in inputs of the BeagleBoard or a PC sound card. 

And a standard digital Television tuner covering:

FM band 76.00 to 108.00 MHz, Mono / Stereo
Low band 55.25 to 160.00 MHz&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Mid band 160.00 to 442.00 MHz&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;High band 442.00 to 801.25 MHz&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;NOAA POES / APT satellite reception and Spectrum analyser signals will be extracted from a 2nd IF sound output of the digital tuner and SDR.

Software:

NOAA POES satellite signal recording to audio .wav file.
Simple satellite image display. (APT decoding)

FM mono/stereo tuner application. (search, tune, store)

General coverage receiver programs. (scan, tune, observe signals).

   More detailed information along with progress reports and images is available from the link below.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <rssfeed></rssfeed>
    <homepage>http://djlewis.us/files/projects/beagleScanSpec/</homepage>
    <render_skin>project</render_skin>
    <edit_skin>edit_project</edit_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/project/BeagleScanSpec/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <errmsg></errmsg>
    <shortdesc>Utilise a BeagleBoard and readily available digital
tuners along with some external circuitry to produce a radio frequencies scanner and spectrum analyser for 1.8 MHz through 30 MHz and 50 MHz through 800 MHz.</shortdesc>
    <user>donlewis.myopenid.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
