<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="199" name="about" prototype="Page" created="1215035644542" lastModified="1217682667279">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; U; Intel Mac OS X 10.5; en-US; rv:1.9.0.1) Gecko/2008070206 Firefox/3.0.1</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>about</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">02.08.2008 08:11:07 CDT</time>
    <prev idref="76" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.76.31.18.1wxc3dxdgdtla</hopsession>
    <user>blog.hangerhead.com</user>
    <body>
 &lt;h1&gt;About BeagleBoard.org&lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;BeagleBoard.org is an all volunteer activity started-up by a collection of passionate individuals interested in creating powerful, open, and embedded devices. We invite you to participate and become part of BeagleBoard.org, defining its direction.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Support for the Beagle Board comes from the very active development community through this website, the mailing list, and the IRC channel. Distribution is handled by Digi-Key, a major international distributor.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The Beagle Board is a low-cost, fan-less single-board computer based on Texas Instruments OMAP35x processors featuring the ARM Cortex-A8 core with all of the expandability of today&apos;s desktop machines, but without the bulk, expense, or noise.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  For some additional background, you can look at
  &lt;a href=&quot;/brief&quot;&gt;the Beagle Board brief.&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  The core team is Gerald Coley (hardware),
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://khasim.blogspot.com/&quot;&gt;Khasim Syed Mohammad&lt;/a&gt;
  (test software and Linux kernel community coordination), and
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hangerhead.com&quot;&gt;Jason Kridner&lt;/a&gt;
  (website and other coordination), but many people have provided a lot of help to get the project this far.  We are still in the early stages, but the activity is frantic.  Special thanks in this early phase go to Koen Kooi and Steve Kipisz, but there so many more people on the mailing list and IRC channel who have made major contributions.  I&apos;d name a few more, but I fear embarrassing them.
 &lt;/p&gt;
</body>
    <http_language>en-us,en;q=0.8,ja;q=0.5,zh;q=0.3</http_language>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/about/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
