<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="199" name="about" prototype="Page" created="1215035644542" lastModified="1385502644663">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>192.94.94.106</http_remotehost>
    <registrant>blog.hangerhead.com</registrant>
    <oauth2-token></oauth2-token>
    <beagleirclog>000000</beagleirclog>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <uri>about</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/31.0.1650.57 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <time type="date">26.11.2013 15:50:44 CST</time>
    <hopsession>192.94.94.1ci20cblul7t7</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;h1&gt;About BeagleBoard.org&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The BeagleBoard.org Foundation is a US-based 501(c) non-profit corporation 
    existing to provide education in and 
    promotion of the design and use of open-source software and hardware in embedded 
    computing. BeagleBoard.org provides a forum for the owners and 
    developers of open-source software and hardware to
    exchange ideas, knowledge and experience. On occasion,
    BeagleBoard.org provides for the promotion of communication with other 
    individuals interested in open-source software and hardware.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeagleBoard.org is the result of an effort by a collection of passionate
    individuals, including several employees of Texas Instruments, interested in
    creating powerful, open, and embedded devices. We invite you to participate 
    and become part of BeagleBoard.org, defining its direction.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Support for BeagleBoard.org boards comes from the very active development 
    community through this website, the mailing list, and the IRC channel. 
    Original production funding was provided by &lt;a href=&quot;http://digikey.com&quot;&gt;
    Digi-Key&lt;/a&gt;, a major international distributor, but distribution has now 
    been opened up to dozens of distributors across the world. On-going funding
    for board prototypes has been provided by CircuitCo, manufacturer of the
    boards. Texas Instruments generously allows Gerald Coley, hardware designer
    of all of the BeagleBoard.org boards, and Jason Kridner, community manager
    and software cat herder, to spend time
    to provide support and development of the BeagleBoard.org project as part of
    their duties at TI. CircuitCo pays volume prices for the TI (and all other)
    components. BeagleBoard.org does not currently get any money
    on board sales.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://circuitco.com&quot;&gt;CircuitCo Printed Circuit Board Solutions&lt;/a&gt;
    out of Richardson, TX is the primary manufacturer of BeagleBoard.org
    products, but all the designs are fully open source and components are
    available for anyone to manufacture compatible hardware. We do request
    contact and permission before considering the use of the BeagleBoard.org 
    name on any products.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The boards are low-cost, fan-less single-board computers based on low-power 
    Texas Instruments processors featuring the ARM Cortex-A series core with 
    all of the expandability of today&apos;s desktop machines, but without the bulk, 
    expense, or noise. Initially, development was targeted at enabling Linux
    distributions to improve support for ARM devices. With tremendous success
    and support by numerous Linux distributions, development has become more
    focused on enabling simplified physical computing on advanced GUI-enabled
    and/or networked-enabled devices with a super-simple out-of-box learning
    experience and support for development environments familiar to just about
    every developer, from Ubuntu, QNX, Windows Embedded, Android and web tools
    to bare metal and even Arduino/Wiring-style programming.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  For some additional background, you can look at the 
  &lt;a href=&quot;/brief&quot;&gt;BeagleBoard brief.&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Media contacts&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jason Kridner&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
BeagleBoard.org co-founder&lt;br /&gt;
Telephone: 713-234-0535&lt;br /&gt;
Email: &lt;span id=&quot;email1&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tara Stratton&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Media Relations&lt;br /&gt;
Telephone: 972-341-2562&lt;br /&gt;
Email: &lt;span id=&quot;email2&quot;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Current BeagleBoard.org Foundation Board Members&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Gerald Coley - Texas Instruments - Hardware design and QA&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Clint Cooley - CircuitCo - Sourcing and manufacturing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Jason Kridner - Texas Instruments - Community manager and usability&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
    var email1 = &quot;jkrXXXidner@beaXXXgleboard.oXXXrg&quot;.replace(/XXX/g,&apos;&apos;);
    var email2 = &quot;tstratXXXton@XXXgolinXXXharrisXXX.comXXX&quot;.replace(/XXX/g,&apos;&apos;);
    $(&apos;#email1&apos;).html(&apos;&lt;a href=&quot;&apos; + email1 + &apos;&quot;&gt;&apos; + email1 +&apos;&lt;/a&gt;&apos;);
    $(&apos;#email2&apos;).html(&apos;&lt;a href=&quot;&apos; + email2 + &apos;&quot;&gt;&apos; + email2 +&apos;&lt;/a&gt;&apos;);
&lt;/script&gt;</body>
    <prev idref="76" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://www.beagleboard.org/about/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>www.beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>dbutler@flomedia.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <hop:child idref="3090" prototyperef="Page"/>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
