<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="199" name="about" prototype="Page" created="1215035644542" lastModified="1215035644567">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
 &lt;div&gt;
  &lt;h1&gt;About BeagleBoard.org&lt;/h1&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;BeagleBoard.org is an all volunteer activity started-up by a collection of Texas Instruments (TI) employees as what is called a &quot;small dreams&quot; project.  &quot;Small dreams&quot; is an initiative at TI where employees with good ideas that don&apos;t necessarily require a large team are given a bit of funding to pursue their idea, in this case having a board fabricated and getting hosting for a website.  The Beagle Board project is, however, not meant to be a Texas Instruments project.  Instead, we welcome those who are interested in powerful, open, and embedded devices to participate and become part of BeagleBoard.org, defining its direction.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   Fortunately, the excitement within TI for this board is quite high.  The positive response inside TI could be predicted based upon the success of the $20 MSP430 development boards and the growing push towards supporting
   &lt;a href=&quot;http://opensource.ti.com&quot;&gt;open source&lt;/a&gt;
   efforts.  The Beagle Board is also very interesting for
   &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ti.com/university&quot;&gt;TI&apos;s university programs.&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   &lt;a href=&quot;/support&quot;&gt;Support&lt;/a&gt;
   for the Beagle Board comes from the very active development community through this website, the mailing list, and the IRC channel.  Distribution will be handled by a major international distributor.
  &lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
   For some additional background, you can look at
   &lt;a href=&quot;http://BeagleBoard.org/brief&quot;&gt;the Beagle Board brief.&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <user>blog.hangerhead.com</user>
    <prev idref="76" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <uri>about</uri>
    <time type="date">02.07.2008 16:54:04 CDT</time>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
