<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="2213" name="legal" prototype="Page" created="1351635982106" lastModified="1448993418771">
  <hop:parent idref="2092" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64) AppleWebKit/537.11 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/23.0.1271.64 Safari/537.11</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>legal</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">28.11.2012 18:18:52 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2092" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.198.47.16.lkkg7flucmyt</hopsession>
    <user>pelochino.myopenid.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">1392.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;title&gt;Beagle Bone Cape Contest Official Rules&lt;/title&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;b&gt;BeagleBone Cape Contest Official Rules&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;For purposes of these Rules, “TI” shall mean Texas Instruments Incorporated and its subsidiaries and “Circuitco” shall mean Circuitco Electronics LLC and its subsidiaries. TI and Circuitco are collectively referred to herein as the “Sponsors.”&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;ol start=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;To be eligible to compete, each entrant must read and complete the entry form found 
    at 
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beagleboard.org/capecontest&quot;&gt;www.beagleboard.org/capecontest&lt;/a&gt; and agree to abide by the contest rules. 
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Entries must be in English, except where prohibited by law. In those countries where the English language is prohibited for these purposes, the entry forms and submission must be made in the official language of the country.
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The contest begins on November 1, 2012 at 12:01 a.m. (EDT) and ends December 31, 2012 at 11:59 p.m. (PST). No submissions submitted after December 31, 2012 at 11:59 p.m. (PST) will be considered. The Sponsors reserve the right to cancel this contest before the end date at their sole discretion, and decline to award prizes if there are no eligible entrants.
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;An entrant may submit multiple Designs. &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Odds of winning are determined by the total number of eligible entries received.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Sponsors reserve the right, in their sole discretion, to disqualify anyone found to have tampered 
	with the contest.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The contest is offered and participation is limited to only RESIDENTS OF those participating countries indicated on this form.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;To be eligible, entrants must be eighteen (18) year of age or older.
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;THERE IS NO ENTRY FEE. &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;PARTICIPANTS DO NOT RECEIVE BY WAY OF OR UNDER THE CONTEST ANY INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS IN ANY COPYRIGHTS, PATENTS, TRADEMARKS, TRADE NAMES, TECHNOLOGY, TRADE SECRETS, OR KNOW-HOW OF THE SPONSORS OR ANY THIRD PARTY.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All design ideas must be submitted to the Sponsors by completing the entry form and (i) submitting it through www.beagleboard.org/capecontest. Entries must be submitted by the deadline to be considered. Participants will not be allowed to change or supplement their submissions once they have been submitted.
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All entrants agree to follow and abide by the design idea requirements and judging criteria.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All entrants warrant and represent that all design ideas and applications submitted are entirely original and that entrant is the owner of all interests in and rights to such designs. This representation is a requirement of participation in the contest. By clicking &quot;I agree,&quot; as part of the online submission, all entrants represent that there is no third party of any kind, whether an academic institution, commercial company, individual, or governmental legal entity which has any proprietary or other interest in, claims or rights to, any intellectual property rights, including trade secret, “know-how,” copyright, patent, trademark or trade name, in any design ideas submitted under the contest.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All entrants agree, represent and guarantee that there are no obligations of any nature, legal or otherwise, which would prohibit, restrict, or interfere with their participation in the contest or submission of their contest design idea. All entrants agree to obtain any necessary clearance or approval from any necessary third party participation in all contest activities and any such approvals which are required as a condition of participation.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;No confidential relationship is established between the Sponsors and the entrant as a result of entering this contest. None of the information submitted by the participants will be treated by the Sponsors as trade secrets, confidential information, or as protected data under any obligation.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All entrants agree to be bound by the contest requirements for licensing of non-exclusive rights.  Ownership of the design ideas (hereinafter “Design” or “Designs”) shall remain with the entrants.  Entrant hereby agrees that the Designs shall be subject to the Creative Commons 3.0 Attribution License.  The Designs are protected by copyright and/or other applicable law.  Any use of the Designs other than as authorized under the Creative Commons 3.0 Attribution License or copyright law is prohibited. &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Taxes (United States federal, state and local and, any foreign) and other obligations are solely the responsibility of the winners. Prizes may be subject to reporting for tax and other purposes. Winners agree to supply Sponsors with any information necessary for tax reporting purposes and to cooperate in fulfilling all applicable legal requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The entrant whose design idea is chosen for consideration for any award, as a condition of award, may be required to submit further information concerning employment and residence. Also, as a condition of award, the entrant may be required to sign (i) other documents necessary to ensure non-exclusive license right to TI, for such design ideas, and (ii) a liability/publicity release.
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The non-exclusive license to TI of intellectual property rights, as described herein is free of charge and without remuneration of any kind. All entrants agree that the opportunity to compete for prizes, receive publicity, and increase one’s understanding of TI products represents full and adequate consideration for license of these rights by all participants. Prizes do not represent fixed-sum monetary remuneration of the licensing of intellectual property and rights in design submissions.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;All entrants grant the Sponsors the right to publicize their names, likeness, any information provided on the entry form or their design idea entry in whatever manner without reservation or compensation. In certain countries, due to local requirements, it may be necessary for entrants to execute, in addition to this entry form, certain other documents for license of intellectual property rights, prior to any publication of the full design idea submission. In those countries, TI will make appropriate arrangements. Entries and design submissions may be published in Sponsor or third party publications.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Entrants will not be reimbursed for any costs incurred or for efforts expended in connection with their participation in the contest. Such costs are the responsibility of the participants.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;NO PURCHASE IS NECESSARY. &lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Decisions by the contest judges are final. The Sponsors reserve the right to refrain from awarding any prize if there are no or minimal qualified entries.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;PRIZES: 
	Total approximate value of all prizes: $1,000  USD&lt;ul&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Grand Prize&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Three (3) winning cape Design entrants will have their Designs prototyped 
			and have at least one (1) production lot manufactured and sold through CircuitCo 
			or CircuitCo&apos;s designated distributor. In the event that a winning cape 
			Design is deemed marketable and sufficient distributor interest is generated, CircuitCo will 
			continue to manufacture the cape Design for distribution.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Additionally, each cape Design winner will receipt $500 USD from TI and $500 USD from Mouser Electronics.  &lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Finally, each cape Design winner will receive their choice of one of the following tools from Total Phase:  (1) a Beagle USB 480 Protocol Analyzer, (2) an I2C/SPI Kit or (3) a CAN/I2C Kit.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Additional third party sponsor prizes may also be awarded.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Winners will be announced via media outlets and BeagleBoard.org.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;In addition to the Grand Prize, weekly drawings will be held in which third party prizes will be awarded.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;In the event of unavailability of any of the stated prizes, Sponsors reserve the right to substitute items of equal or greater value.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If a winner cannot be reached within (10) days of notification, or if a prize is returned with no forwarding address, the Sponsors reserve the right to deem the prize forfeited. The prize will then be awarded to the runner(s)-up for the applicable prize.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Employees and agents of the Sponsors and such individual’s immediate family (including spouse, parents, siblings, grandparents, grandchildren, step-children, step-parents and in-laws) and member of the same household are prohibited from entering this contest.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST SHALL BE CONSIDERED VOID WHERE, AND TO THE EXTENT, PROHIBITED BY LAW.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sponsors reserve the right to use information regarding contestants for future mailings subject to applicable laws and regulations and privacy policies. Texas Instruments’ privacy policy can be found at 
	&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ti.com/home_f_privacy&quot;&gt;www.ti.com/home_f_privacy&lt;/a&gt;. 
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Designs will be judged and voted on by a panel consisting of sponsor representatives. In order to be eligible, entries must include: 
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;schematic capture including reference designators and an extractable net-list&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;bill of materials (BOM) in Excel format with manufacturer part numbers and reference designators. BOM must not exceed $60&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;a video describing the cape Design idea, uploaded to YouTube. By submitting your video you agree 
	that Sponsors may use and demonstrate your video on various platforms and that you will not assert any action against Sponsors for such use and demonstration of your video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Subject to verification of eligibility and compliance with all contest rules, the three 
	Designs chosen by the panel shall be awarded the Grand Prize.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;No entries will be returned to participants, regardless of whether they are accepted. All entries and design submissions become the property of the Sponsors. 
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Where an entry is submitted by two or more contributors, this fact must be disclosed in the entry form. Any prizes will be awarded to the contributors jointly and severally, who will be responsible for dividing the prize among themselves. If there is a dispute regarding the identity of the entrant, the Sponsors reserve the right to deem the account holder of the e-mail address as the entrant. 
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST AND ITS RULES AND CONDITIONS SHALL BE GOVERNED BY THE LAWS OF THE STATE OF TEXAS AND ANY DISPUTE ARISING OUT OF THIS CONTEST SHALL BE WITH ANY U.S. FEDERAL DISTRICT COURT FOR DALLAS, TEXAS.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If any aspect of the contest or any rule or condition be found by a court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid, illegal or void, participants agree to allow the Sponsors to change such provision and, upon notice, to make it valid. Also, in such case, the remaining contest provisions shall remain in full force and effect and the contest shall proceed accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Winners will be notified by the Sponsors on or about January 14, 2013. The names and residence of the winners will be published on www.beagleboard.org. 
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;By entering this contest, each entrant agrees to release and hold the Sponsors harmless from and against any losses, damages, rights, claims and actions of any kind arising from (i) an exclusion or disqualification of a participant pursuant to these Rules, (ii) late, lost, misdirected, or unsuccessful efforts to notify winners of any prize (iii) forfeiture of a prize and the selection of an alternate winner, (iv) late, lost, delayed, damaged, misdirected, incomplete, illegible or unintelligible entries; (v) telephone, electronic, hardware or software program, network, Internet, or computer malfunctions, failures or difficulties of any kind; (iii) failed, incomplete, garbled or delayed computer transmissions; (iv) any condition caused by events beyond their control that may cause the BeagleBone Cape Contest to be disrupted or corrupted; (v) any injuries, losses or damages or any kind relating to a contest prize, or acceptance, possession or use of the prize, or from participation in this contest.
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Sponsors reserve the right to cancel, terminate, modify or suspend this contest if it becomes technically corrupted or if for any reason the Internet portion of the contest is not capable of running as planned, including infections by computer virus, bugs, tampering, unauthorized intervention, fraud, technical failures or any other causes beyond the control of the Sponsors, which corrupt or affect the administration, security, fairness, integrity or proper conduct of this contest. 
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sponsors:&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;table style=&quot;width: 100%&quot;&gt;
		&lt;tr&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Texas Instruments Incorporated&lt;br&gt;
12500 TI Boulevard&lt;br&gt;
Dallas, Texas 75266&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;/td&gt;
			&lt;td&gt;CircuitCo Electronics, LLC&lt;br&gt;
			1380 Presidential Dr. #100&lt;br&gt;
			Richardson, Texas 75081&lt;/td&gt;
		&lt;/tr&gt;
	&lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Participating Countries&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;The following is a list of the participating countries, arranged in the regions in which they will be competing:&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Americas&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;table style=&quot;width: 100%&quot;&gt; 
&lt;tbody&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; style=&quot;width: 160px&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Argentina&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; style=&quot;width: 160px&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Chile&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; style=&quot;width: 160px&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Venezuela&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Brazil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Colombia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;United States&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Canada &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Mexico&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt; &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;/tbody&gt;
 &lt;/table&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Europe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;table style=&quot;width: 100%&quot;&gt; 
&lt;tbody&gt;
 &lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; style=&quot;width: 160px&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Austria&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; style=&quot;width: 160px&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Great Britain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; style=&quot;width: 160px&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Poland&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Belarussia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Greece&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Romania&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Belgium&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Hungary&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Bulgaria&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Ireland&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Slovakia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Croatia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Israel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Slovenia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Czech Republic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Latvia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;South Africa&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Denmark&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Lithuania&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Spain&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Egypt&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Luxembourg&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Sweden&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Estonia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Switzerland&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Finland&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Nigeria&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Turkey&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Germany&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Norway&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Ukraine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Ghana&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt; &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt; &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/tbody&gt;
 &lt;/table&gt;

 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Asia&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;table style=&quot;width: 100%&quot;&gt; 
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; style=&quot;width: 160px&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;China&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; style=&quot;width: 160px&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;The Philippines&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; style=&quot;width: 160px&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Australia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Korea&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Singapore&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;India&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Indonesia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Taiwan&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;New Zealand&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 
&lt;tr&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Malaysia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt;&lt;p&gt;Thailand&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;td valign=&quot;top&quot; &gt; &lt;/td&gt;
 &lt;/tr&gt;
 &lt;/tbody&gt;
 &lt;/table&gt;

 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Japan&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All prefectures in Japan&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Sponsors are collecting and using the information you submit to evaluate your entry and contact you about it.&lt;/p&gt;</body>
    <oauth2-token></oauth2-token>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/CapeContest/legal/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
