<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="238" name="terms" prototype="Page" created="1216302046625" lastModified="1365601416862">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <gpv_p9_o>%2Farm-based%20processor%20platforms%2F%2Farm-based%20processor%20platforms%20choose%20a%20core%20tab-en</gpv_p9_o>
    <ev0>dsps_arm_102109</ev0>
    <rembr549>uid=x0179354|securitylevel=1</rembr549>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>10.247.22.70</http_remotehost>
    <s_cc>true</s_cc>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <wbmain_flyout-products-webench>0</wbmain_flyout-products-webench>
    <uri>terms</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64) AppleWebKit/537.31 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/26.0.1410.43 Safari/537.31</http_browser>
    <tipage>/arm-based processor platforms//arm-based processor platforms choose a core tab-en</tipage>
    <time type="date">10.04.2013 09:43:36 EDT</time>
    <wbmain_flyout-tools-webench>0</wbmain_flyout-tools-webench>
    <usertype>Anonymous</usertype>
    <s_sq>[[B]]</s_sq>
    <hopsession>10.247.22.1b5flbq9ikj0l</hopsession>
    <ticontent>/ARM-Based Processor Platforms/</ticontent>
    <body> &lt;h1&gt;Terms and Conditions&lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;ACCEPTANCE OF TERMS&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  BeagleBoard.org provides its service to you subject to the following Terms of Service (&quot;TOS&quot;).  BeagleBoard.org reserves the right to make modifications to this site and to the TOS at any time.  You can review the most current version of the TOS at any time at:
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://BeagleBoard.org/terms&quot;&gt;http://BeagleBoard.org/terms.&lt;/a&gt;
  Any change in the TOS will be prospective only, unless retroactive effect is legally required. Your continued use of this site will constitute your acceptance of any new or amended terms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The information, material and related graphics available on this site (&quot;Materials&quot;) are provided by BeagleBoard.org registered editors. By using this site you agree that you have read and understood the TOS and agree to be bound by these terms, and to comply with all applicable laws and regulations regarding use of this site. If you do not agree to these terms, do not use this site.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;BeagleBoard.org operates this site from within the United States. BeagleBoard.org makes no representations that the Materials referenced on this site are appropriate or available for use in other areas of the world. Those who access this site from locations outside the United States are responsible for compliance with applicable local laws. Any claim relating to this site or use of this site will be governed by and interpreted in accordance with the laws of the State of Texas, without reference to its conflict-of-laws principles. Any dispute arising out of or related to your use of this site will be brought in, and you hereby consent to exclusive jurisdiction and venue in, the state and federal courts sitting in Harris County, Texas. You agree to waive all defenses of lack of personal jurisdiction and forum non-conveniens and agree that process may be served in a manner authorized by applicable law or court rule.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;DESCRIPTION OF SERVICE&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;BeagleBoard.org provides editable web pages and storage for resources meant for download.  BeagleBoard.org also may host programs, such as Java applications, meant for running via your web browser for the purpose of interacting with other BeagleBoard.org community members.  All mailing list, chat services, issue tracking, and other services are currently hosted elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;WARRANTIES AND DISCLAIMERS&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;BeagleBoard.org intends for the Materials contained on this site to be accurate and reliable. These Materials may, however, contain technical inaccuracies, typographical errors or other mistakes. BeagleBoard.org and community members may make corrections or other changes to these Materials at any time. BeagleBoard.org and its suppliers reserve the right to make corrections, modifications, enhancements, improvements and other changes to its products, programs and services at any time or to discontinue any products, programs, or services without notice.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;THE MATERIALS ON THIS SITE ARE PROVIDED &quot;AS IS&quot;. BeagleBoard.org AND ITS RESPECTIVE SUPPLIERS MAKE NO REPRESENTATIONS ABOUT THE SUITABILITY OF THESE MATERIALS FOR ANY PURPOSE AND DISCLAIM ALL WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS WITH REGARD TO THESE MATERIALS, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO, ALL IMPLIED WARRANTIES AND CONDITIONS OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, TITLE AND NON-INFRINGEMENT OF ANY THIRD PARTY INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHT.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;YOU ACKNOWLEDGE AND AGREE THAT THE APPLICATION NOTES, REFERENCE DESIGNS AND OTHER SUCH DESIGN MATERIALS INCLUDED HEREIN ARE PROVIDED AS AN EXAMPLE ONLY AND THAT YOU WILL EXERCISE YOUR OWN INDEPENDENT ANALYSIS AND JUDGMENT IN YOUR USE OF THESE MATERIALS. BeagleBoard.org ASSUMES NO LIABILITY FOR YOUR USE OF THESE MATERIALS OR YOUR PRODUCT DESIGNS OR ANY APPLICATIONS ASSISTANCE PROVIDED BY BeagleBoard.org.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;BeagleBoard.org DOES NOT WARRANT OR REPRESENT THAT ANY LICENSE, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, IS GRANTED UNDER ANY PATENT RIGHT, COPYRIGHT, MASK WORK RIGHT, OR OTHER INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHT OF TI OR BeagleBoard.org COVERING OR RELATING TO THESE MATERIALS OR ANY COMBINATION, MACHINE, OR PROCESS TO WHICH THESE MATERIALS RELATE OR WITH WHICH THESE MATERIALS MAY BE USED.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THIS SITE MAY REQUIRE A LICENSE FROM A THIRD PARTY UNDER THE PATENTS OR OTHER INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY OF THAT THIRD PARTY, OR A LICENSE FROM TI OR BeagleBoard.org UNDER THE PATENTS OR OTHER INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY OF TI OR BeagleBoard.org.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;LIMITATION OF LIABILITY&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;IN NO EVENT SHALL BeagleBoard.org OR ITS SUPPLIERS BE LIABLE FOR ANY INDIRECT, SPECIAL, INCIDENTAL OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES OR ANY DAMAGES WHATSOEVER, INCLUDING BUT NOT LIMITED TO, DAMAGES RESULTING FROM LOSS OF USE, DATA OR PROFITS, WHETHER IN AN ACTION OF CONTRACT, NEGLIGENCE OR OTHER TORTIOUS ACTION RESULTING FROM USE OF THIS SITE OR ARISING OUT OF THE USE OR PERFORMANCE OF THE MATERIALS AVAILABLE ON THIS SITE, REGARDLESS OF WHETHER BeagleBoard.org OR AN AUTHORIZED BeagleBoard.org REPRESENTATIVE HAS BEEN ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGES.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;SPECIFIC NOTICE REGARDING SOFTWARE AVAILABLE ON THIS SITE&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Any software that is made available to download from this site (&quot;Software&quot;) is copyrighted. Use of this Software is governed by the terms of the license agreement, if any, that accompanies or is included with such Software (&quot;License Agreement&quot;). A user will be unable to install any Software that is accompanied by or includes a License Agreement before first agreeing to the License Agreement terms. Any reproduction or redistribution of the Software not in accordance with the License Agreement is expressly prohibited, and may result in civil and criminal penalties.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;WITHOUT LIMITING THE FOREGOING, COPYING OR REPRODUCTION OF THE SOFTWARE TO ANY OTHER LOCATION FOR FURTHER REPRODUCTION OR REDISTRIBUTION IS PROHIBITED, UNLESS SUCH REPRODUCTION OR REDISTRIBUTION IS EXPRESSLY PERMITTED BY THE LICENSE AGREEMENT ACCOMPANYING SUCH SOFTWARE. FOR YOUR CONVENIENCE, BeagleBoard.org MAY MAKE AVAILABLE ON THIS SITE OR IN ITS SOFTWARE PRODUCTS, TOOLS AND UTILITIES FOR USE OR DOWNLOAD. BeagleBoard.org or TI DOES NOT MAKE ANY ASSURANCES WITH REGARD TO THE ACCURACY OF THE RESULTS OR OUTPUT THAT DERIVES FROM SUCH USE OF ANY SUCH SOFTWARE PRODUCTS, TOOLS AND UTILITIES.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;SPECIFIC NOTICE REGARDING LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Links provided may permit exit from this site and to external sites. These linked sites are not under BeagleBoard.org&apos;s jurisdiction or control. BeagleBoard.org is not responsible for the contents of any linked site or any changes or updates to such sites. BeagleBoard.org provides these links to you only as a convenience, the inclusion of any link does not imply endorsement by TI or BeagleBoard.org of any linked site.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;BeagleBoard.org&apos;s PUBLICATION OF INFORMATION REGARDING THIRD-PARTY PRODUCTS OR SERVICES DOES NOT CONSTITUTE AN ENDORSEMENT REGARDING THE SUITABILITY OF SUCH PRODUCTS OR SERVICES OR A WARRANTY, REPRESENTATION OR ENDORSEMENT OF SUCH PRODUCTS OR SERVICES, EITHER ALONE OR IN COMBINATION WITH ANY TI OR BeagleBoard.org PRODUCT OR SERVICE.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;SPECIFIC NOTICE REGARDING PRODUCTS PURCHASED FROM THIS SITE&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Products cannot be directly purchased from this site, but are available via distributor.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
    <pathbytype>Anonymous:/arm-based processor platforms//arm-based processor platforms choose a core tab-en</pathbytype>
    <hqs>arm</hqs>
    <ev63>dsps_arm_102109</ev63>
    <s_ppv>/arm-based%20processor%20platforms//arm-based%20processor%20platforms%20choose%20a%20core%20tab-en,62,43,1086</s_ppv>
    <gpn>Non-Product</gpn>
    <http_referer>http://ims-mm01.am.dhcp.ti.com:5001/terms/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>ims-mm01.am.dhcp.ti.com:5001</http_host>
    <ap_cookie_en>computerId-C_EN_152046639&amp;geoStateCode-TX&amp;ipGeoMapDate-1365458024737&amp;expiryDate-1397075795470&amp;lastVisitedDate-1365539795470&amp;geoRegion-Americas&amp;createdDate-1364997123797&amp;geoCountryCode-US&amp;ipAddress-128.247.107.49&amp;</ap_cookie_en>
    <user>rachelmarionball@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
