<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="238" name="terms" prototype="Page" created="1216302046625" lastModified="1216302521591">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <body>
 &lt;h1&gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;UNDER CONSTRUCTION&lt;/strong&gt;
 &lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;h1&gt;Terms and Conditions&lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;1. ACCEPTANCE OF TERMS&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  BeagleBoard.org welcomes you.  BeagleBoard.org provides its service you subject to the following Terms of Service (&quot;TOS&quot;).  BeagleBoard.org reserves the right to make changes to this site and to the TOS at any time.  You can review the most current version of the TOS at any time at:
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://BeagleBoard.org/terms&quot;&gt;http://BeagleBoard.org/terms.&lt;/a&gt;
  Any change in the TOS will be prospective only, unless retroactive effect is legally required. Your continued use of this site will constitute your acceptance of any new or amended terms.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The information, material and related graphics available on this site (&quot;Materials&quot;) are provided by BeagleBoard.org registered editors. By using this site you agree that you have read and understood the TOS and agree to be bound by these terms, and to comply with all applicable laws and regulations regarding use of this site. If you do not agree to these terms, do not use this site.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;BeagleBoard.org operates this site from within the United States. BeagleBoard.org makes no representations that the Materials referenced on this site are appropriate or available for use in other areas of the world. Those who access this site from locations outside the United States are responsible for compliance with applicable local laws. Any claim relating to this site or use of this site will be governed by and interpreted in accordance with the laws of the State of Texas, without reference to its conflict-of-laws principles. Any dispute arising out of or related to your use of this site will be brought in, and you hereby consent to exclusive jurisdiction and venue in, the state and federal courts sitting in Harris County, Texas. You agree to waive all defenses of lack of personal jurisdiction and forum non-conveniens and agree that process may be served in a manner authorized by applicable law or court rule.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;2. DESCRIPTION OF SERVICE&lt;/h2&gt;
</body>
    <user>blog.hangerhead.com</user>
    <uri>terms</uri>
    <time type="date">17.07.2008 08:40:46 CDT</time>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
