<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="2462" name="Page" prototype="Page" created="1365629951501" lastModified="1446122768579">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64) AppleWebKit/537.31 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/26.0.1410.64 Safari/537.31</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>dwcontest</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">25.04.2013 22:56:54 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.198.47.16.1nnwxqcrwvg2w</hopsession>
    <user>jessica.lynne.callaway@gmail.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">495.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;body&gt;
DESIGN WEST BEAGLEBONE BLACK ON-SITE GIVEAWAY CONTEST RULES

&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For purposes of these Rules, “TI” shall mean Texas Instruments, Inc and its subsidiaries, “Circuitco” shall mean Circuitco Electronics LLC and its subsidiaries, “element 14” shall mean Premier Farnell plc and its subsidiaries and “Mouser” shall mean Mouser Electronics, Inc and its subsidiaries. TI, Circuitco, element 14 and Mouser are collectively referred to herein as the “Sponsors.”


&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To be eligible to compete, each entrant must read and agree to abide by the Contest rules. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each entrant must willingly surrender a business card. The business card is considered the official entry form to this contest. Submitting a Twitter handle is optional and doubles the entrants’ chances of winning. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Entries must be in English.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase one of the Contest begins on April 23, 2013 at 1:00 p.m. (PDT) and ends April 23, 2013 at 7:00 p.m. (PDT).  No submissions submitted after April 23, 2013 at 2:00 p.m. (PDT) will be considered.  Phase 1 award recipients will be contacted before 7:00 p.m. (PDT) on April 23, 2013 and will have until 4:00 p.m. (PDT) April 25, 2013 to claim their prize from the element 14 booth. Texas Instruments reserves the right to cancel this Contest phase before the end date at its sole discretion, and decline to award prizes if there are no eligible entrants. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phase two of the Contest begins on April 24, 2013 at 12:00 p.m. (PDT) and ends April 24, 2013 at 5:30 p.m. (PDT). No submissions submitted after April 24, 2013 at 1:00 p.m. (PDT) will be considered. Phase 2 award recipients will be contacted before 5:30 p.m. (PDT) on April 24, 2013 and will have until 4:00 p.m. (PDT) April 25, 2013 to claim their prize from the Mouser Booth.  Texas Instruments reserves the right to cancel this Contest phase before the end date at its sole discretion, and decline to award prizes if there are no eligible entrants.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple entries per person are allowed, but only one business card submission and one Twitter handle submission per Contest phase will be accepted.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Odds of winning are determined by the total number of eligible entries received. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sponsors reserve the right, at its sole discretion, to disqualify anyone found to have tampered with the Contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST IS OFFERED AND PARTICIPATION IS LIMITED TO ONLY RESIDENTS OF THE UNITED STATES, CANADA AND MEXICO.  &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To be eligible, entrants must be eighteen (18) year of age or older. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;THERE IS NO ENTRY FEE.  &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;ENTRANTS DO NOT RECEIVE BY WAY OF OR UNDER THE CONTEST ANY INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS IN ANY COPYRIGHTS, PATENTS, TRADEMARKS, TRADE NAMES, TECHNOLOGY, TRADE SECRETS, OR KNOW-HOW OF TEXAS INSTRUMENTS OR ANY THIRD PARTY.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Entrants must agree to these terms and conditions to be eligible to participate in this Contest.  Entries must be submitted by the deadline to be considered.  Entrants will not be allowed to change or supplement their submissions once they have been submitted. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants agree to follow and abide by the judging criteria.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants warrant and represent that the business card and/or Twitter handle is entirely original and that entrant is the owner of said business card and Twitter handle.  This representation is a requirement of participation in the Contest.  By submitting a business card or Twitter handle, all entrants represent and that there is no third party of any kind, whether an academic institution, commercial company, individual, or governmental legal entity which has any proprietary or other interest in, claims or rights to, any intellectual property rights, including trade secret, “know-how,” copyright, patent, trademark or trade name, in any material submitted under the Contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants agree, represent and guarantee that there are no obligations of any nature, legal or otherwise, which would prohibit, restrict, or interfere with their participation in the Contest or submission of their video content.  All entrants agree to obtain any necessary clearance or approval from any necessary third party participation in all Contest activities and any such approvals, which are required as a condition of participation.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No confidential relationship is established between TI and the entrant as a result of entering this Contest.  None of the content submitted by the entrants will be treated by TI as trade secrets, confidential information, or as protected data under any obligation.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Taxes (United States federal, state and local) and other obligations are solely the responsibility of the winners.  Prizes may be subject to reporting for tax and other purposes.  Winners agree to supply TI with any information necessary for tax reporting purposes and to cooperate in fulfilling all applicable legal requirements. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The entrant whose business card is chosen for consideration for any award, as a condition of award, may be required to submit further information concerning employment and residence.  Also, as a condition of award, the entrant may be required to sign a liability/publicity release.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;The non-exclusive license to Sponsors of intellectual property rights, as described herein, is free of charge and without remuneration of any kind.  All entrants agree that the opportunity to compete for prizes and receive publicity represents full and adequate consideration for license of these rights by all entrants.  Prizes do not represent fixed-sum monetary remuneration of the licensing of intellectual property.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants grant to Sponsors the right to publicize their names, likeness, any information provided on the business card in whatever manner without reservation or compensation.  Entrants further agree to execute, at TI’s request, a publicity release related to TI’s use of an entrant’s name, likeness or information.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;Entrants will not be reimbursed for any costs incurred or for efforts expended in connection with their participation in the Contest.  Such costs are the responsibility of the participants.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;NO PURCHASE IS NECESSARY.&lt;/li&gt;  

&lt;li&gt;Decisions by the Contest judges are final. Sponsors reserve the right to refrain from awarding any prize if there are no or minimal qualified entries.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;PRIZES:  The thirty (30) winners of the first and second phases of the contest will receive BeagleBone Black boards valued at $45 USD each or BeagleBone.org hats valued at $6 USD each, depending on the order in which their business cards were drawn. The first 15 drawn in each of the two phases of the contest will receive a hat and the second 15 drawn in each of the two phases of the contest will receive a BeagleBone Black board. Total approximate value of all prizes: $2,025.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In the event of unavailability of any of the stated prizes, Sponsors reserves the right to substitute items of equal or greater value.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If a winner cannot be reached by 4:00 p.m. (PDT) on April 25, 2013 Sponsors reserve the right to deem the prize forfeited. &lt;li&gt;Employees and agents of Sponsors and such individual’s immediate family (including spouse, children, parents, siblings, grandparents, grandchildren, step-children, step-parents and in-laws) and members of the same household are prohibited from entering this Contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST SHALL BE CONSIDERED VOID WHERE, AND TO THE EXTENT, PROHIBITED BY LAW.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sponsors reserve the right to use information regarding contestants for future mailings subject to applicable laws and regulations and privacy policies.  Texas Instruments’ privacy policy can be found at www.ti.com/home_f_privacy.  &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Subject to verification of eligibility and compliance with all Contest rules, the first thirty (30) business cards drawn will be awarded Prizes during each of the two phases of the contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No entries will be returned to participants, regardless of whether they are accepted.  All business cards become the property of TI. The winners’ names will be published on Sponsors’ websites and media outlets.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If there is a dispute regarding the identity of the entrant, Sponsors reserves the right to deem the account holder of the e-mail address as the entrant.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST AND ITS RULES AND CONDITIONS SHALL BE GOVERNED BY THE LAWS OF THE STATE OF TEXAS AND ANY DISPUTE ARISING OUT OF THIS CONTEST SHALL BE BROUGHT IN, AND YOU HEREBY CONSENT TO EXCLUSIVE JURISDICTION AND VENUE IN, THE FEDERAL DISTRICT COURTS SITTING IN DALLAS COUNTY, TEXAS.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If any aspect of the Contest or any rule or condition be found by a court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid, illegal or void, participants agree to allow TI to change such provision and, upon notice, to make it valid.  Also, in such case, the remaining Contest provisions shall remain in full force and effect and the Contest shall proceed accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Phase 1 contest winners will be notified by Sponsors by 7:00 p.m. (PDT) on April 23, 2013. Phase 2 contest winners will be notified by Sponsors by 5:30 p.m. (PDT) on April 24, 2013. The prizes for phases 1 and 2 will be awarded no later than 4 p.m. (PDT) on April 25, 2013.The names and residence of the winners will be published on BeagleBoard.org.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;By entering this Contest, each entrant agrees to release and hold Sponsors harmless from and against any losses, damages, rights, claims and actions of any kind arising from (i) an exclusion or disqualification of an entrant pursuant to these Rules; (ii) late, lost, misdirected, or unsuccessful efforts to notify winners of any prize; (iii) forfeiture of a prize and the selection of an alternate winner; (iv) late, lost, delayed, damaged, misdirected, incomplete, illegible or unintelligible entries; (v) telephone, electronic, hardware or software program, network, Internet, or computer malfunctions, failures or difficulties of any kind; (iii) failed, incomplete, garbled or delayed computer transmissions; (iv) any condition caused by events beyond TI’s control that may cause the Contest to be disrupted or corrupted; (v) any injuries, losses or damages of any kind relating to a contest prize, or acceptance, possession or use of the prize, or from participation in this Contest. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sponsors reserve the right to cancel, terminate, modify or suspend this Contest if it becomes corrupted or if for any reason the Internet portion of the Contest is not capable of running as planned, including infections by computer virus, bugs, tampering, unauthorized intervention, fraud, technical failures or any other causes beyond the control of Sponsors, which corrupt or affect the administration, security, fairness, integrity or proper conduct of this Contest.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;A list of the winners will be available after May 1, 2013.  For a list of the winner’s, send a self-addressed, stamped envelope to:&lt;/li&gt;  
&lt;br /&gt;
Jessica Callaway
&lt;br /&gt;
12500 TI BLVD
&lt;br /&gt;
Mail Station: 8726
&lt;br /&gt;
Dallas, TX 75243
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


Sponsors:

&lt;br /&gt;
Texas Instruments Incorporated
&lt;br /&gt;
12500 TI Boulevard
&lt;br /&gt;
Dallas, Texas 75266 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Circuitco Electronics, LLC&lt;br /&gt;
1380 Presidential Dr. #100
&lt;br /&gt;
Richardson, Texas 75081 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Premier Farnell plc
&lt;br /&gt;
Farnell House
Forge Lane
&lt;br /&gt;
Leeds LS12 2NE &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Mouser Electronics Incorporated
&lt;br /&gt;
1000 North Main Street
&lt;br /&gt;
Mansfield, TX 76063
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

DESIGN WEST ELEMENT 14 BEAGLEBONE BLACK GIVEAWAY SOCIAL MEDIA CONTEST RULES
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
For purposes of these Rules, “TI” shall mean Texas Instruments Incorporated and its subsidiaries, “element 14” shall mean Premier Farnell plc and its subsidiaries. TI and element 14 are collectively referred to herein as the “Sponsors.”


&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;


&lt;li&gt;To be eligible to compete, each entrant must read and agree to abide by the Contest rules. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Each entrant must take a picture of Boris during DESIGN West and show the photo at the element 14 booth or tweet the photo. Showing the photo to an element 14 representative at the show booth or tweeting the photo is considered the official entry form to this contest. &lt;/li&gt;
	
&lt;li&gt;Entries must be in English.&lt;/li&gt;  

&lt;li&gt;The Contest begins on April 23, 2013 at 9:00 a.m. (PDT) and ends April 25, 2013 at 5:00 p.m. (PDT).  No submissions submitted after April 23, 2013 at 7:00 p.m. (PDT) will be considered.  The award recipients will be contacted before 5:00 p.m. (PDT) on April 25, 2013 and will have until 5:00 p.m. (PDT) April 25, 2013 to claim their prize from the element 14 booth. Texas Instruments reserves the right to cancel this Contest phase before the end date at its sole discretion, and decline to award prizes if there are no eligible entrants. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Only one entry per person is allowed during each phase of the contest.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;Odds of winning are determined by the total number of eligible entries received.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sponsors reserve the right, at its sole discretion, to disqualify anyone found to have tampered with the Contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST IS OFFERED AND PARTICIPATION IS LIMITED TO ONLY RESIDENTS OF THE UNITED STATES, CANADA AND MEXICO.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To be eligible, entrants must be eighteen (18) year of age or older.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;THERE IS NO ENTRY FEE.&lt;/li&gt;  

&lt;li&gt;ENTRANTS DO NOT RECEIVE BY WAY OF OR UNDER THE CONTEST ANY INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS IN ANY COPYRIGHTS, PATENTS, TRADEMARKS, TRADE NAMES, TECHNOLOGY, TRADE SECRETS, OR KNOW-HOW OF TEXAS INSTRUMENTS OR ANY THIRD PARTY.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Entrants must agree to these terms and conditions to be eligible to participate in this Contest.  Entries must be submitted by the deadline to be considered.  Entrants will not be allowed to change or supplement their submissions once they have been submitted. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants agree to follow and abide by the judging criteria.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants warrant and represent that their entry is entirely original and that entrant is the owner of said entry.  This representation is a requirement of participation in the Contest.  By participating in the contest, all entrants represent and that there is no third party of any kind, whether an academic institution, commercial company, individual, or governmental legal entity which has any proprietary or other interest in, claims or rights to, any intellectual property rights, including trade secret, “know-how,” copyright, patent, trademark or trade name, in any material submitted under the Contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants agree, represent and guarantee that there are no obligations of any nature, legal or otherwise, which would prohibit, restrict, or interfere with their participation in the Contest or submission of their video content.  All entrants agree to obtain any necessary clearance or approval from any necessary third party participation in all Contest activities and any such approvals, which are required as a condition of participation.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No confidential relationship is established between TI and the entrant as a result of entering this Contest.  None of the content submitted by the entrants will be treated by TI as trade secrets, confidential information, or as protected data under any obligation.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Taxes (United States federal, state and local) and other obligations are solely the responsibility of the winners.  Prizes may be subject to reporting for tax and other purposes.  Winners agree to supply TI with any information necessary for tax reporting purposes and to cooperate in fulfilling all applicable legal requirements.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The entrant that is chosen for consideration for any award, as a condition of award, may be required to submit further information concerning employment and residence.  Also, as a condition of award, the entrant may be required to sign a liability/publicity release.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;The non-exclusive license to Sponsors of intellectual property rights, as described herein, is free of charge and without remuneration of any kind.  All entrants agree that the opportunity to compete for prizes and receive publicity represents full and adequate consideration for license of these rights by all entrants.  Prizes do not represent fixed-sum monetary remuneration of the licensing of intellectual property.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants grant to Sponsors the right to publicize their names, likeness, any information provided on the business card or their Twitter handle in whatever manner without reservation or compensation.  Entrants further agree to execute, at TI’s request, a publicity release related to TI’s use of an entrant’s name, likeness or information.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;Entrants will not be reimbursed for any costs incurred or for efforts expended in connection with their participation in the Contest.  Such costs are the responsibility of the participants.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;NO PURCHASE IS NECESSARY.&lt;/li&gt;  

&lt;li&gt;Decisions by the Contest judges are final. Sponsors reserve the right to refrain from awarding any prize if there are no or minimal qualified entries.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;PRIZES:  The five (5) winners of the contest will receive BeagleBone Black boards valued at $45 USD each. Total approximate value of all prizes: $180.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In the event of unavailability of any of the stated prizes, Sponsors reserves the right to substitute items of equal or greater value.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If a winner cannot be reached by 5:00 p.m. (PDT) on April 25, 2013 Sponsors reserve the right to deem the prize forfeited.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;Employees and agents of Sponsors and such individual’s immediate family (including spouse, children, parents, siblings, grandparents, grandchildren, step-children, step-parents and in-laws) and members of the same household are prohibited from entering this Contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST SHALL BE CONSIDERED VOID WHERE, AND TO THE EXTENT, PROHIBITED BY LAW.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sponsors reserve the right to use information regarding contestants for future mailings subject to applicable laws and regulations and privacy policies.  Texas Instruments’ privacy policy can be found at www.ti.com/home_f_privacy.  &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Subject to verification of eligibility and compliance with all Contest rules, the first five (5) entrants to show their picture of Boris at element 14’s booth or to tweet the picture during DESIGN West will be awarded Prizes during the contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No entries will be returned to participants, regardless of whether they are accepted.  All business cards become the property of TI. The winners’ names will be published on Sponsors’ websites and media outlets.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If there is a dispute regarding the identity of the entrant, Sponsors reserves the right to deem the account holder of the e-mail address as the entrant.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST AND ITS RULES AND CONDITIONS SHALL BE GOVERNED BY THE LAWS OF THE STATE OF TEXAS AND ANY DISPUTE ARISING OUT OF THIS CONTEST SHALL BE BROUGHT IN, AND YOU HEREBY CONSENT TO EXCLUSIVE JURISDICTION AND VENUE IN, THE FEDERAL DISTRICT COURTS SITTING IN DALLAS COUNTY, TEXAS.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If any aspect of the Contest or any rule or condition be found by a court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid, illegal or void, participants agree to allow TI to change such provision and, upon notice, to make it valid.  Also, in such case, the remaining Contest provisions shall remain in full force and effect and the Contest shall proceed accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Winners will be notified by Sponsors by 5:00 p.m. (PDT) on April 25, 2013. The prizes will be awarded no later than 5 p.m. (PDT) on April 25, 2013.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;By entering this Contest, each entrant agrees to release and hold Sponsors harmless from and against any losses, damages, rights, claims and actions of any kind arising from (i) an exclusion or disqualification of an entrant pursuant to these Rules; (ii) late, lost, misdirected, or unsuccessful efforts to notify winners of any prize; (iii) forfeiture of a prize and the selection of an alternate winner; (iv) late, lost, delayed, damaged, misdirected, incomplete, illegible or unintelligible entries; (v) telephone, electronic, hardware or software program, network, Internet, or computer malfunctions, failures or difficulties of any kind; (iii) failed, incomplete, garbled or delayed computer transmissions; (iv) any condition caused by events beyond TI’s control that may cause the Contest to be disrupted or corrupted; (v) any injuries, losses or damages of any kind relating to a contest prize, or acceptance, possession or use of the prize, or from participation in this Contest. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sponsors reserve the right to cancel, terminate, modify or suspend this Contest if it becomes corrupted or if for any reason the Internet portion of the Contest is not capable of running as planned, including infections by computer virus, bugs, tampering, unauthorized intervention, fraud, technical failures or any other causes beyond the control of Sponsors, which corrupt or affect the administration, security, fairness, integrity or proper conduct of this Contest.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;A list of the winners will be available after May 1, 2013.  For a list of the winner’s, send a self-addressed, stamped envelope to:&lt;/li&gt;  
&lt;br /&gt;
Jessica Callaway
&lt;br /&gt;
12500 TI BLVD
&lt;br /&gt;
Mail Station: 8726
&lt;br /&gt;
Dallas, TX 75243
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


Sponsors:

&lt;br /&gt;
Texas Instruments Incorporated
&lt;br /&gt;
12500 TI Boulevard
&lt;br /&gt;
Dallas, Texas 75266 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Premier Farnell plc
&lt;br /&gt;
Farnell House
Forge Lane
&lt;br /&gt;
Leeds LS12 2NE &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;



DESIGN WEST MOUSER BEAGLEBONE BLACK GIVEAWAY SOCIAL MEDIA CONTEST RULES
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

For purposes of these Rules, “TI” shall mean Texas Instruments Incorporated and its subsidiaries, “Mouser” shall mean Mouser Electronics, Inc and its subsidiaries. TI and Mouser are collectively referred to herein as the “Sponsors.”
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To be eligible to compete, each entrant must read and agree to abide by the Contest rules. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Each entrant must be a follower of both TI (@TXInstruments) and Mouser (@MouserElec) Twitter handles and submit the code words 1)unscrambled, and 2)in the correct order via Twitter with the hashtag #BeagleBoneCode. Five (5) winners will be drawn from the qualified entrants.&lt;/li&gt;
	
&lt;li&gt;Entries must be in English.&lt;/li&gt;  

&lt;li&gt;The Contest begins on April 23, 2013 at 9:00 a.m. (PDT) and ends April 25, 2013 at 7:00 p.m. (PDT).  No submissions submitted after April 25, 2013 at 7:00 p.m. (PDT) will be considered.  Award recipients will be contacted via Twitter before 5:00 p.m. (PDT) on April 26, 2013 and will have until 5:00 p.m. (PDT) May 1, 2013 to claim their prize by contacting Sponsors by the same method. Texas Instruments reserves the right to cancel this Contest phase before the end date at its sole discretion, and decline to award prizes if there are no eligible entrants. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Only one entry per person is allowed during each phase of the contest.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;Odds of winning are determined by the total number of eligible entries received.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sponsors reserve the right, at its sole discretion, to disqualify anyone found to have tampered with the Contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST IS OFFERED AND PARTICIPATION IS LIMITED TO ONLY RESIDENTS OF THE UNITED STATES, CANADA AND MEXICO.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;To be eligible, entrants must be eighteen (18) year of age or older. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;THERE IS NO ENTRY FEE.&lt;/li&gt;  

&lt;li&gt;ENTRANTS DO NOT RECEIVE BY WAY OF OR UNDER THE CONTEST ANY INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY RIGHTS IN ANY COPYRIGHTS, PATENTS, TRADEMARKS, TRADE NAMES, TECHNOLOGY, TRADE SECRETS, OR KNOW-HOW OF TEXAS INSTRUMENTS OR ANY THIRD PARTY.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Entrants must agree to these terms and conditions to be eligible to participate in this Contest.  Entries must be submitted by the deadline to be considered.  Entrants will not be allowed to change or supplement their submissions once they have been submitted. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants agree to follow and abide by the judging criteria.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants warrant and represent that their entry is entirely original and that entrant is the owner of said entry.  This representation is a requirement of participation in the Contest.  By participating in the contest, all entrants represent and that there is no third party of any kind, whether an academic institution, commercial company, individual, or governmental legal entity which has any proprietary or other interest in, claims or rights to, any intellectual property rights, including trade secret, “know-how,” copyright, patent, trademark or trade name, in any material submitted under the Contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants agree, represent and guarantee that there are no obligations of any nature, legal or otherwise, which would prohibit, restrict, or interfere with their participation in the Contest or submission of their video content.  All entrants agree to obtain any necessary clearance or approval from any necessary third party participation in all Contest activities and any such approvals, which are required as a condition of participation.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No confidential relationship is established between TI and the entrant as a result of entering this Contest.  None of the content submitted by the entrants will be treated by TI as trade secrets, confidential information, or as protected data under any obligation.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Taxes (United States federal, state and local) and other obligations are solely the responsibility of the winners.  Prizes may be subject to reporting for tax and other purposes.  Winners agree to supply TI with any information necessary for tax reporting purposes and to cooperate in fulfilling all applicable legal requirements.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The entrant that is chosen for consideration for any award, as a condition of award, may be required to submit further information concerning employment and residence.  Also, as a condition of award, the entrant may be required to sign a liability/publicity release.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;The non-exclusive license to Sponsors of intellectual property rights, as described herein, is free of charge and without remuneration of any kind.  All entrants agree that the opportunity to compete for prizes and receive publicity represents full and adequate consideration for license of these rights by all entrants.  Prizes do not represent fixed-sum monetary remuneration of the licensing of intellectual property.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;All entrants grant to Sponsors the right to publicize their names, likeness, any information provided on the business card or their Twitter handle in whatever manner without reservation or compensation.  Entrants further agree to execute, at TI’s request, a publicity release related to TI’s use of an entrant’s name, likeness or information. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Entrants will not be reimbursed for any costs incurred or for efforts expended in connection with their participation in the Contest.  Such costs are the responsibility of the participants.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;NO PURCHASE IS NECESSARY.&lt;/li&gt;  

&lt;li&gt;Decisions by the Contest judges are final. Sponsors reserve the right to refrain from awarding any prize if there are no or minimal qualified entries.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;PRIZES:  The fifteen (5) winners of the first and second phases of the contest will receive BeagleBone Black boards valued at $45 USD each. Total approximate value of all prizes: $225.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;In the event of unavailability of any of the stated prizes, Sponsors reserves the right to substitute items of equal or greater value.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If winners cannot be reached by 5:00 p.m. (PDT) on May 1, 2013 Sponsors reserve the right to deem the prize forfeited.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Employees and agents of Sponsors and such individual’s immediate family (including spouse, children, parents, siblings, grandparents, grandchildren, step-children, step-parents and in-laws) and members of the same household are prohibited from entering this Contest.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST SHALL BE CONSIDERED VOID WHERE, AND TO THE EXTENT, PROHIBITED BY LAW.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sponsors reserve the right to use information regarding contestants for future mailings subject to applicable laws and regulations and privacy policies.  Texas Instruments’ privacy policy can be found at www.ti.com/home_f_privacy.  &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Subject to verification of eligibility and compliance with all Contest rules, the five (5) random winners chosen awarded.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No entries will be returned to participants, regardless of whether they are accepted.  All business cards become the property of TI. The winners’ names will be published on Sponsors’ websites and media outlets.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If there is a dispute regarding the identity of the entrant, Sponsors reserves the right to deem the account holder of the e-mail address as the entrant.&lt;/li&gt; 

&lt;li&gt;THE CONTEST AND ITS RULES AND CONDITIONS SHALL BE GOVERNED BY THE LAWS OF THE STATE OF TEXAS AND ANY DISPUTE ARISING OUT OF THIS CONTEST SHALL BE BROUGHT IN, AND YOU HEREBY CONSENT TO EXCLUSIVE JURISDICTION AND VENUE IN, THE FEDERAL DISTRICT COURTS SITTING IN DALLAS COUNTY, TEXAS.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;If any aspect of the Contest or any rule or condition be found by a court of competent jurisdiction to be invalid, illegal or void, participants agree to allow TI to change such provision and, upon notice, to make it valid.  Also, in such case, the remaining Contest provisions shall remain in full force and effect and the Contest shall proceed accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Contest winners will be notified by Sponsors by 5:00 p.m. (PDT) on April 26, 2013. The prizes for will be awarded no later than 5 p.m. (PDT) on May 1, 2013. The names and residence of the winners will be published on BeagleBoard.org.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;By entering this Contest, each entrant agrees to release and hold Sponsors harmless from and against any losses, damages, rights, claims and actions of any kind arising from (i) an exclusion or disqualification of an entrant pursuant to these Rules; (ii) late, lost, misdirected, or unsuccessful efforts to notify winners of any prize; (iii) forfeiture of a prize and the selection of an alternate winner; (iv) late, lost, delayed, damaged, misdirected, incomplete, illegible or unintelligible entries; (v) telephone, electronic, hardware or software program, network, Internet, or computer malfunctions, failures or difficulties of any kind; (iii) failed, incomplete, garbled or delayed computer transmissions; (iv) any condition caused by events beyond TI’s control that may cause the Contest to be disrupted or corrupted; (v) any injuries, losses or damages of any kind relating to a contest prize, or acceptance, possession or use of the prize, or from participation in this Contest. &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Sponsors reserve the right to cancel, terminate, modify or suspend this Contest if it becomes corrupted or if for any reason the Internet portion of the Contest is not capable of running as planned, including infections by computer virus, bugs, tampering, unauthorized intervention, fraud, technical failures or any other causes beyond the control of Sponsors, which corrupt or affect the administration, security, fairness, integrity or proper conduct of this Contest. &lt;/li&gt;





&lt;li&gt;A list of the winners will be available after May 1, 2013.  For a list of the winner’s, send a self-addressed, stamped envelope to:  &lt;/li&gt;

&lt;br /&gt;
Jessica Callaway
&lt;br /&gt;
12500 TI BLVD
&lt;br /&gt;
Mail Station: 8726
&lt;br /&gt;
Dallas, TX 75243
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

Sponsors:

&lt;br /&gt;
Texas Instruments Incorporated
&lt;br /&gt;
12500 TI Boulevard
&lt;br /&gt;
Dallas, Texas 75266 &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

Mouser Electronics Incorporated
&lt;br /&gt;
1000 North Main Street
&lt;br /&gt;
Mansfield, TX 76063
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;








&lt;/body&gt;

&lt;/html&gt;
</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/dwcontest/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
