<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="2801" name="Page" prototype="Page" created="1372191685830" lastModified="1449005397128">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_4) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/27.0.1453.116 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>bad-to-the-bone</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">26.06.2013 15:49:50 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.192.94.94.16y4dhn3hk151</hopsession>
    <user>jkridner@gmail.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">8017.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;div style=&quot;float:right;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;http://rcm.amazon.com/e/cm?lt1=_blank&amp;bc1=000000&amp;IS2=1&amp;bg1=FFFFFF&amp;fc1=000000&amp;lc1=0000FF&amp;t=bloghanerhead-20&amp;o=1&amp;p=8&amp;l=as4&amp;m=amazon&amp;f=ifr&amp;ref=ss_til&amp;asins=1627051376&quot; style=&quot;width:120px;height:240px;&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; marginwidth=&quot;0&quot; marginheight=&quot;0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bad to the Bone&lt;/em&gt;: Crafting Electronics Systems with BeagleBone and BeagleBone Black&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.morganclaypool.com/doi/abs/10.2200/S00500ED1V01Y201304DCS041&quot;&gt;
Published by Morgan and Claypool&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;April 2013, 430 pages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Authors&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Steven F. Barrett, University of Wyoming&lt;br /&gt;
Jason Kridner, Texas Instruments
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;    
&lt;p&gt;This comprehensive book provides detailed materials for both novice and 
experienced programmers using all BeagleBone variants which host a powerful 
32-bit, super-scalar TI Sitara ARM Cortex A8 processor. Authored by Steven F. 
Barrett and Jason Kridner, a seasoned ECE educator along with the founder of 
Beagleboard.org, respectively, the work may be used in a wide variety of 
projects from science fair projects to university courses and senior design 
projects to first prototypes of very complex systems. Beginners may access the 
power of the &quot;Bone&quot; through the user-friendly Bonescript examples. Seasoned 
users may take full advantage of the Bone&apos;s power using the underlying 
Linux-based operating system, a host of feature extension boards (Capes) and a
wide variety of Linux community open source libraries. The book contains 
background theory on system operation coupled with many well-documented, 
illustrative examples. Examples for novice users are centered on motivational, 
fun robot projects while advanced projects follow the theme of assistive 
technology and image processing applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Key Features:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Provides detailed examples for all BeagleBone variants, including the 
        newest &quot;next generation&quot; BeagleBone Black
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        BeagleBone is a low cost, open hardware, expandable computer first 
        introduced in November 2011 by BeagleBoard.org
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        BeagleBone variants, including the original BeagleBone and the new 
        BeagleBone Black, hosts a powerful 32-bit, super-scalar ARM Cortex A8 
        processor
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        BeagleBone is small enough to fit in a small mint tin box
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        &quot;Bone&quot; may be used in a wide variety of projects from middle school 
        science fair projects to university courses and senior design projects 
        to first prototypes of very complex systems
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        Novice users may access the power of the Bone through the user-friendly
        BoneScript environment    
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        Seasoned users may take full advantage of the Bone&apos;s power using the 
        underlying Linux-based operating system
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        A host of feature extension boards (Capes) and a wide variety of Linux 
        community open source libraries are available
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        The book provides an introduction to this powerful computer and has 
        been designed for a wide variety of users
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        The book contains background theory on system operation coupled with
        many well-documented, illustrative examples
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        Examples for novice users are centered on motivational, fun robot
        projects
    &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;
        Advanced projects follow the theme of assistive technology and image 
        processing applications
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jadonk/bad-to-the-bone-examples&quot;&gt;Examples
    from the text&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;clear:both;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/bad-to-the-bone/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
