<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="2803" name="Replicape Plus" prototype="Page" created="1372202077172" lastModified="1372202077173">
  <hop:parent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <edit_skin>edit_project</edit_skin>
    <updatetime type="date">25.06.2013 18:14:37 CDT</updatetime>
    <uri>Replicape Plus</uri>
    <time type="date">25.06.2013 18:14:37 CDT</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <registrant>stephen.edwards65@gmail.com</registrant>
    <pname>Replicape Plus</pname>
    <user>stephen.edwards65@gmail.com</user>
    <body>Features include:  
-   6 stepper motors (2.5A DRV8825) (X, Y, Z, Ext1, Ext2, Ext3)  
-   5 high power MOSFETs (PWM controlled) for 3 extruders,1 HPB and 1 Room.  (12..36V)  
-   3 medium power MOSFETs (PWM controlled) for up to 3 fans/LED strips.  (12V)
-   1 RGB full PWM low power LED output (12v)  
-   3 analog input ports for thermistors. noise-filtered inputs and option for shielding 
-   3 Thermocouple inputs for higher temperatures and finer temperature controll. 
-   6 inputs for end stops (X, Y, Z).  
-   Programmable current limits on steppers motor drivers (SMD). No need to manually adjust a pot meter.  
-   Microstepping individually programmable for each SMD from 1 to 32.  
-   All steppers are controlled by the Programmable Realtime Unit (PRU) for hard real time operation.  
-   Seperate Power input for 12v, 12-36v steppers and 12-36v Mosfets with auxillary power in for extra drive!
-   Comptabile with BeagleBone Black.  
-   Open source hardware and software.  
-   Software written in Python for maintainability and hackability. </body>
    <errmsg></errmsg>
    <homepage>http://goo.gl/tb8cU</homepage>
    <render_skin>project</render_skin>
    <shortdesc>A Motion controller Cape for the BeagleBoneBlack.
Based on the replicape by Elias Bakken. This is a modified design the Plus Sizes the number of steppers, the mosfets power supplies and allows thermocouple connections. 

The Cape allows interchangable or replacement parts for anything that may blow.</shortdesc>
    <rssfeed></rssfeed>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
