<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="2865" name="Video Switcher" prototype="Page" created="1373701454439" lastModified="1446673910245">
  <hop:parent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <pname>Video Swithcer/Mixer Control Board</pname>
    <registrant>clarkcablenetwork</registrant>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.9</http_language>
    <uri>Video Switcher</uri>
    <http_browser>Opera/9.80 (Windows NT 6.2; WOW64) Presto/2.12.388 Version/12.16</http_browser>
    <time type="date">13.07.2013 08:03:35 UTC</time>
    <updatetime type="date">13.07.2013 07:44:14 UTC</updatetime>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.140.232.179.1ngbrq8z8yt2a</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;p&gt;Video Switchers, also commonly referred to as Video Mixers, are an integral part of TV and video production, and yet are frequently prohibitively expensive, costing thousands of dollars for even just the control board. &amp;nbsp;As such, we&apos;ve decided to build our own out of a Beaglebone Black and some rows of light up buttons, with a lever for fading built out of a linear slide pot. &amp;nbsp;All of this will then be placed inside a sloped box with the buttons/lights exposed and the Beaglebone within, possibly alongside a dedicated motherboard with capture cards to do the switching itself. &amp;nbsp;Alternately, the Beaglebone&apos;s USB can be connected to any computer with switching software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has only just begun, and is being done by a team of amateurs with very little experience in programming, electronics, or embedded computing, so any help would be much appreciated. &amp;nbsp;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <rssfeed></rssfeed>
    <pvcount type="float">3151.0</pvcount>
    <homepage>http://clarkcablenetwork.wordpress.com/</homepage>
    <render_skin>project</render_skin>
    <edit_skin>edit_project</edit_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/project/Video%20Switcher/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <errmsg></errmsg>
    <shortdesc>The goal of this project is to build a homemade video switcher, taking input from a row of light-up buttons and giving USB output to a computer running a switcher program.</shortdesc>
    <user>clarkcablenetwork@gmail.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
