<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="2878" name="BeagleBoy" prototype="Page" created="1374072137671" lastModified="1374761849405">
  <hop:parent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <pname>BeagleBoy</pname>
    <registrant>thecapelesscrusaders</registrant>
    <http_language>en-US</http_language>
    <uri>BeagleBoy</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (compatible; MSIE 10.0; Windows NT 6.1; WOW64; Trident/6.0)</http_browser>
    <time type="date">25.07.2013 09:17:29 CDT</time>
    <updatetime type="date">17.07.2013 09:42:17 CDT</updatetime>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.192.91.66.3v4at2genryb</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;font face=&quot;Times New Roman&quot;&gt;The circuitry of the BeagleBoy consists of two subsystems: the battery power circuit and a network of 12 buttons. The battery power design was largely taken from the open-source battery cape available from CircuitCo with a few small changes. We used the TSSOP package for the TPS61032 DC/DC converter instead of the QFN and chose larger packages for the resistors so that the PCB would be significantly easier to hand-solder. We also added a power switch so that the user could keep the BeagleBoy off without removing the batteries. The 12 buttons are in positions to emulate an older controller or handheld designed by Nintendo, which means the BeagleBoy includes the standard A, B, X, Y, L, R, start, and select buttons along with a directional pad. This configuration allows the BeagleBoy to be used like a Gameboy Advance or an SNES controller, allowing the user to be more flexible when choosing an emulation program. &lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;font face=&quot;Times New Roman&quot;&gt;The BeagleBoy is meant to be used with a case, but steps were taken in the design process to ensure a system consisting of only a cape, BeagleBone Black, and a compatible display would be useable. The batteries were placed toward the sides of the cape so that their weight would be evenly distributed and to provide gripping points in the event that a user does not have a case. The pads for the controller buttons are dual-purpose. The two large rectangular pads allow for the specific design of buttons used in a traditional video game controller to be integrated into the case design, while the nearby through hole pads provide a way for tactile switches to be soldered directly to the cape.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;font size=&quot;3&quot;&gt;&lt;font face=&quot;Times New Roman&quot;&gt;The design also includes a plastic case to house the BeagleBone Black and the BeagleBoy cape.&lt;span style=&quot;mso-spacerun: yes;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;In an interdisciplinary effort, the PCB and 3D-printed case were designed in tandem so that all components of the cape would fit together inside. The case holds the controller buttons in place and in alignment with the rectangular pads on the PCB while housing the BeagleBone Black and still maintaining access to the HDMI, USB, and Ethernet hubs.&lt;span style=&quot;mso-spacerun: yes;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;The BeagleBoy cape stacks on top of the microcontroller with controller buttons coming through the top of the case to enhance usability.&lt;span style=&quot;mso-spacerun: yes;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;Supports inside of the case prevent movement of components during use.&lt;span style=&quot;mso-spacerun: yes;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;The case also allows the headers from the BeagleBoy to come through so that the LCD cape can be stacked on top.&lt;span style=&quot;mso-spacerun: yes;&quot;&gt;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/span&gt;The overall goal of the case is to allow the user comfort while using the cape/playing the device.&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/font&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <rssfeed></rssfeed>
    <homepage>https://github.com/CapelessCrusaders/BeagleBoy</homepage>
    <render_skin>project</render_skin>
    <edit_skin>edit_project</edit_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/project/BeagleBoy/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <errmsg></errmsg>
    <shortdesc>This project is an entry in the Texas Instruments Intern Design Challenge 2013.  It is a cape for the BeagleBone Black which turns the BBB into a handheld gaming console with the addition of an LCD cape stacked on top or a controller when connected to an HDMI monitor. </shortdesc>
    <user>thecapelesscrusaders@gmail.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
