<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="2928" name="Page" prototype="Page" created="1375136870530" lastModified="1377271893344">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>192.91.75.29</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <uri>fedora</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_4) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/28.0.1500.95 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <time type="date">23.08.2013 10:31:33 CDT</time>
    <hopsession>192.91.75.172.24.0.kpaqxte8h4yf</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;h1&gt;Fedora on BeagleBone Black&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did you know, BeagleBone Black alredy runs Fedora?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://elinux.org/BeagleBoardFedora&quot;&gt;BeagleBoardFedora on
        eLinux.org wiki
    &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Doesn&apos;t open source software deserve open source hardware?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeagleBone Black is true open source hardware with every part available
    through everyday distributors in quantity one. The BeagleBoard.org
    Foundation is a non-profit and charges no royalties for the design
    materials, all released under open licenses. Based on a super-scalar ARMv7
    processor core with ARM-standard vector processing extensions running at
    1GHz, BeagleBone Black fits in a mint tin and enables open source software
    developers to show off without breaking their power budget---or their
    piggy bank. Now at only $45 through distributors world-wide, shouldn&apos;t you
    be showing off on BeagleBone Black too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in advancing the state of Fedora on BeagleBone Black,
    let&apos;s talk! E-mail jkridner AT beagleboard DOT org.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let&apos;s code!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ready to start coding? Folks in the Fedora community already have Fedora
    running on BeagleBone Black and you can try it out.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/project/fedora&quot;&gt;Official project page&lt;/a&gt; - Link to the wiki
        that has information on where to download the current latest image.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next steps include providing a USB-based flasher to avoid needing to
    work with microSD cards and bringing in the rest of the BeagleBone Black
    experience that will help new people get started with Fedora.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The BeagleBone Black experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeagleBone Black is a great way for developers who program for the web to
    get a first taste of hardware---and for many hardware hackers to get a
    first taste of Linux. To bridge these communities, it is important to have
    a solid first experience.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Elements of the desired experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Web-based IDE - Cloud9 ships with the boards today, but the Adafruit
        IDE and codebender.cc solutions look very interesting.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;BoneScript - A JavaScript library built on node.js along with the bone101
        tutorial that utilizes remote procedure calls within the browser to
        become interactive, minimizing the effort to go from web programming to
        physical interactions with all sorts of sensors and actuators. 
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Python - The Adafruit Python library is rapidly growing along with
        libraries of demos on how to get started with physical computing in
        a popular first (and sometimes last) language.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Gcc, make, autotools, OpenCV, pkg-config and a bunch of libraries - 
        Building simple applications in C/C++ should be simple!
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Real-time patches - Not yet shipping in all distros, real-time
        performance is a critcal aspect for building physically interactive
        devices.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;PRU support - The PRUs are 200MHz 32-bit microcontrollers within the
        on-board processor that are dedicated to real-time interface tasks---
        supported by an open source assembler and a remote proc kernel interface,
        much work still needs to be done to utilize these processing elements
        that eliminate the need to add an Arduino or other real-time solutions.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Networking and file storage over USB - You shouldn&apos;t need to buy extra
        hardware to get started; everything in the box should be enough and it
        should be as self-documenting as possible.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Devicetree snippets for embedded interfaces and the devicetree compiler&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;USB-based eMMC flasher - All reflashing instructions today point people
        to write microSD cards, but the processor can be bootloaded over USB
        directly using the processor ROM---and entirely over libusb to make it
        run on multiple operating systems, giving people who have never tried
        out Fedora a way to do so without altering their current system.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Much of the above is already included in the Angstrom Distribution, in work
    in the BeagleBoard.org Google Summer of Code projects or being executed
    elsewhere. Having Fedora maintainers bring that experience to Fedora will
    benefit Fedora, BeagleBone Black users and even users of other low-cost
    development platforms where much of the code can be shared, thanks to us
    all running Linux that abstracts all the low-level interfaces.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Where can delivering this experience lead?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the right solutions, Fedora could be established as the perferred
    distribution for embedded developers and developers seeking to wrap some
    plastic, sensors, lights and motors around their software solutions.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interested?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Contact me at jkridner AT beagleboard DOT org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div id=&quot;disqus_thread&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;
var disqus_shortname = &apos;beagleboard-project&apos;;
(function() {
 var dsq = document.createElement(&apos;script&apos;); dsq.type = &apos;text/javascript&apos;; dsq.async = true;
 dsq.src = &apos;http://&apos; + disqus_shortname + &apos;.disqus.com/embed.js&apos;;
 (document.getElementsByTagName(&apos;head&apos;)[0] || document.getElementsByTagName(&apos;body&apos;)[0]).appendChild(dsq);
})();
&lt;/script&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/fedora/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>jkridner@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
