<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="2928" name="Page" prototype="Page" created="1375136870530" lastModified="1375805780425">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <uri>fedora</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_4) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/28.0.1500.95 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <time type="date">06.08.2013 11:16:20 CDT</time>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.192.94.94.1r02ohpk32194</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;h2&gt;Doesn&apos;t open source software deserve open source hardware?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeagleBone Black is true open source hardware with every part available
    through everyday distributors in quantity one. The BeagleBoard.org
    Foundation is a non-profit and charges no royalties for the design
    materials, all released under open licenses. Based on a super-scalar ARMv7
    processor core with ARM-standard vector processing extensions running at
    1GHz, BeagleBone Black fits in a mint tin and enables open source software
    developers to show off without breaking their power budget---or their
    piggy bank. Now at only $45 through distributors world-wide, shouldn&apos;t you
    be showing off on BeagleBone Black too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in advancing the state of Fedora on BeagleBone Black,
    let&apos;s talk! E-mail jkridner at beagleboard dot org.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&apos;s code!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The BeagleBone Black experience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BeagleBone Black is a great way for developers who program for the web to
    get a first taste of hardware---and for many hardware hackers to get a
    first taste of Linux. To bridge these communities, it is important to have
    a solid first experience.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Elements of the desired experience&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Web-based IDE - Cloud9 ships with the boards today, but the Adafruit
        IDE and codebender.cc solutions look very interesting.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;BoneScript - A JavaScript library built on node.js along with the bone101
        tutorial that utilizes remote procedure calls within the browser to
        become interactive, minimizing the effort to go from web programming to
        physical interactions with all sorts of sensors and actuators. 
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Python - The Adafruit Python library is rapidly growing along with
        libraries of demos on how to get started with physical computing in
        a popular first (and sometimes last) language.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;gcc, make, autotools, OpenCV, pkg-config and a bunch of libraries - 
        Building simple applications in C/C++ should be simple!
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;real-time patches - Not yet shipping in all distros, real-time
        performance is a critcal aspect for building physically interactive
        devices.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Networking and file storage over USB - You shouldn&apos;t need to buy extra
        hardware to get started; everything in the box should be enough and it
        should be as self-documenting as possible.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Interested?&lt;/h2&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/fedora/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>blog.hangerhead.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
