<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="2967" name="2010-12-18-looking-for-college-intern-for-this" prototype="Page" created="1375203002954" lastModified="1443105799982">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_4) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/28.0.1500.71 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>2010-12-18-looking-for-college-intern-for-this</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">30.07.2013 16:50:03 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.192.94.94.1agh54kvhedkc</hopsession>
    <user>doug@dougloo.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">948.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;h3 class=&apos;post-title entry-title&apos; itemprop=&apos;name&apos;&gt;
Looking for a college intern for this summer
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div class=&apos;post-header&apos;&gt;
&lt;div class=&apos;post-header-line-1&apos;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&apos;post-body entry-content&apos; id=&apos;post-body-7163980250064787706&apos; itemprop=&apos;description articleBody&apos;&gt;
In the past, for job postings and other commercial solicitations around the BeagleBoard I&apos;ve recommended utilizing the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.linkedin.com/groups?gid=1474607&quot;&gt;BeagleBoard LinkedIn group&lt;/a&gt; because I never went deeper than the page that said that the job board was free.&amp;nbsp; As I tried to list my own opening, I found that it was going to cost me almost $200.&amp;nbsp; Given that, I welcome anyone contacting me with information on cheaper ways to do job listings and other commercial solicitations related to BeagleBoard activities.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
What I&apos;m inquiring about here is to fill an ARM microprocessor community development team internship position at Texas Instruments for summer 2011.&amp;nbsp; You can find other job opportunities at TI with &lt;a href=&quot;https://hrprod.ext.ti.com/psc/psprodSSS/EMPLOYEE/HRMS/c/HRS_HRAM.HRS_CE.GBL?Action=A&amp;amp;SiteId=2&quot;&gt;TI&apos;s CareerBuilder site&lt;/a&gt; (try keyword &quot;Linux&quot;) or at &lt;a href=&quot;http://careers.ti.com/&quot;&gt;http://careers.ti.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Job Description&lt;/b&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Serve the needs of open source software developers utilizing TI  ARM-based microprocessors by advocating within TI, consolidating and  communicating valuable information internally and externally, and  solving technical and organizational challenges including patches to fix  open source software bugs or functional gaps in software like u-boot,  Linux, applications within GNU/Linux distributions and tools to build  software systems.  Producing written, recorded and interactive  presentation materials to train technical and semi-technical audiences  on utilization and extension of open hardware platforms, such as the  BeagleBoard, is required.  A public reputation in open source software  development is highly desirable.  Some travel required.  On-line  communication skills are a must.  This position is potentially very  flexible in hours and location as long as mastery of communications with  the core team can be demonstrated.  Other potential benefits include  flexibility in software projects and resources of perhaps the largest  volume ARM microprocessor supplier in the industry.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Minimal Skills Required&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;On-line communications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conflict resolution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C and C++ programming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shell scripting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrated knowledge in Linux, operating system and build system concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software revision control management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oral and written communications in English (additional languages are desirable, especially Japanese, Spanish, German, Portuguese, and Hindi)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Company Description&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Texas Instruments (TI) is a global analog and digital semiconductor IC  design and manufacturing company. In addition to analog technologies,  digital signal processing (DSP) and microcontroller (MCU)  semiconductors, TI designs and manufactures semiconductor solutions for  analog and digital embedded and application processing.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Where to send your information&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Please send all TI ARM microprocessor community development job related queries to me with &quot;JOB&quot; in the subject heading and to my jkridner account on beagleboard.org.
&lt;div style=&apos;clear: both;&apos;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2010-12-18-looking-for-college-intern-for-this/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
