<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="2990" name="where-is-beagleboardorg-headed" prototype="Page" created="1375369121714" lastModified="1451882038454">
  <hop:parent idref="2989" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_4) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/28.0.1500.71 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>where-is-beagleboardorg-headed</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">01.08.2013 15:32:03 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2989" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.192.94.94.8bmeguap0p3p</hopsession>
    <user>jkridner.wordpress.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">19.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;h1&gt;Where is BeagleBoard.org headed?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ultimate goal is to improve access to technology that can be helpful in
    solving problems---global problems, local problems, educational problems and
    everyday problems of efficiency that prevent people from contributing more
    of their time and effort in more productive endeavors. The fundamental
    question is, what
    are the most critical problems an organization like BeagleBoard.org
    can be involved in solving?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you aren&apos;t aware, the
    BeagleBoard.org Foundation is a 501(c) non-profit US-based corporation, yet
    there are obvious ties to the for-profit companies Texas Instruments, who
    pays my salary and produces the processors we use for the board designs, and
    CircuitCo Electronics, who buys all the components, assembles the boards and
    ships those boards to distributors around the world.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;What have I learned?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The everyday second grader and everyday electronics design engineer certainly
    have different care abouts, but they are also remarkably similar. Beyond
    the obvious need for a nap in the afternoon that they feel they&apos;ve outgrown,
    they are also both plagued by incredibly short attention spans.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation wins. I don&apos;t necessarily mean that those people who are the
    most innovative win, but rather that innovation itself drives change and
    new innovations spread through the world if we like them or not. It then
    becomes a requirement that if we want positive change for the world, we
    must be involved in innovations that produce positive results.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Innovation doesn&apos;t always come in the form of an improved product.
    Sometimes innovation can be as simple as providing a better description
    of how to use an existing product, providing a better way of building a
    product or even have nothing to do with a product at all.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s not about what communities of developers can do for a project, it&apos;s
    about what a project can do for a community. In many respect, we&apos;ve really
    had this right relative to many other projects, because we&apos;ve focused on
    what we do well and done what we can to enable others to provide innovation
    around the project. The Raspberry Pi folks have tought me one place where
    we&apos;ve done this wrong, and that is in giving a clear goal for the project
    such that communities of developers understand where their contributions to
    the project ultimately pay off in having a better world. Certainly that
    has been our goal the entire time, but how are developers seeing the
    results?
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Collaborative&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Open&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog-drafts/where-is-beagleboardorg-headed/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
