<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="309" name="faq" prototype="Page" created="1218456920368" lastModified="1218857839052">
  <hop:parent idref="121" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; U; Intel Mac OS X 10.5; en-US; rv:1.9.0.1) Gecko/2008070206 Firefox/3.0.1</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>faq</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">15.08.2008 22:37:19 CDT</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="121" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.76.31.18.1wxc3dxdgdtla</hopsession>
    <user>blog.hangerhead.com</user>
    <body>
 &lt;h1&gt;Frequently Asked Questions&lt;/h1&gt;
 &lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
   &lt;b&gt;Why is there no Ethernet port?&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
   &lt;b&gt;How do I connect a keyboard and mouse?&lt;/b&gt;
   &lt;br/&gt;
   &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
     Be certain that you are using a mini-
     &lt;b&gt;
      &lt;i&gt;A&lt;/i&gt;
     &lt;/b&gt;
     to standard-A USB adapter.  Mini-B adapters will not work without additional hardware modifications.  Recommended peripherals can be found on
     &lt;a href=&quot;/hardware&quot;&gt;the product details page.&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;It is also necessary to build support for USB OTG host mode into your kernel.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The port can only supply 100mA, so you might need a powered hub for power-hungry keyboards and mice&lt;/li&gt;
   &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
   &lt;b&gt;Is BeagleBoard.org Linux only?&lt;/b&gt;
   &lt;br/&gt;
   Beagle Board as such is not associated to Linux only.
   &lt;br/&gt;
   BeagleBoard.org gives links and pointers (including source) for data related to Beagle. If some one has done an excellent work on Beagle with a propriety OS, we will give links to his site from beagleboard.org, it’s left to him if he wants to open his source or not.
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
   &lt;b&gt;What software can be downloaded directly from BeagleBoard.org?&lt;/b&gt;
   &lt;br/&gt;
   You will be able to download Linux and Booting S/W directly from the site.  The discussion forums will be organic, growing out of whatever projects are started, not centrally controlled and categorized.  We will educate people how to start their own forums and we will provide a central repository of projects on-going and aggregate news from those projects ala http://planet.maemo.org and others.  The task of the site will to be generate awareness of the projects.
  &lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ol&gt;
</body>
    <http_language>en-us,en;q=0.8,ja;q=0.5,zh;q=0.3</http_language>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/support/faq/edit</http_referer>
    <hop:child idref="324" prototyperef="Page"/>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
