<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3119" name="2013-10-01-project spotlight-facebook-like-counter" prototype="Page" created="1380639813037" lastModified="1380657096671">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-10-01-project spotlight-facebook-like-counter</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">01.10.2013 14:51:36 CDT</time>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.52ryllfm880u</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; Facebook “Like” Counter&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;/br&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            Here’s something we are sure you will ‘Like.’ While at Maker 
            Faire Bay Area this year, we gave away a few BeagleBone Black 
            open-source computers to some lucky faire attendees. We heard back 
            from one of the winners, Christopher Berg, about a creative but 
            functional project he’s created on the board over the past few 
            months that would make Facebook co-founder Mark Zuckerberg quite 
            proud.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
            Christopher made a Facebook “Like” Counter for his wife—an author 
            who was in the middle of writing her first romance novel and was 
            interested in tracking the number of ‘Likes’ on her Facebook page. 
            His device gives his wife a readout of Facebook Likes that is easily 
            readable and constantly updating. According to Christopher, many of 
            his projects are inspired by his family—his kids have been the 
            beneficiaries of many of his projects. (Cool side note—check out 
            the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instructables.com/id/Childs-Quorra-Tron-Costume/&quot;&gt;
            Quorra from Tron costume &lt;/a&gt; he made his daughter for Halloween!)]
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/LT9NDkB.jpg&quot; WIDTH=480 HEIGHT=272
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            The Facebook Like Counter uses the JSON interface provided by 
            Facebook to count the number of Likes for a page. Once it reads the 
            value, the counter updates the display using a simple bit-bang SPI 
            interface. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            “It’s currently a really simple setup, but I’m planning on expanding
            it to provide more metrics, including books sold, Twitter followers, 
            etc.,” said Christopher.    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The part count for the project is really low. Christopher used the 
            BeagleBone Black open-source computer (of course) as well as some 
            jumper wires and a four-digit, seven-segment display that he found 
            on eBay through some friends at &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.43oh.com/topic/2583-spi-4-digit-7-segment-displays/&quot;&gt;43oh.com&lt;/a&gt;.
            The display uses a PT6961 driver from Oasis. Christopher 
            noted the display is “dead-easy to control and has a low pin-count. 
            A few simple SPI commands and you’re good to go.”    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            But why BeagleBone Black? Christopher said he had his eye on 
            BeagleBone for a while.    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            “When the new version came out, including a price drop — I had to 
            have one,” he said.     
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            After years of experience developing projects such as an electronic 
            etch-a-sketch, a &lt;i&gt;Bluetooth&lt;/i&gt;®-controlled RC car and even a retro VFD 
            tube clock on several of TI’s development boards, including his 
            favorite MSP430™ Value Line LaunchPad as well as the Tiva™ C Series 
            LaunchPad and MSP430FR5739 FRAM Experimenter Board, he felt 
            comfortable picking up the TI Sitara™ AM335x processor-based 
            BeagleBone Black computer. In addition, the Ethernet on BeagleBone 
            Black came in handy for this project. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            “When you need a network-enabled board, there’s really no easier way 
            to go,” Christopher said.     
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            With several years of experience developing on TI’s microcontroller-
            based LaunchPads, Christopher admitted that he faced a challenge 
            with this project since he knew almost nothing about Linux. However, 
            he said that the Ångström distribution that comes loaded on 
            BeagleBone Black helped him get the project going without having too 
            much to learn. He used the Cloud9 IDE that comes pre-installed and 
            was able to use JavaScript—something he’s already familiar with 
            since he is a Web developer. Once he started working with the on-
            board software, he was able to get the project up and running fairly 
            quickly.     
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            “I have absolutely no electronics training, but I’m a great example 
            that with the right tools, almost anyone can create these types of 
            projects,” said Christopher.    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            What’s next on Christopher’s list of DIY projects? He said he’s 
            always wanted to create a Hexapod using a BeagleBone Black and a 3D 
            printer. Based on his track record, we can assume it will be awesome!    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            More details about Christopher’s Facebook Like Counter are available 
            at &lt;a href=&quot;http://forum.beaglefu.com/topic/124-facebook-like-counter-7-segment-display-and-cloud9/&quot;&gt;http://forum.beaglefu.com/topic/124-facebook-like-counter-7-segment-display-and-cloud9/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-10-01-project+spotlight-facebook-like-counter/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
