<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3125" name="2013-10-03-beagleboardorg-collaborates-with-arduino" prototype="Page" created="1380827660869" lastModified="1380830740063">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>89.97.163.86</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <uri>2013-10-03-beagleboardorg-collaborates-with-arduino</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_5) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/30.0.1599.66 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <time type="date">03.10.2013 15:05:40 CDT</time>
    <hopsession>89.97.163.kqt0jk66iu0w</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;h1&gt;BeagleBoard.org collaborates in creation of new Arduino TRE&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two open hardware pioneers have combined forces to bring the famously 
easy-to-use experience of Arduino to a high-performance 
ARM&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;-based Linux computer and prototyping platform derived from 
the open hardware designs of BeagleBoard.org and Arduino Leonardo. As an open 
hardware project, BeagleBoard.org&apos;s collaboration with Arduino helps to advance 
accessible technology for artists, designers, hobbyists and anyone interested in 
creating interactive objects or environments everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Arduino familiarity, freed from the tether of a laptop&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For many projects that previously required an external computer, the Arduino 
TRE will provide all the necessary tools on one small board at an affordable 
price with low power consumption. Programmable in Arduino&apos;s highly accessible 
C-derived language with open source roots in Processing and Wiring, Arduino TRE 
enables users to target real-time microcontroller tasks or Linux tasks using 
open source libraries supporting vision and graphics functionality. Arduino TRE 
provides a combination of instant familiarity with a monumental jump in 
performance and available software to extend the experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Arduino TRE features the processor that powers BeagleBone Black, a TI 
Sitara&lt;sup&gt;™&lt;/sup&gt; AM335x. It also features a common footprint and 
electronics as the Arduino Leonardo, enabling compatibility with a huge 
variety of Arduino shields. Further integration includes a 4-port USB hub for 
hosting a large number of standard USB peripherals, a 2-port USB hub on the 
client side for simultaneous access to both integrated processors on-board, a 
stereo audio codec with standard 1/8th&quot; stereo speaker and line-input jacks, a 
dedicated XBee connector for wireless communications and a full-sized HDMI 
connector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;See the pictures below and the post on &lt;a href=&quot;http://arduino.cc/en/Main/ArduinoBoardTre&quot;&gt;arduino.cc&lt;/a&gt;
for additional preview information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/tre/IMG_1241_smaller.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/tre/IMG_1242_smaller.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/tre/IMG_1244_smaller.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/tre/IMG_1246_smaller.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;BeagleBoard.org is a community built on openness and a commitment to 
longevity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For BeagleBoard.org, this alliance is a true honor that we hope will 
positively shape collaboration in the open hardware world moving forward, 
growing the abilities of developers using open tools and advancing open 
hardware platforms optimized for running the largest body of open source 
software. While this will be an Arduino product, supported through the 
Arduino forums, the BeagleBoard.org discussion group has consistently been a 
place for lively discussion of all platforms and pride in BeagleBoard.org 
workmanship is inescapable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While Arduino TRE prototype development was initially done with a relatively 
small group of collaborators, including the BeagleBoard.org Foundation, the 
plan is to now move quickly into an open development phase where broad 
community feedback and contributions will play a critical role in the final 
development of the product. Because of this, we can&apos;t say exactly when the 
final version of the product will ship, but developers can look to be fully 
informed of ongoing development work in the future so they can make informed 
decisions on when to become active with their own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We find incredible satisfaction in this collaboration with Arduino and look forward to working with other individuals and groups who can see benefit in advancing open hardware based platforms optimized for running the most open source software and growing the body of developers using open tools, especially including all existing BeagleBoard.org platforms and the new Arduino TRE. We can&apos;t wait to find out what you will create!&lt;/p&gt;

</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-10-03-beagleboardorg-collaborates-with-arduino/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>jkridner@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
