<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3140" name="2013-10-01-project-spotlight-the-deck" prototype="Page" created="1381242598111" lastModified="1381244686470">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-10-01-project-spotlight-the-deck</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">08.10.2013 10:04:46 CDT</time>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.1t8nxsmzt0qce</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; The Deck&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            Phil Polstra had a problem. He had a vision for a portable 
            penetration testing (pentesting) and forensics device, but he didn’t 
            have the technology he would need to do it. One fateful day at Maker 
            Faire Detroit, Polstra found himself right next to Jason Kridner, 
            who was showing off the (then) new BeagleBoard-xM. “This was my
            first introduction to the Beagles. I was very impressed with the xM 
            and thought I might use them in some future project,” said Polstra.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
           That day, “The Deck” started taking shape.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Polstra began creating a USB forensic device based on BeagleBoard-xM. 
            As he got into his project, he realized that the hardware was very 
            powerful and could handle more than the one simple task he had 
            running on it. He decided to work on creating a full penetrating 
            testing device with the forensic capabilities included. Polstra 
            said, “I became so immersed in developing a penetration testing 
            Linux distribution that I almost forgot to implement the forensics 
            piece!”
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            The original version of the Deck ran on a BeagleBoard-xM attached to 
            a monitor, keyboard and mouse, or to a touchscreen. Polstra 
            installed a portable version in a Buzz Lightyear lunch box with a
            wireless presenter keyboard/mouse, USB hub, network switch and 
            wireless adaptor. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Kku1HLG.jpg&quot; WIDTH=165 HEIGHT=221 alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/BkgHRiz.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
           The Deck can be used to replace a desktop or laptop system used by an 
           information security professional conducting a penetration test. The 
           Deck can also be used as a drop box system. Thanks to its small size 
           and low power requirements, a device running The Deck is easily 
           planted and can run for days off battery power. Unlike many other 
           drop box options, The Deck provides every tool a penetration tester 
           could possible want.  
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/DggiVZn.png&quot; WIDTH=576 HEIGHT=324
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
            The true power of The Deck comes when multiple devices are used in 
            coordination. An army of drones running The Deck can perform 
            coordinated attacks with a command console which is up to a mile 
            away. The drones may also be separated from each other with 
            distances up to a mile. Penetration tests can now be performed 
            poolside at the hotel down the street instead of in the back of a 
            suspicious van in the parking lot.     
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            There is even an aerial drone running The Deck available. The drone 
            can be used as a single attack device, as a router for drones, or as 
            a combination. The aircraft can be flown as an airplane and flown 
            around a target for initial reconnaissance. It is also capable of 
            vertical flight, takeoffs and landings. This capability allows the 
            drone to fly in, land on the roof of a target, hack the target and 
            then fly away.    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            You may have already heard of “The Deck.” This device has already 
            made the news at 
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WzqJeCVK8Wc&quot;&gt;
            44CON&lt;/a&gt;, 
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://media.blackhat.com/eu-13/videos/eu-13-Polstra-mesh-stalkings.mp4&quot;&gt;
            Black Hat Europe&lt;/a&gt;, 
             &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FHJSekw-n3Q&quot;&gt;
            DEFCON&lt;/a&gt;, and GrrCON, where many editors (and even wishful 
            employers!) have taken notice of the project. 
            The Deck has truly taken the industry by storm, 
            inspiring lots of picture-taking, tweeting and texting. Polstra 
            attributes this to the fact that The Deck is flexible as well as a 
            small fraction of the cost of commercial drop boxes. Someone can get 
            started with The Deck running on multiple devices for less than 
            $200, making it attractive to a wide audience of infosec 
            professionals. “Another way to look at it is that I can build an 
            army with more than a dozen devices and an aerial drone for less 
            than the cost of a MacBrook Pro.”     
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Polstra also says that The Deck is one of the first projects where 
            small computer boards are being pushed to do something more than 
            just blink a couple of LEDs as well as one of the first involving 
            multiple devices coordinated via wireless. “The standard model seems 
            to be one penetration tester sitting at a laptop attacking a 
            network. The ability to deploy multiple devices and remove yourself 
            a comfortable distance from the target really opens up the 
            possibilities of doing penetration tests.”. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The Deck runs on BeagleBoard-xM, BeagleBone, and now, BeagleBone 
            Black. The portable unit uses the 7” touchscreen from 
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.BeagleBoardToys.com/&quot;&gt;
            BeagleBoardToys.com&lt;/a&gt;. For a keyboard and mouse, he uses the Favi 
            wireless presenter keyboard/mouse/laser pointer units, which can be 
            found online for about $25. For wireless pentesting, he uses the 
            Alfa AWUS036H adapters because they are cheap, reliable and 
            compatible. Drone communication is via the 802.15.4 Xbee/Zigbee 
            modules from Digi .      
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            “When BeagleBone Black came out, I was elated. Now I had an even 
            more powerful board with HDMI output at half the price of the 
            original BeagleBone. The total cost for a complete device based on 
            the BBB was actually less than what it would cost to attempt to obtain 
            nearly the same results on similar low-cost boards. The HDMI output
            was also a big plus as I now had a device that could be used as a 
            drone or a desktop replacement. Getting the same performance from a 
            $45 BeagleBone Black as what I was used to seeing from the $149
            BeagleBoard-xM was also pretty sweet,” said Polstra. He also credits 
            the BeagleBoard.org community for offering him support while he was
            creating his own Linux distribution.    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            However, Polstra isn’t done with The Deck yet. At the moment, he is 
            working on a cape for connecting the Xbee radios as well as a 
            pwnage cape that would do Xbee and have a USB hub and network 
            switch. Also on the list of future innovations is a cape for 
            operating the aerial drone. He also would like to use a BeagleBone 
            Black computer to replace the autopilot board in the Quadshot 
            aircraft he is using to build his aerial drone. In a perfect world, 
            he says he would develop more of a true unmanned aerial vehicle. “I 
            would like to use a GPS and set of sensors to allow the drone to 
            automatically fly itself to the target and/or circle it. I would 
            also like to install some sensors that would allow the drone to fly 
            away when someone approaches it.”   
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           No doubt, Phil Polstra will be one maker we will continue to follow. 
           You can check out his blog at &lt;a href=&quot;http://polstra.org/&quot;&gt;
            Polstra.org&lt;/a&gt; for more information 
           or updates about The Deck. You can also follow him &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/ppolstra/&quot;&gt;
            (@ppolstra)&lt;/a&gt; on 
           Twitter. And, stay tuned for his book called &lt;i&gt;Hacking and Pentesting 
           with Low-Power Devices&lt;/i&gt; that is due out next summer!    
            &lt;/p&gt;
         
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-10-01-project-spotlight-the-deck/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
