<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3164" name="2013-10-15-project-spotlight-disorient-pyramid" prototype="Page" created="1381847841642" lastModified="1381847841797">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>170.200.168.10</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-10-15-project-spotlight-disorient-pyramid</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">15.10.2013 09:37:21 CDT</time>
    <hopsession>170.200.168.1e7x9k0nvnxda</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; Disorient Pyramid&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            When you think of Pyramids in the middle of the desert, you think of 
            Egypt—not Nevada. The Disorient Pyramid, which was on display at B
            urning Man 2013 this year in the Black Rock Desert of Nevada, is 
            changing all that.
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
         &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/N7s3sDI.jpg&quot; WIDTH=518 HEIGHT=345
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            This year at Burning Man, the Disorient Camp hosted a 23-foot tall 
            pyramid with more than half a kilometer of LED strips. Several 
            artists, including Disorient founder Leo Villareal and Fresno Idea 
            Works’ Jacob Joaquin, designed patterns for the panel. Designs 
            included the double helix of DNA, wiggling snakes and abstract 
            patterns. The pyramid could be seen from almost everywhere on the 
            playa, helping people find the camp and making it a popular place to 
            gather.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            A Sitara-based BeagleBone Black open-source computer running 
            LEDscape drove each face of the pyramid, slicing the images into 
            individual panels. BeagleBone Black then sent each piece to four 
            Teensy 3.0 USB development boards, which drove eight LED strips on 
            each panel. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            A Toughbook ran the pyramidTransmitter code, which rendered the 
            animation frames to 24-bit bitmaps and sent them to the network via 
            USD.   
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The pyramid’s tall panels were powered by 5V 40a power supplies, 
            and the smaller panels were powered by 5V 30A power supplies. The 
            heat and dust caused several of the power supplies to fail, leading 
            the team to do some ad hoc maintenance during Burning Man. 
            Nevertheless, the Disorient Pyramid and its 16,000 LEDs gave quite a 
            show during Burning Man!    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            NYC Resistor has some great pictures of this project at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nycresistor.com/2013/09/05/disorient-pyramid&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
            http://www.nycresistor.com/2013/09/05/disorient-pyramid/&lt;/a&gt;. 
            For more information about the Disorient camp, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://wiki.disorient.info&quot;&gt;
            http://wiki.disorient.info/&lt;/a&gt;

              
            &lt;/p&gt;
         
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-10-15-project-spotlight-disorient-pyramid/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
