<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3189" name="2013-10-22-project-spotlight-octoscroller" prototype="Page" created="1382451987849" lastModified="1383055549535">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-10-22-project-spotlight-octoscroller</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">29.10.2013 09:05:49 CDT</time>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.1eo0jssynttwh</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; The Octoscroller&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            New York is one of the brightest places on Earth. Times Square is 
            definitely a large factor, but now a new BeagleBone Black-based 
            project—the Octoscroller—is adding to the glow.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
             &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/VINl9ZE.jpgg&quot; WIDTH=391 HEIGHT=170
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
           The Octoscroller, which you may have seen at Maker Faire New York a 
           few weeks ago, is a project created by NYC Resistor’s Trammel Hudson 
           and Matt Mets. The Octoscroller is a classic message alert polygon 
           featuring eight 16x32 RGB LED matrix panels. It features LEDS at 
           eight to 16 levels of brightness for each color (producing 
           approximately 12-bit color). The userspace application renders 
           images into a shared memory frame buffer or can receive UDP packets 
           containing video images from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-10-15-project-spotlight-disorient-pyramid/&quot;&gt;Disorient Pyramid&lt;/a&gt;
           transmitter.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Oce4HhQ.jpg&quot; WIDTH=397 HEIGHT=298
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
           The BeagleBone Black open-source computer, based on TI&apos;s Sitara 
           AM335x processor, is the brains behind the operation. The LEDscape 
           custom firmware runs on the AM335x processor’s programmable real-time 
           unit (PRU)—two separate real-time microcontrollers built into the 
           die, with full access to the GPIO lines and cache-coherent access to 
           the main memory. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/osresearch/LEDscape/blob/master/matrix.p&quot;&gt;
           LEDscape custom firmware&lt;/a&gt; allows the user 
           application render into a frame buffer, which is then driven to the 
           Octoscroller’s panels by the PRU. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Trammel and Matt purchased the &lt;a href= &quot;http://www.adafruit.com/products/420&quot;&gt;
            16×32 RGB panels&lt;/a&gt; on the Octoscoller 
            from Adafruit Industries. The panels are very inexpensive since they 
            require continuous refresh by an external driver. With LEDscape, 
            BeagleBone Black can drive up to four chains of four panels, each at 
            0 percent CPU load. The panels are built as six parallel shift 
            registers, each with 32 bits and 12 16-channel constant current LED 
            drivers. The connectors have six data inputs and six control inputs 
            each: F1, G1, B1, R2, G2 and B2; and A, B, C, CLK, LTC and OE. The 
            three address select lines (A, B and C) select which two rows are 
            currently displayed. On each falling edge of the CLK line, a new bit
            is shifted in on the six data inputs. On the falling edge of the LAT 
            line, the new data is latched and, when OE is held low, displayed. 
            To save on GPIO lines, the PRU shares the control lines between all 
            output chains and only needs the six additional data lines per 
            chain. If the HDMI hardware is disabled, four chains can be driven 
            by a single BeagleBone Black. The panels and BeagleBone Black are 
            powered by a &lt;a href= &quot;http://www.adafruit.com/products/658&quot;&gt;
            5V 10A DC supply&lt;/a&gt;.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            If you missed Trammell and Matt’s Octoscroller at Maker Faire New 
            York, find out more about it from Trammell’s 
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nycresistor.com/2013/09/12/octoscroller/&quot;&gt;recent blog post&lt;/a&gt;.  
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;iframe class=&quot;vine-embed&quot; src=&quot;https://vine.co/v/h17j6QuqXxP/embed/simple&quot; width=&quot;695&quot; height=&quot;695&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowTransparency=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;script async src=&quot;//platform.vine.co/static/scripts/embed.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://www.beagleboard.org/blog/2013-10-22-project-spotlight-octoscroller/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>www.beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
