<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3201" name="2013-10-29-project-spotlight-bbot" prototype="Page" created="1383055947329" lastModified="1383056314996">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-10-29-project-spotlight-bbot</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">29.10.2013 09:18:34 CDT</time>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.1eo0jssynttwh</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; BBot robot&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            What’s your perfect vacation? Mine involves sitting out by the pool 
            under the sun as people deliver me ice-cold drinks. Andy Gikling 
            seems to have a similar dream, and he figured out a way to live the 
            good life every weekend—by developing the BBot robot!
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
            The BBot is an open source, remote-controlled drink serving robot. 
            This “cooler camel” puts a cooler on a mini trailer and delivers 
            drinks to people at the pool. As Andy put it, “Why not have a robot 
            go get the drinks?  It’s 2013 people!” And with the ability to haul 
            30-40 lbs, BBot keeps the drinks flowing. This robot does more than 
            just deliver drinks. It can talk to you, see the world around it and 
            even display drink prices and beer advertisements on the screen. One 
            very unique feature is that when people try to steal drinks, the 
            robot kicks on its absurdly loud alarm system.&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
             &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/WBwyHff.jpg&quot; WIDTH=336 HEIGHT=554
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
           Andy used 900 MHz XBee radios to transport remote control data from 
           the Microsoft .NET GUI to BeagleBone Black. XBee connectivity 
           enables very long range control, making it possible to “order” drinks 
           from miles away. “The XBee radios were a treat to finally work with,” 
           said Andy.  “They are so cool and simple to use.” 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           The BeagleBone Black computer is the brain of the device. It parses 
           the data and routes it to the various control systems on the robot. 
           “There’s nothing like it with as much computing power, flexibility, 
           and size of active community at the $45 price point,” said Andy. 
           “I needed the vast number if I/O found on BeagleBone Black for my 
           robot. I love how small it is too!” It also provided Andy with a 
           great way to learn more about Linux and C++. “Although BeagleBone 
           Black is rather new, there are an amazing number of sources on the 
           Internet that show you how to do common things,” said Andy. He 
           specifically credited &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/user/DerekMolloyDCU&quot;&gt;
           Derek Molloy’s videos&lt;/a&gt; for helping him go from 
           “zero to hero” with some of the software development challenges he 
           faced.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Andy stacked a &lt;a href=&quot;http://valentfx.com&quot;&gt;ValentFX&lt;/a&gt; FPGA cape 
            on top of BeagleBone Black to 
            provide a robust means of low-level hardware interfacing. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Andy coded the names of the classes and variables to be 
            anthropomorphic. For example, rather than calling the code that runs 
            the robot’s wheels “Motors.cpp” or “Drives.cpp,” he named them 
            things like “Voice.cpp” and “Legs.cpp.”  Functions might be “Walk  
            int speed );” instead of “Drive ( int speed );.” The GUI follows the 
            same trend, with the main window user controls named things like 
            “eye ball,” “legs,” and “voice.” Each control communicates with one 
            of BBot’s systems. Another cool feature of the GUI is that the user 
            can connect it to a Leap Motion controller so that the robot can be 
            driven by a simple wave of the hand above the sensor! 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            Andy says that the robot has a fairly simple mechanical design. The 
            main chasse consists of some simple Plexiglas disks stacked on top 
            of each other with threaded steel rods, nuts and washers. Everything 
            for the mechanical assembly can be purchased at a hardware store.
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            It seems like BBot already has it all, but Andy has plans to keep 
            adding features to the platform. He would like to add a precision 
            pan/tilt camera system and incorporate a tracking algorithm called 
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://personal.ee.surrey.ac.uk/Personal/Z.Kalal/tld.html&quot;&gt;
            TLD&lt;/a&gt; so that the robot can follow its user around. He is also 
            contemplating having the main data, video and audio link run 
            through the cell network so he can approach people on the street and 
            offer them a free soda from a friendly and seemingly autonomous 
            robot!
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
           Want your own BBot? (We do too!) Working source code, photos, video 
           and documentation can be found at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/andygikling/BBot&quot;&gt;
           https://github.com/andygikling/BBot&lt;/a&gt;.
           &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://www.beagleboard.org/blog/2013-10-29-project-spotlight-bbot/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>www.beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
