<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3212" name="2013-11-05-project-spotlight-grannycam" prototype="Page" created="1383665837825" lastModified="1383666461899">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-11-05-project-spotlight-grannycam</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">05.11.2013 09:47:41 CST</time>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.bkl1a6ync9q</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; GrannyCam&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            The holidays are around the corner, and with them come the fun and 
            excitement of big family gatherings. However, a lot of families are 
            spread across the country and not able to get together for the 
            holidays. That’s why Charles Hamilton developed GrannyCam, a safe, 
            durable videophone that his kids can use to stay in touch with their 
            grandparents, not only during the holiday season but throughout the 
            year. In September, the device received great response and an 
            Editor’s Choice Blue Ribbon from Make Magazine at Maker Faire New 
            York.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
             &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/mTR7tVH.jpg&quot; WIDTH=384 HEIGHT=512
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
           GrannyCam is a wireless, portable, one-touch videophone designed to 
           be extremely simple and friendly to operate so seniors and their 
           young grandchildren can video chat anytime. “The project grew from 
           observing my mother and two-year-old son, who struggled with the 
           typical tools—smartphones, computers, tablets —available for speaking 
           to one another. For my mom, now in her 70s, the tools currently 
           available are an enormous challenge: too feature-laden, too complex. 
           For my son, the tools are also challenging, but for slightly 
           different reasons: too easily broken or disconnected, too expensive 
           to handle unsupervised, too fraught with concerns over privacy,” said 
           Charles. GrannyCam enabled Charles’s little boy to speak to his 
           grandma without help so that they can more easily keep in touch. 
           “GrannyCam provides a quick and easy way to share the latest progress 
           in our son’s development and provides an opportunity for increased 
           socialization and improvements in our toddler’s speech.”  
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           GrannyCam’s external design is friendly for both grandmas and 
           toddlers. The hardware is covered in a soft, crocheted shell. A 
           physical button includes an oversized “arcade-style” button for both 
           initiating and accepting a chat session. The button also flashes to 
           alert an end user that they have an incoming call. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/V8EuQSB.jpg&quot; WIDTH=367 HEIGHT=490
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            The current GrannyCam prototype is built around the 
            Sitara-processor-based BeagleBone Black 
            open-source computer, which connects to an LCD screen, a webcam and 
            a sound card. Devices communicate with each other over Wi-Fi 
            (dongled) via open-source VoIP/SIP software. No cellular connection 
            is planned as part of the design roadmap. Power supply is currently 
            AC, though one of Charles’s next goals is to upgrade to rechargeable 
            DC. Configuration of the devices is done remotely via command line 
            or browser.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/y7cd8Hg.jpg&quot; WIDTH490 HEIGHT=367
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Charles says he chose the BeagleBone Black to power GrannyCam 
            because its high performance enables delivery of simultaneous voice 
            and video for chat sessions, and its truly open source design 
            provides significant advantages for the long-term design criteria of 
            the device. After trying out Ångström and Debian distributions, 
            Charles finally settled on Ubuntu 12.04 as it is the most stable in 
            handling the video chat client software. Charles said he is 
            currently also investigating a port of Tizen onto BeagleBone Black 
            with a port of a SIP client package as well. He is hoping these 
            options may lead to a better solution with higher data throughput, 
            viz., smoother video and better audio quality.  
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Charles was able to rapidly prototype GrannyCam and is now 
            generating user feedback and gauging interest in the device as a 
            potential product. His long-term vision for GrannyCam is to create 
            a product that is scalably manufactured and leverages open-source 
            hardware and software. The product path includes a design for a 
            modular platform that can add sensors to make the device a more 
            integrated part of the home monitoring landscape for seniors.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            For more information about GrannyCam, visit 
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://hudsonwerks.com/current-projects/grannycam&quot;&gt;
            http://hudsonwerks.com/current-projects/grannycam/&lt;/a&gt;. 
            You can also check out Charles’s blogs on &lt;a href=&quot;http://hudsonhardwear.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;
            DIY electronics and hardware products&lt;/a&gt; as well as 
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://uxhealth.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;tech trends in health and wellness&lt;/a&gt;.    
                            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://www.beagleboard.org/blog/2013-11-05-project-spotlight-GrannyCam/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>www.beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
