<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3224" name="Page" prototype="Page" created="1383837369316" lastModified="1383850734276">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>98.250.142.42</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <uri>2013-11-07-project-spotlight-growcubes</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_5) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/30.0.1599.101 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <time type="date">07.11.2013 12:58:54 CST</time>
    <hopsession>98.250.142.1r21z81a3slbu</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;script&gt;window.location=&quot;/blog/2013-11-07-project-spotlight-growcubes/&quot;;&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; GrowCubes&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            Open-source technology is all about getting the power of technology 
            into the hands of everyone. That’s why we at BeagleBoard.org really 
            like the idea of GrowCubes —stackable, modular farming environments 
            that use mobile technology and aeroponics to grow delicious, 
            organic produce indoors—using 90% less water. Developed by a team 
            at NYC Resistor (NYCR), GrowCubes democratize agriculture by placing 
            the power to grow back into the hands of individuals and 
            communities. “It’s based on the radical idea that food should be 
            healthy, tasty and accessible to all,” said Chris Beauvois, founder 
            of GrowCubes. This idea of open-source agriculture has implications 
            not only for culinary culture, but for some of the urgent public 
            health issues facing us today.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/B8l4bwF.jpg&quot; height=&quot;324&quot; width=&quot;480&quot;&gt;
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           According to Chris, developing GrowCubes was very challenging. 
           “Aeroponics is a delicate process, and we spent more than a year 
           developing our misting hardware alone.” In addition to these 
           aeroponic spray misters, the system also includes a network of 
           sensors and data from the Internet to give the system intel about 
           what each plant needs. With this information, GrowCubes automatically 
           rotate shelves, ensuring plants get the best possible light. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/FHdLIQT.png&quot; height=&quot;280&quot; width=&quot;282&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            GrowCubes are powered by BeagleBone Black. Chris and his team at 
            NYCR chose BeagleBone Black for its high performance, large GPIO 
            pin count and the added real-time performance of the programmable 
            real-time unit (PRU) within TI’s Sitara AM335x processor. 
            “BeagleBone Black is the most complete solution of any kind and is 
            especially suited to handling the complexities of our product,” 
            said Chris.
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Now that the NYCR team has its project complete, it plans to build 
            a large run of GrowCubes to distribute to public schools in New York 
            City.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           GrowCubes is currently a contender in Engadget’s Insert Coin: New 
           Challengers competition, where readers can vote for the most 
           promising crowd-funding hardware. Online voting starts at 5 p.m. EST 
           on Saturday, Nov. 9 and ends at 4:30 p.m. on Sunday, Nov. 10. 
           If you are inspired by what GrowCubes can do for agriculture in our 
           cities (or anywhere else for that matter), consider voting for them 
           &lt;a href=&quot;http://insertcoin2.engadget.com&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  
            &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           Want even more information about GrowCubes? The best place to start 
           at the moment is &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/16nmQWR&quot;&gt;this YouTube video&lt;/a&gt;. 
           You can also check out Chris Beauvois’ interview with Mike Riggs at 
           &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theatlanticcities.com/technology/2013/10/computer-assisted-aeroponic-growing-future-urban-farming/7207/&quot;&gt;
           The Atlantic Cities blog&lt;/a&gt;. And 
           lastly, tune into MSNBC at 4 p.m. on Sunday, Nov. 10. Chris will be 
           a featured guest!     
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
           
         
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/2013-11-07-project-spotlight-growcubes/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>jkridner@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
