<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3236" name="2013-11-12-project-spotlight-openrov" prototype="Page" created="1384268436085" lastModified="1384269537224">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>170.200.168.24</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-11-12-project-spotlight-openrov</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">12.11.2013 09:18:57 CST</time>
    <hopsession>170.200.168.1kw73ry335myx</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; OpenROV&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            Whether you want to explore the seas for science and education, 
            “snorkel” for fish and coral without getting wet, or hunt for 
            buried treasure in unexplored seas, OpenROV is something you need 
            to check out!
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
           David Lang and Eric Stackpole created OpenROV—an underwater robot 
           that can be controlled with a laptop—in a garage in Cupertino, Calif. 
           with the goal of exploring an underwater cave. After finding a global 
           community of co-developers on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/openrov/openrov-the-open-source-underwater-robot&quot;&gt;
           Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;, the project evolved, 
           developing into a global community of DIY ocean explorers who are 
           using and improving the OpenROV design. The community gathers 
           everyone from professional ocean engineers and software developers 
           to hobbyists and students, all who want to learn and explore the 
           oceans and lakes of the world. Adventurous souls can make their own 
           OpenROV from scratch, using design files on OpenROV.com for support. 
           Explorers also can 
           &lt;a href=&quot;http://openrov.myshopify.com/collections/frontpage/products/openrov-2-5-kit&quot;&gt;
           buy an OpenROV kit&lt;/a&gt;, which comes with all the 
           hardware needed to assemble your own OpenROV, for only $849.00.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ztgni0G.jpg&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; width=&quot;561&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            
            &lt;img src=&quot;&quot;http://i.imgur.com/xbgdxLp.jpg&quot; height=&quot;374&quot; width=&quot;561&quot;
           The newest OpenROV robot—OpenROV 2.5—was introduced in September 
           2013. It is now powered by the Sitara-processor-based BeagleBone Black 
           (it was formerly powered by the original BeagleBone), enabling lower 
           cost and higher performance robots. Its many other upgrades include a 
           durable polypropylene shell, more efficient propellers, added buoyancy 
           to support more payloads, more robust battery tubes, and laser range 
           and size calculating capability. These submarine-like robots are 
           open-source, enabling anyone to hack them to add new features and 
           functionality. David and Eric say the robot kit can be built in a 
           single weekend, so you can kick off your treasure hunt in no time, 
           even without a degree in engineering!
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            OpenROV sounds cool, but it’s even more impressive in action. Check 
            out CNN’s video of OpenROV to see how it works:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/ko7wwbB-0lw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           There are now more than 500 OpenROVs swimming in more than 50 
           countries around the world. Want to explore your own unchartered 
           waters? Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://openrov.com&quot;&gt;OpenROV.com&lt;/a&gt; to find out more.
            &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           If you want to hear more about David Lang’s leap into the Maker 
           movement and how he grew to be a successful entrepreneur, check out 
           his new book &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Zero-Maker-Learn-Enough-Anything/dp/1449356435&quot;&gt;
           &lt;i&gt;Zero to Maker: Learn (Just Enough) to Make (Just About) 
           Anything&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
           
         
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-11-12-project-spotlight-openrov/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
