<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3253" name="2013-11-19-project-spotlight-opensprinkler" prototype="Page" created="1384872729572" lastModified="1384893665778">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>192.94.94.106</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8,fr;q=0.6</http_language>
    <uri>2013-11-19-project-spotlight-opensprinkler</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/31.0.1650.57 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <time type="date">19.11.2013 14:41:05 CST</time>
    <hopsession>192.94.94.xs34jwl5fy80</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; Open Sprinkler Beagle (OSBo)&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            Planning to buy a sprinkler timer for your loved ones this holiday 
            season? Have no fear, OpenSprinkler is here! Developed by Ray Wang 
            at Rayshobby LLC, OpenSprinkler Beagle—nicknamed OSBo—was released 
            last week. It is an open-source sprinkler/irrigation extension 
            board for the Sitara-processor-based BeagleBone Black. The board 
            helps you easily develop BeagleBone Black into a low-cost, 
            web-connected smart sprinkler controller. It comes with a 
            full-featured sprinkler scheduling program, uses online weather 
            data to help regulate water time, and enables users to remotely 
            change setting and programs while away from home. It works with the 
            standard 24VAC sprinkler valves commonly found in household 
            watering and irrigation systems and allows for an unlimited number 
            of water zones to be individually controlled. Because it’s open 
            source, it offers a lot of flexibility in features and 
            functionality. Users are encouraged to hack the hardware and/or 
            software (written in Python, which is easy to learn). 
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/bRHA9fA.jpg&quot; height=&quot;308&quot; width=&quot;410&quot;&gt;
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           What motivated Ray to create such an innovative and futuristic 
           project? Ray wanted to provide a solution to the limited set of 
           fixed functionality and outdated user interface that come with most 
           commercial sprinkler timers or controllers. Ray even included a 
           relay on OSBo and hopes it can be used for opening/closing garage 
           doors as well at some point in the future! 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Ray has made several other versions of OpenSprinkler based on other 
            low-cost computers, but he selected BeagleBone Black for the newest 
            version to add even more features thanks to the large number of 
            GPIO pins, built-in analog pins, eMMC, microSD card, and the 
            high-performance Sitara AM335x processor from TI. The OSBo board 
            contains a 24VAC to 5VDC switching regulator, shift register, 
            triacs, terminal blocks, a zone expansion board connector, a rain 
            sensor terminal, and a mini-relay. It provides 5V power to 
            BeagleBone Black and uses four GPIO pins to interface with the 
            shift register as well as SDA2/SCL2 to interface with the DS1307 
            RTC. The BeagleBone Black computer is oriented face-down, and it 
            plugs directly into the extra-long male pin headers. The biggest 
            advantage of the face-down design is doesn’t necessitate cables, 
            thus there is extra space in the upper-half of the enclosure that 
            makes it possible to add additional modules. To make it easy to 
            reuse the available pins on BeagleBone Black, Ray also mapped out 
            all of the 46 pins on ports P8 and P9 to the pinout area.
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
         &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/lve68f3.jpg&quot; height=&quot;308&quot; width=&quot;410&quot;&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Check out the OSBo homepage at &lt;a href=&quot;http://beagle.opensprinkler.com&quot;&gt;
            http://beagle.opensprinkler.com&lt;/a&gt; for 
            more information or to purchase the OSBO v1 open-source sprinkler / 
            irrigation extension board. You can also stay up to date on what 
            Ray is developing on his blog at &lt;a href=&quot;http://rayshobby.net/?page_id=1857&quot;&gt;
            http://blog.rayshobby.net&lt;/a&gt;.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
           
         
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-11-19-project-spotlight-opensprinkler/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>jessica.lynne.callaway@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
