<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3260" name="2013-11-26-project-spotlight-dirty-dish-detector" prototype="Page" created="1385474550978" lastModified="1385474598825">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>170.200.168.24</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-11-26-project-spotlight-dirty-dish-detector</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">26.11.2013 08:03:18 CST</time>
    <hopsession>170.200.168.19saai25uvil5</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; Dirty Dish Detector&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            Thanksgiving is one of my favorite holidays. My family usually runs 
            a turkey trot together, makes and eats great food, and spends the 
            evening playing board games. The one down side of Thanksgiving is 
            all of those dirty dishes! Sometimes I think it takes more time to 
            clean up than we even spend eating turkey dinner. The result? The 
            family falls asleep on the floor (thanks tryptophan!) before all of 
            the dishes are cleaned up, leaving a mess in the kitchen sink.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/bRHA9fA.jpg&quot; height=&quot;308&quot; width=&quot;410&quot;&gt;
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           Lucky for us all, &lt;a href=&quot;https://london.hackspace.org.uk/&quot;&gt;London Hackspace&lt;/a&gt; member
           Tom created the Dirty Dish Detector to help keep the hackspace sink 
           clean. The system alerts users when a dish has been left in the sink 
           for too long, ensuring you’ll get all of those dishes cleaned up 
           before napping ensues. The Dirty Dish Detector uses a webcam above 
           the sink, hooked to a BeagleBone open-source computer, based on TI’s 
           Sitara AM335x processor. The computer runs the HoughCircles function 
           in OpenCV to detect circle-shaped items like plates, classes and 
           bowls. BeagleBone then sends a signal to an Arduino, which deploys 
           different alerts (based on how long the sink has been full) to 
           remind people to clean up their dishes. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Tom has a few upgrades planned that may help us catch more criminals 
            by next year’s Thanksgiving! Right now, cutlery can escape the gaze 
            of OpenCV since it isn’t circular. Next year’s offenders will be 
            caught red-handed for cutlery misdeeds. Tom plans to add a 
            camera to catch mugshots of these dish delinquents as well. 
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Want to make your own Dirty Dish Detector? Visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fridgehead/Dish-Detector&quot;&gt;
                Tom&apos;s GitHub site&lt;/a&gt; to find the code!
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
           
         
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-11-26-project-spotlight-dirty-dish-detector/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
