<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3266" name="2013-12-03-project-spotlight-uss-langley" prototype="Page" created="1386083949026" lastModified="1386084793308">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-12-03-project-spotlight-uss-langley</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">03.12.2013 09:33:13 CST</time>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.xc6ewt3e9nc3</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone-xM project spotlight:&lt;br&gt; USS Langley Space Server&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            You’ve heard of monkeys and apes being sent to space, but did you 
            know a Beagle is also being launched into the ether? In 2014, Sam 
            Sipe and his team at the U.S. Naval Academy are launching a 
            BeagleBoard-xM into space as part of their Unix Space Server.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           Sam Sipe got the idea for a Linux-based, open-source webserver in 
           space during his sophomore year at the Academy. “I was taking EA204, 
           which is our introduction to Astronautical Engineering course, while 
           simultaneously teaching myself web code for an unrelated venture. 
           Eventually I asked my instructor, CDR Blocker, why there weren’t any 
           TCP/IP-capable satellites in low-earth orbit — less than 1,200 miles 
           in altitude. He suggested that I do more research and report back. 
           This, in turn, turned into an independent research project the next 
           semester,” said Sam.  Sam fully fleshed out the project, deciding to 
           develop a 3U CubeSat that will host a webserver in space. This small 
           satellite server would provide a faster link between clients and 
           hosts without needing to use the terrestrial network. Titled USS 
           Langley after the first aircraft carrier, this space server is now a 
           Capstone Senior Design Project at the Academy.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
             &lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/C8VpHTu.jpg&quot; WIDTH=221 HEIGHT=294 alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/fwLxdeH.jpg&quot; Width=221 Height=294 alt=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/t2XDLsf.jpg&quot; Width=392 Height=294 alt=&quot;3&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;p&gt;
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
            The USS Langley development team is made up of eight undergraduate 
            students and two professors. The team chose to base USS Langley on 
            a BeagleBoard-xM open-source computer, powered by a TI Sitara 
            processor. “We chose the BeagleBoard-xM because of its small form 
            factor, customizability, and low power requirements,” said Sam.
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            The project has not been without its challenges, according to Sam. 
            “The biggest problem when designing a satellite with non-space-rated 
            hardware is verifying that it will do what you need it to do in 
            space, with no heat convection, no air, huge swings in temperature, 
            and radiation. This has been overcome with testing and modification 
            flight hardware,” said Sam. Another major concern that the team has 
            dealt with regularly is finding continued funding. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The team has secured a spot on a launch set for late 2014, and it 
            will deliver the satellite early in the summer. Keep your eyes on 
            the skies to see USS Langley in action!
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/1ARjvxh.jpg&quot; Width=480 Height=264
             &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            While Sam himself may not be going to space, he will be going 
            through flight school after he graduates from the Academy in May. 
            Sam is definitely one to keep an eye on in the future! If you want 
            to find out more about USS Langley or keep tabs on Sam’s projects, 
            you can visit his personal website at 
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://samsipe.com/#/research&quot;&gt;http://samsipe.com/#/research&lt;/a&gt;.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
           
         
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-12-03-project-spotlight-uss-langley/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
