<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3282" name="2013-12-10-project-spotlight-lasersaur" prototype="Page" created="1386629815226" lastModified="1386629934154">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>170.200.128.10</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-12-10-project-spotlight-lasersaur</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">09.12.2013 16:58:54 CST</time>
    <hopsession>170.200.128.1s7jy11phf90g</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt;The Lasersaur&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            Addie Wagenknecht and Stefan Hachenberger, co-founders of NORDT 
            Labs, have many secret talents. Addie can bake some mean chocolate 
            chip cookies at 15,000+ feet in high winds on a mountain, and she 
            can open a beer bottle with just about anything (like a lighter) 
            thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://sternlab.org/&quot;&gt;Becky Stern&lt;/a&gt;. 
            Stefan, on the other hand, makes the best &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kaiserschmarrn&quot;&gt;
            kiserschmann&lt;/a&gt; in Austria, according to Addie. But their most 
            recent project—the Lasersaur—shows their best talent yet.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           The Lasersaur is an open source laser cutter. With CAD drawings, 
           circuit schematics, software and a bill of materials available from 
           NORTD Labs, end users can build these laser cutters themselves. The 
           Lasersaur was designed to fill the needs of makers, artists and 
           scientists who want a safe and highly capable machine.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/smTOD65.jpg&quot; WIDTH=400 HEIGHT=267
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
            When Addie and Stefan designed the Lasersaur, they weren’t 
            interested in building the cheapest machine. They were interested 
            in building a platform that is sourceable worldwide, simple to 
            build, reproduce, duplicate and understand, dependable after 
            hundreds of hours of use, and safe. They want the end users to 
            truly own it and have access to all the designs that went into it.
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            “We had spent thousands of hours on other people’s laser cutters 
            while in graduate school. We depended on the systems, yet they were 
            expensive and frustrating to use,” said Addie. “The software was 
            often horrible. We would have to run some obscure machine, running 
            CorelDrAW, and transfer everything from our OSX or Ubuntu systems to 
            do it. We felt like it could be done better, and for a lot less than
            what it would cost to buy ready-made.” 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            As a result of this experience, Addie and Stefan have written the 
            Lasersaur’s open-source software and plug-ins from the ground up, 
            and according to Addie, they “will do things you have never seen 
            before—open-source software or not. It is locally hosted and can 
            run off of any web browser, which means you don&apos;t have to install 
            additional software or extensions to get it to cut. It&apos;s plug and 
            play.”
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Addie and Stefan haven’t fully opened the source for the Lasersaur 
            yet, but hacker spaces in Philadelphia, Dublin and Tokyo; labs at 
            Carnegie Mellon, NYU and the University of São Paulo; and many 
            individuals have already built their own Lasersaur.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The Lasersaur is based on BeagleBone Black, powered by TI’s Sitara 
            AM335x processor. Addie and Stefan chose this computer because they 
            were interested in continuing to work with and support Linux. 
            “Since Ångström was pre-installed, we were able to continue to use 
            Ubuntu for the Lasersar. We found BeagleBone Black plays well with 
            USB peripherals like Wi-Fi dongles. It was rather painless to get 
            the Lasersaur image configured onto BeagleBone Black, so it felt 
            like a shoo-in. As a bonus, it’s globally available, stable, easy 
            to pick up, learn and hack, and the price is right!” said Addie. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Lasersaurs are built to use 40-200 watt carbon dioxide lasers and to 
            have a bed size of 24 × 48 in (61 × 120 cm). They are comprised of 
            both stationary and dynamic parks. The primary building blocks of 
            both the frame and the ganty are T-slot aluminum extrusions bolted 
            together with M5 bolts and T-slot nuts. The Lasersaur is designed 
            around extrusions with 20, 40 and 80 mm side lengths. All of the
            mount assemblies are built from angle brackets. A few parts are 
            custom-cut 6 mm acrylic (or more recently, aluminum) pieces. CAD 
            drawings for the acrylic parts are freely available and can be made 
            using a laser cutter - and should they fail, they may be replaced 
            with spare parts made by the Lasersaur itself. Aluminum versions of 
            those parts may be purchased from the NORTD Labs store, or users can 
            have them cut somewhere. No proprietary rails and carriage 
            assemblies are used. The Lasersaur carriages are built from 
            standard-sized ball bearings (with nylon coating), cap screws and 
            custom-cut acrylic or metal pieces.    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            According to Addie, the biggest issue has been funding. “At first we 
            used &lt;a href =&quot;http://www.kickstarter.com/projects/nortd/lasersaur-open-source-laser-cutter-0&quot;&gt;
            Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;. At some point far enough into development, we were 
            able to take fellowships and residencies to further fund the 
            project and push it forward. We also put our own money and time 
            into it. At some point, the community support allowed the project 
            to almost become self-sustained. We hope to get the financial and 
            social capital to 100% one day. University builds like that of 
            Carnegie Melon and New York University have been a big help to the 
            exposure of the project.”    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            For more information about Lasersaur, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lasersaur.com&quot;&gt;Lasersaur.com&lt;/a&gt;. 
            Addie and Stefan have completed many other successful projects. To 
            find about more about them, visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://labs.nortd.com/&quot;&gt;the NORTD Labs website&lt;/a&gt;. 
            And definitely stay tuned: they’ve been toying with an interesting 
            idea for an open-source industrial robotic arm! 
                
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
           
    
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-12-10-project-spotlight-lasersaur/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
