<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3294" name="USB_Hotplugging" prototype="Page" created="1386855369006" lastModified="1386855369008">
  <hop:parent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <edit_skin>edit_project</edit_skin>
    <updatetime type="date">12.12.2013 07:36:09 CST</updatetime>
    <uri>USB_Hotplugging</uri>
    <time type="date">12.12.2013 07:36:09 CST</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <registrant>emagii.myopenid.com</registrant>
    <pname>Beaglebone Black USB Hotplugging</pname>
    <user>emagii.myopenid.com</user>
    <categories>distro,library,utility</categories>
    <body>&lt;section class=&quot;fl description rounded shadow&quot;&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;user-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project aims to solve the Hotplugging problem with the USB host&lt;br /&gt; driver on the Texas Instruments AM335x processor on the Beaglebone Black.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My name is Ulf Samuelsson, and eMagii is my own company.&lt;br /&gt; In my previous career, I was an application engineer for Atmel, and provided&lt;br /&gt; a lot of patches to the OpenEmbedded project and Buildroot free of charge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now I work as a consultant, but would&amp;nbsp; like to continue to work in these&lt;br /&gt; projects, but beeing self-employed this will not bring any bread to the table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Selected the USB hotplugging problem as a test, if this is feasible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What We Need &amp;amp; What You Get&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Building Angstrom is quite time consuming, so I have invested in a workstation&lt;br /&gt; allowing me to reduce the buildtime from more than 3 hours, to less than one and a half.&lt;br /&gt; This cost me $3-4k.&lt;br /&gt; Will also pay for engineering time invested in this project. &lt;br /&gt; Normally I can charge $125/hour as a consultant, and hopefully crowdfunding will make commercial sense, as long as I can solve real critical problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If this works out OK, then I hope to look into how to configure the Beaglebone&lt;br /&gt; using a WiFi dongle in SoftAP mode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;USB and hotplugging is like bread and butter. It is expected to work. Right now,&amp;nbsp; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first attempt at crowd-sourcing, but as you can see from the video in the Gallery, it already works on my system!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Ways You Can Help&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Really, it is Texas Instruments that is is responsible for getting their BSP to work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Talked to them, and they said they would solve it internally in 3.12-rc1, but according to&lt;br /&gt;people testing 3.12, the problem remains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not ask your local Texas Instruments to get the meta-beaglebone source code&lt;br /&gt; and have them release to the public?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/section&gt;</body>
    <errmsg></errmsg>
    <homepage>http://igg.me/at/eMagii/x/5581172</homepage>
    <render_skin>project</render_skin>
    <shortdesc>This crowdfunding project aims to solve the Hotplugging problem with the USB host driver on the Texas Instruments AM335x processor on the Beaglebone Black.</shortdesc>
    <rssfeed></rssfeed>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
