<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3315" name="2013-12-17-project-spotlight-orbital-rendersphere" prototype="Page" created="1387297627770" lastModified="1387298451422">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>170.200.168.24</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2013-12-17-project-spotlight-orbital-rendersphere</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">17.12.2013 10:40:51 CST</time>
    <hopsession>170.200.168.x61owavre70q</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt;Orbital Rendersphere&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            If you went to Maker Faire New York this year, you could not have 
            missed the Orbital Rendersphere. This “Big Giant Spinning Limb 
            Slicer,” as the &lt;a href = &quot;http://blog.makerbar.com/&quot;&gt;Hoboken MakerBar&lt;/a&gt;   
            team affectionately calls it, displays images and videos on a 
            four-foot diameter spherical surface using persistence of vision 
            (POV) spinning at 450 RPM. It had a constant crowd surrounding it 
            and earned five ribbons at the faire: four Editor’s Choice ribbons 
            and one Educator’s Choice ribbon.
    &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
             &lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/3DZjBwA.jpg&quot; WIDTH=263 HEIGHT=350 alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/KEUsf0x.jpg&quot; Width=466 Height=350 alt=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;p&gt;
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           The Orbital Rendersphere started out as an idea for an entry into the 
           2013 Red Bull Creation Contest in April 2013. Red Bull sent the crew 
           at Maker Bar a number of LED strips and asked them to build something 
           cool out of it. They developed the idea, and then started building 
           only a few days before the contest deadline. After spending a crazy 
           weekend working like madmen on the project, the Orbital Rendersphere 
           didn’t orbit! The team decided that the project was too good to let 
           die, so they set their sights on having the project done by Maker 
           Faire New York. The team also decided to set their sights higher for 
           what they wanted the display to do. They increased the size and 
           resolution of the display and redesigned it to be able to display
           video at 30 frames per second by spinning four vertical LED strips 
           spaced 90 degrees apart at 450 RPM, or 7.5 rotations per second!
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
            After first experimenting with microcontrollers, the team selected 
            BeagleBone Black, to power the Rendersphere’s 36 feet of WS80211 LED 
            strips. BeagleBone provided much more memory to accommodate 
            larger image data and was able to update the LED strips extremely 
            quickly through the use of Trammel Hudson&apos;s LEDScape code. The 
            LEDScape code uses the programmable real-time units (PRU) on the 
            Texas Instruments Sitara AM335x processor that powers BeagleBone 
            Black to update multiple LED strips simultaneously with very little 
            burden on the CPU. The team also uses a custom circuit board to 
            buffer and connect GPIO outputs to the LED strips.
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            The main controller is a Mac Mini mounted in a custom arcade 
            console. Every frame of video is rendered on this console and 
            streamed over Wi-Fi to reduce the number of wires needed—normal 
            wires don’t work for a POV display because they would get tangled 
            up from all of the spinning. Because of this challenge, all of the 
            brains required to run the display are mounted to the spinning part 
            and spin along with the display.  
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/LMfUfOq.jpg&quot; WIDTH=365 HEIGHT=274
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The only wires the team required between the spinning and 
            non-spinning part were for the power and ground connections. The 
            team ran these lines from the power supply (3 10-amp 5V power 
            supplies), one to the top and the other to the bottom of the axle 
            where they contacted copper slip rings, and then distributed power 
            to everything on the spinning part.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The Orbital Rendersphere frame presented the team with another 
            challenge. The team needed to create a frame that offers structural 
            stability, provides good visibility to the display and can be 
            quickly assembled/dissembled for transport. The team created a 
            modular frame design that provides unobstructed views of the 
            display from three sides, bolts together quickly, and fits in a 
            single van.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Now that the team had a desired rotation rate for the display and a 
            frame to offer stability, they had to figure out how to actually 
            spin the display. They tried a number of different configurations, 
            but in the end, the simplest idea was the best. They mounted an 
            electric heavy duty hand drill (Harbor Freight) to the top of the 
            frame and used it to spin the axle. This provided a nice solution 
            since hand drills have built-in high-torque axial transmission, 
            which allows the Orbital Rendersphere to spin up gradually from a 
            dead stop without slipping or burning out the motor.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            We asked Travis what his team at MakerBar has coming down the pipe. 
            He said that they going to scale up the concept they’ve started. 
            “We don’t want to spoil the surprise, but it’s going to be BIG!” 
            Travis said. He also invited others with a love for electronics and 
            a passion for making cool projects to “come down, share your 
            projects or ideas, have a beer with us, and share in our passion for 
            all things electric!” Whether you make it to Hoboken or not, 
            hopefully we’ll see more of the Orbital Rendersphere (or the big 
            next generation) at Maker Faire 2014!    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            For more information about MakerBar, or to help out and support 
            The Orbital Rendersphere project, check out their &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/themakerbar&quot;&gt;
            Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/makerbar/&quot;&gt;Twitter feed&lt;/a&gt; 
            and &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.makerbar.com/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.
                
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
           
    
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2013-12-17-project-spotlight-orbital-rendersphere/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
