<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3385" name="2014-01-14-project-spotlight-volumio" prototype="Page" created="1389713509139" lastModified="1389713630149">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2014-01-14-project-spotlight-volumio</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">14.01.2014 09:33:50 CST</time>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.1qpqf6tz445rg</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt;Volumio&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            What is your go-to activity when you can’t sleep? For some it’s 
            reading a book or counting sheep, but for music and technology 
            enthusiast Michelangelo Guarise, it’s Volumio.
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           Volumio is a free and open-source Linux Audiophile music player for 
           embedded computers that, when paired with the Sitara-powered 
           BeagleBone Black, can transform an entire building into a connected 
           audio center. Inspired by his passion for music, Guarise worked 
           tirelessly on Volumio with the help of users worldwide. 
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
            “What you have here is the result of sleepless coding nights, 
            precious feedbacks from our users, and a pure, intense, visceral 
            passion for music and technology,” Guarise said. 
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            In fact, Guarise cites “passion” as the only thing users need to 
            have to be able to use Volumio. It can be downloaded for free and 
            comes ready to start playing audio files immediately.    
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            After the initial download, Volumio has to be flashed onto an SD 
            card and connected through a network. Volumio can be downloaded 
            with Windows, Macintosh or Linux systems. From there, users can go 
            to volumio.local/ and use the WebUi to start listening.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Volumio is equipped to play all music—FLAC, MP3, WAV, AAC, ALAC and 
            Musepack files are all compatible, in addition to streaming 
            Internet radio.  It can be controlled via WebUi from a smartphone, 
            tablet or computer. BeagleBone Black supports the program well 
            because of its large expandability and affordable price.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/xj8C7vC.png&quot; WIDTH=500 HEIGHT=150
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Guarise wants Volumio users to be able to sit back, relax and 
            listen to their favorite tunes from anywhere in their house.  
            Multiple BeagleBone Black platforms can be connected, allowing 
            users to select from which device the music will be flowing. 
            Simultaneous playback mode is going to be available soon, giving 
            developers the chance to build an open-source multi-room audio 
            system.   
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            He gives credit to his fellow music and technology gurus who have 
            worked on the open-source code. &quot;This project relies also on tons 
            of good code made by developers all around the world. What we did 
            was just put it all together and make it act as one ecosystem,” 
            Guarise said.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Volumio hosts a blog and forum on its website for anyone working on 
            the code and improving the project. It is always being updated to 
            give users the best version. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Even though Guarise is studying psychology, he works endlessly with 
            music. He has a mix of valve and digital amplifiers that he built 
            himself during a few sleepless nights. His passion for music and 
            technology inspires him to work on projects like Volumio and 
            struggle to turn his volume down.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Complete Volumio features list:&lt;br&gt;
                 - Ready to play: Flash it and you’re ready&lt;br&gt;
                 - Audiophile Quality: Bit-perfect playback&lt;br&gt;
                 - FLAC, WAV, MP3, AAC, ALAC, PLS support&lt;br&gt;
                 - Music libraries on Samba, NFS and USB drives&lt;br&gt;
                 - Webradios support out of the box&lt;br&gt;
                 - Control it via integrated Webui with PC, smartphone, tablet&lt;br&gt;
                 - AirPlay capability&lt;br&gt;
                 - Ramplay support&lt;br&gt;
                 - DSD native playback&lt;br&gt;
                 - Multiroom playback via Android App&lt;br&gt;
                 - Output playback device selection&lt;br&gt;
                 - Audio out via HDMI, USB, Analog Jack, S/PDIF, I2S &lt;br&gt;
                 - Compatible with all UAC2 compliant USB DACs&lt;br&gt;
                 - Wireless Nnetwork configuration&lt;br&gt;
                 - Various resampling options, up to 32bit/384khrtz&lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            For more information on Volumio or to download it, visit 
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://volumio.org&quot;&gt;http://volumio.org/&lt;/a&gt;.
               &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
    
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
           
    
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://www.beagleboard.org/blog/2014-01-14-project-spotlight-volumio/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>www.beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
