<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3395" name="2014-01-21-project-spotlight-petcube" prototype="Page" created="1390323568687" lastModified="1391100958894">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2014-01-21-project-spotlight-petcube</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">30.01.2014 10:55:58 CST</time>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.1qedfyqm5zolp</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt;Petcube&lt;/h1&gt;
      
       &lt;p&gt;
            As Alex Neskin slipped out the front door for work, he couldn’t 
            help but feel the heartache as he heard the barks and cries from 
            his Chihuahua, Rocky. It was the same routine every day. He would 
            try to sneak out the door attempting to be unnoticed by Rocky, but 
            every time the door would shut, the barking and crying would start. 
            The separation anxiety not only took a toll on him and Rocky, but 
            even the neighbors when they had to deal with the unnerving sound 
            of a barking dog. This separation anxiety is what led Alex to 
            create Petcube.
    &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
             &lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/DShRbXM.jpg&quot; WIDTH=428 HEIGHT=285 alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Sgr781i.jpg&quot; Width=425 Height=285 alt=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt; &lt;/P&gt;&lt;p&gt;
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           Petcube is a gadget that lets you watch, talk and play laser games 
           with your pet through a mobile application, anytime, anywhere. Alex 
           came up with the design of a movable webcam combined with a laser so 
           he could see his best friend while he controlled the laser (Rocky’s 
           favorite toy!) to entertain him.            
               
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
            The aesthetic design of Petcube is a 10x10x10 aluminum and glass 
            cube. Its internal hardware contains a wide angle camera, laser 
            diode, two servo motors to control it, microphone and speakers. The 
            camera allows you to take pictures and videos and share them with 
            friends all while live video streaming to your phone. The 
            microphone lets you hear your pet, and the speakers enable you to 
            call them over. 
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            Petcube uses the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beagleboard.org/Products/BeagleBone%20Black&quot;&gt;
            BeagleBone Black computer&lt;/a&gt;, based on a TI &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ti.com/pro-arm-bborgblog-e2e-lp&quot;&gt;
            Sitara processor&lt;/a&gt;, with a custom cape to control all peripherals. Alex 
            chose the BeagleBone Black computer for the Petcube because of its 
            open schematics that allowed him to create a custom board with a 
            unique shape and design. “Everything works pretty much easy and 
            fast out of the box,” said Alex.  
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
        
            The live video streaming is the most intriguing attribute of the 
            Petcube. According to Alex, the real-time interaction not only puts 
            pet owners at ease, but also keeps pets entertained and out of 
            trouble. Alex also plans to put a number of Petcubes in animal 
            shelters. Petcube has started partnering with U.S. shelters in 
            order to boost adoption rates. There are an estimated 5 million 
            pets that enter shelters every year, and Petcube hopes to help find 
            homes for these homeless animals. Public streaming will allow 
            people to see and play with homeless dogs and cats. This will not 
            only improve the emotional and physical health of the homeless 
            animals, but could also lead to more adoptions by giving more 
            exposure to the animals. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/0g8oxiI.jpg&quot; WIDTH=520 HEIGHT=325
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            One thing is clear after talking to Alex: Petcube is committed to 
            improving pets and their parent’s lives with technology. They plan 
            to expand their product line with other high-tech pet accessories. 
            They are planning on integrating Petcube with collars and feeders, 
            allowing pets to have scheduled feeding times with portion control.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
    
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
           
    
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://www.beagleboard.org/blog/2014-01-21-project-spotlight-petcube/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>www.beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
