<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3411" name="2014-01-29-project-spotlight-beedome" prototype="Page" created="1390922340548" lastModified="1390922836477">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2014-01-29-project-spotlight-beedome</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">28.01.2014 09:27:16 CST</time>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.yentrxnfqqtd</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt;The BeeDome&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            ForestDew Apiaries, located in Ottawa, Ontario, has been keeping, 
            testing and trying 20 breeds of bees from all over the world for 
            13 years.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           They pride themselves on coming up with innovative products and 
           solutions in the bee industry, and their BeeDome is definitely one 
           of these solutions.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The BeeDome is a system to control the environment of indoor 
            nucleus colonies (nucs) where small honey bees are kept indoors 
            over the winter months. The BeeDome extends the bee breading season 
            so ForestDew can offer strong, healthy nucs to beekeepers early in 
            the spring at reasonable prices to replace bees lost over winter. 
            This is especially important in northern climates where winter 
            creeps in early. After more than five years of research and 
            prototyping, ForestDew Aparies is now live trialing the BeeDome. 
            ForestDew Apiaries puts its nucs into the BeeDome in later November 
            for the winter, where they are kept in environmental conditions 
            that ensure minimal food store consumption. ForestDew Apiaries 
            credits the BeeDome for helping it deliver reasonable priced, 
            quality bees to its customers.
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  
        &lt;table&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://imgur.com/BKrp5Sn.jpg&quot; WIDTH=419 HEIGHT=558 alt=&quot;1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/saq8ISo.jpg&quot; Width=419 Height=558 alt=&quot;2&quot;/&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/table&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
        Image credit: ForestDew Apiaries
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
            The BeeDome is a computerized system based on the Sitara-processor-
            powered BeagleBone Black computer as well as a specially designed 
            “cape” plug-in board. BeagleBone Black is connected to the Internet,
            and stats are uploaded periodically to a website so that the company 
            can closely monitor the nucs. The BeeDome also integrates GE 
            Telaire T6613/T6615 and MG811 sensors to monitor the CO2 level; 
            DS18B20 sensors to monitor temperature; DH22 sensors to monitor 
            humidity and temperature; and Sharp COM-10636 SSR devices to 
            control 120V devices. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            “Bee” sure to check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forestdewapiaries.com/the-beedome/&quot;&gt;
            ForestDew Apiaries’ website &lt;/a&gt; for more information on this 
            “unbeelievable” project! 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;                
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
           
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2014-01-29-project-spotlight-beedome/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
