<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3437" name="2014-02-11-project-spotlight-ece-christmas-lights" prototype="Page" created="1392140065324" lastModified="1392140352275">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>2014-02-11-project-spotlight-ece-christmas-lights</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <time type="date">11.02.2014 11:39:12 CST</time>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.1u4kafuih5qof</hopsession>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt;Rose-Hulman ECE Christmas lights&lt;/h1&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            Imagine having the ability to personalize your Christmas tree 
            lights. When the holiday is approaching and it’s time for your 
            family tradition of picking a tree, baking cookies, and putting on 
            the garland, lights, ornaments, and big star on top, it seems like 
            there is always something wrong with the lights! A few bulbs have 
            gone out, some are missing, and you find yourself scrambling around 
            trying to find replacements to put in to make sure your tree still 
            shines bright next holiday season.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            A holiday humbug situation like this is just what Mark Yoder and the 
            students in his electrical and computer engineering (ECE) class at 
            Rose-Hulman Institute of Technology were trying to avoid when they 
            turned a string of Adafruit digital RGB LEDs into lights for the 
            department Christmas tree.
           &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           Mark’s students created a kernel driver, Blockly interface, and the 
           necessary programs to control the LED string. With the collaborative 
           work of Mark and his students, the ECE Christmas tree lights were 
           born. 
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;  
            The Adafruit digital RGB LED strings, with the help of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ti.com/pro-arm-bborgblog-e2e-lp&quot;&gt;
            Sitara-processor&lt;/a&gt;-powered&lt;a href=&quot;http://beagleboard.org/Products/BeagleBone%20Black&quot;&gt;
            BeagleBone Black&lt;/a&gt; open-source computer, make it possible to set each LED 
            to a color and intensity. The ECE Christmas tree lights are two 
            five-meter Adafruit strings interfaced to the BeagleBone Black computer.
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
            Adafruit LED strings carry 32 RGB LEDs per meter, and allow each 
            LED to be programmed and controlled individually. The strings are 
            weatherproof and easily able to be cut with some wire cutters. The 
            ECE Christmas tree light strings are powered at 3.3V from BeagleBone 
            Black, which is powered with a 5V external supply.
                        &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
           BeagleBone Black was chosen to work with the lights because it is 
           inexpensive and capable of an assortment of tasks at high 
           performance. By putting it with the Adafruit LED strings, fun and 
           unique light displays can be made! You can see these lights in 
           action: 
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
           &lt;object width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot;&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;movie&quot; value=&quot;//www.youtube.com/v/4BbRNn3VadA?hl=en_US&amp;version=3&amp;rel=0&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowFullScreen&quot; value=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;param name=&quot;allowscriptaccess&quot; value=&quot;always&quot;&gt;&lt;/param&gt;&lt;embed src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/v/4BbRNn3VadA?hl=en_US&amp;version=3&amp;rel=0&quot; type=&quot;application/x-shockwave-flash&quot; width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; allowscriptaccess=&quot;always&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;true&quot;&gt;&lt;/embed&gt;&lt;/object&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;  
            “One of my favorite displays starts an LED at the bottom of the 
            string and sequences it up to the top,” Mark said. “It starts a dim 
            red and as it moves along, it gets brighter and brighter. The LED 
            represents someone sledding and they are getting hotter and hotter 
            as they climb the hill. One of these sledders is started every two 
            seconds and the whole collection is a sledding party. Once they 
            reach the top, they turn around and sled down, getting bluer and 
            bluer and colder as they go.”
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Even though the tree has been taken down until next Christmas, 
            students have requested to keep the LEDs on display to play with on 
            study breaks and create new light patterns.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Mark has different pattern examples written in C, python, shell 
            scripts, and JavaScript. A challenge he faces is finding enough 
            time to play with the LED string. “It doesn’t take long to 
            implement a new pattern, but once you get it going you think of 
            other, cooler, things to do.” &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           
           While the holidays have already passed this season, Yoder is working 
           on implementing a TI SimpleLink™ Bluetooth low energy CC2541 based 
           SensorTag  kit for next Christmas. The SensorTag is able to 
           communicate with the BeagleBone Black, so the lights respond when 
           you move the SensorTag around. He also is working to have the lights 
           respond to audio. The louder the sound, the more LEDs will light up. 
           &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
        
           Mark’s next endeavor with the ECE Christmas Tree Lights is to connect 
           them to a TI LaunchPad so he can control the LEDs. 
           &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
        
           Bring the light back to your Christmas spirit by customizing your own 
           Christmas lights! The course github is available here.
            &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_referer>http://www.beagleboard.org/blog/2014-02-11-project-spotlight-ece-christmas-lights/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>www.beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <user>tarajstratton@gmail.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
