<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3448" name="2014-02-18-project-spotlight-logi-bone" prototype="Page" created="1392739888846" lastModified="1447158309940">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; rv:17.0) Gecko/20100101 Firefox/17.0</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>2014-02-18-project-spotlight-logi-bone</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">18.02.2014 17:42:40 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.yn0qukem3cc7</hopsession>
    <user>jkridner.wordpress.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">3363.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt;LOGi-Bone &lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Tara Stratton&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            As working professionals, Michael Jones, Jonathan Piat and their 
            team at Valent F(x) know that interfacing with FPGA boards can be a 
            clunky and cumbersome process. With these complexities of electronic 
            design in mind, they strove to devise a more user-friendly, 
            plug-and-play method to, as Michael put it, “make even students and 
            hobbyists smile.”
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           As a result, the folks at Valent F(x) developed the LOGi family of 
           FPGA development boards. According to Michael, these boards “were 
           created with a dual-use purpose: to limit the sharp learning curve 
           associated with FPGA development and to enable the unification of 
           existing hardware interfaces and open-source development platforms,” 
           including our own &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beagleboard.org/Products/BeagleBone%20Black&quot;&gt;BeagleBone Black&lt;/a&gt;. 
           Valent F(x) claims that they help their customers overcome various 
           challenges by developing open-source hardware that is easy to use, 
           program and interface with various existing hardware peripherals. 
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/cMm5cTU.jpg&quot; HEIGHT=350 WIDTH=490&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Image credit: Valent F(x)
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
            The LOGi-Bone is a LOGi FPGA board that recently met with great 
            success on Kickstarter. The heart of the LOGi-Bone—like all of the 
            other LOGi-boards—is a Xilinx Spartan 6 FPGA. The LOGi-Bone has two 
            rows of connectors on the underside of the FPGA board that allow 
            users to interface with the 2x46 headers on BeagleBone Black, 
            based on TI’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ti.com/pro-arm-bborgblog-e2e-lp&quot;&gt;
            Sitara AM335x processor&lt;/a&gt;. The board is also compatible with the 
            original &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.beagleboard.org/Products/BeagleBone&quot;&gt;BeagleBone&lt;/a&gt;. 
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            The main controller is a Mac Mini mounted in a custom arcade 
            console. Every frame of video is rendered on this console and 
            streamed over Wi-Fi to reduce the number of wires needed—normal 
            wires don’t work for a POV display because they would get tangled 
            up from all of the spinning. Because of this challenge, all of the 
            brains required to run the display are mounted to the spinning part 
            and spin along with the display.  
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Other LOGi-Bone features include:&lt;br&gt;
                &amp;#9679;    256 Mb SDRAM &lt;br&gt;
                &amp;#9679;	2x LEDs&lt;br&gt;
                &amp;#9679;	2x push buttons&lt;br&gt;
                &amp;#9679;	2x DIP switches &lt;br&gt;
                &amp;#9679;	1 high-bandwidth SATA connector expansion port&lt;br&gt;
                &amp;#9679;	2x Digilent Inc. PMOD expansion ports supporting 59+ plug-and-play hardware modules &lt;br&gt;
                &amp;#9679;	1x Arduino-compatible headers connected to the FPGA pins (3.3V only); supports more than 200+ Arduino Shield modules&lt;br&gt; 
                &amp;#9679;	Optional GPMC, SPI or I2C port access from the BeagleBone Black&lt;br&gt; 
                &amp;#9679;	10x length-tuned LVDS pairs &lt;br&gt;
                &amp;#9679;	Bit-stream-loading interface connected to the host processor; optional bitstream FPGA self-loading from onboard Flash &lt;br&gt;
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            “The LOGi-Bone adds FPGA flexibility and capability to the 
            BeagleBone, allowing it to be easily morphed into endless digital 
            applications,” said Michael. In fact, the Valent F(x) team has 
            already created applications for the LOGi-Bone, including a Bitcoin 
            miner, machine vision and autonomous vehicle and robotic 
            controllers. All applications are open source and available on the 
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fpga-logi&quot;&gt;LOGi repository&lt;/a&gt;. You can 
            also find videos of some their current applications on the 
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/channel/UCDt1_Vd3ECYYhVIT1fM06Nw&quot;&gt;
            LOGi YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;.  
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Valent F(x) says that they are all about user collaboration and 
            hope to create a community infrastructure that allows users to work 
            together to create unique and interesting projects. Generally, 
            users have strengths in one of the many facets involved in 
            electronics, thus making it difficult to create and finish a 
            project that requires a wide range of electronic functionality. 
            Enabling multiples users with varying skills to work together 
            allows multi-faceted projects to be created, with each user adding 
            their respective strengths to the project. Valent F(x) would love 
            to hear from you to know what kind of projects and applications you 
            would like to see created and get involved in.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Now that their Kickstarter is closed, the Valent F(x) team will 
            start manufacturing boards and will start fulfilling orders later 
            this year. Visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.valentfx.com/&quot;&gt;Valent F(x)’s site&lt;/a&gt; 
            for more information on these boards or to order one of your own!
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
         
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
           
    
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2014-02-18-project-spotlight-logi-bone/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
