<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3562" name="2014-04-07-project_spotlight_shield_io" prototype="Page" created="1396900910422" lastModified="1443610967633">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/33.0.1750.154 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>2014-04-07-project_spotlight_shield_io</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">07.04.2014 20:51:18 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>192.91.75.29</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>192.91.75.i8lx6vdfqlev</hopsession>
    <user>jkridner.wordpress.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">2519.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black Project Spotlight: Shield I/O&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some unlikely combinations just seem to work: Oreos and peanut butter, Dwight Schrute and Michael Scott and now Arduino and BeagleBone Black! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/e13pW4j.png&quot; alt=&quot;Shield I/O+ beside the BeagleBone Black&quot; /&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;With the new Shield I/O, you can now use (almost) any Arduino shield with a BeagleBone Black. The Shield I/O, created by Andreas Behrend, adapts Arduino shields to be BeagleBone Black compatible, it doesn&apos;t matter if you&apos;re using 3.3V or 5V logic or up to 5V analog inputs. Precise resistor arrays divide the analog inputs and make it an option to measure up to 5V.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Shield I/O comes with dedicated level shifters for all 14 digital GPIO pins, PWM, I2C and SPI. Something interesting to note is that part of Shield I/O comes from an Atmel ATTiny that lets the user switch logic levels through software over I2C. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The device uses two TXB0108 level shifters for standard I/O lines and one TXS0102 shifting the I2C bus. Shield I/O also comes in a &quot;Plus&quot; version, which features a MCP23017 that is also accessible over the I2C bus.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Andreas saw a need for Shield I/O while working with microcontrollers that had to be rebooted to switch between different programs or adapt to new settings. He wanted to give developers an option for a ready-made Arduino Shield to use with a powerful embedded device, BeagleBone Black. Shield I/O makes it possible to communicate with Arduino shields without re-flashing or rebooting the whole system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andreas chose BeagleBone Black because of its power and compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;It&apos;s the most powerful embedded device out there with enough PWM, SPI, I²C, Timers, analog inputs, which can be muxed to fit the Arduino pin mapping including 2 PRUs to get high speed timing wherever it&apos;s needed,&quot; Behrend stated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andreas is a student currently employed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.impressx.com/en-gb/home.aspx&quot;&gt;impressx media&lt;/a&gt;, who supports the Shield I/O. Additionally, Andreas has worked as a graphic designer and has run his own business. His next project is in the works and will be used in the healthcare industry - a tracker used by doctors to monitor a patient&apos;s overall health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as each developer creates their own projects, the Shield I/O allows its user to employ their own creativity and make their own projects, with Shield I/O as its base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;//www.youtube.com/embed/NnAlJ1jPvFk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, or to donate to this project, visit Shield I/O&apos;s IndieGoGo site: &lt;a href=&quot;http://igg.me/at/ShieldIO/x/3353417&quot;&gt;http://igg.me/at/ShieldIO/x/3353417&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2014-04-07-project_spotlight_shield_io/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
