<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3595" name="2014-04-22-google-summer-of-code-2014-projects" prototype="Page" created="1398184797637" lastModified="1446614098389">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_5) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/34.0.1847.116 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>2014-04-22-google-summer-of-code-2014-projects</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">22.04.2014 16:39:57 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>98.250.189.79</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>98.250.189.1ed7k761e8rlu</hopsession>
    <user>jkridner.wordpress.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">2059.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;h1&gt;BeagleBoard.org Google Summer of Code 2014 projects&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Yesterday, Google announced the project proposals accepted for this
    year&apos;s Summer of Code! 7 of those projects are being mentored by
    BeagleBoard.org. See the full list of approved projects at
    &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/projects/list/google/gsoc2014&quot;&gt;
        https://www.google-melange.com/gsoc/projects/list/google/gsoc2014
    &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;BeagleLogic&lt;/b&gt; - Kumar Abhishek will be working on a logic analzer
        utilizing the BeagleBone PRUs as a way to learn about embedded interfaces,
        mentored by Matt Ranostay, Hunyue Yau and Charles Steinkuehler.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;Kernel MMC+DMA&lt;/b&gt; - Saket Sinha will be working on improving the
        MMC and DMA drivers in the Linux kernel, mentored by Joel Fernandes,
        Greg Kroah-Hartman and others.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;BeaglePilot&lt;/b&gt; - Victor Mayoral Vilches will be working on creating
        a Linux-based autopilot for flying robots, mentored by Andrew Tridgell,
        Hunyue Yau, Luis Gustavo Lira and others.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;Android remote display&lt;/b&gt; - Praveen Kumar Pendyala will be working
        on using an Android phone as an all-in-one user interface for BeagleBone,
        mentored by Vladimir Pantelic and Vlad Ungureanu.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;BotSpeak&lt;/b&gt; - Deepak Karki will be working on an interpreter
        firmware that runs on the BeagleBone PRUs to simplify programming them,
        mentored by Pantelis Antoniou, Hunyue Yau, Jason Kridner, Alex Hiam and
        others.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;Bone101&lt;/b&gt; - Diego Turcios will be working on improving the on-board tutorial
        environment for BeagleBone with live-running interactive examples,
        mentored by me (Jason Kridner), Steve French, David Scheltema and
        Jongseuk Lee.
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;b&gt;PyBBIO&lt;/b&gt; - Rekha Seethamraju will be working on improving the
        PyBBIO Python library for BeagleBone for additional sensors, mentored
        by Alex Hiam and Steve French.
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
    Now is the bonding time between students and mentors and tomorrow at noon
    US Eastern time is the first official meeting between students and mentors.
    All of our student meetings are held in public and you are welcome to join
    us and learn more about these exciting projects. We&apos;ll be asking the
    students to create small introductory videos or screencasts introducing
    their project to the world, making sure they are well aligned with their
    mentors and understand their project goals. Stay tuned for those videos!
&lt;/p&gt;</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2014-04-22-google-summer-of-code-2014-projects/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
