<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3654" name="2014-07-02-beaglebone-black-project-spotlight-object-record" prototype="Page" created="1404317747567" lastModified="1450949541993">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/35.0.1916.153 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>2014-07-02-beaglebone-black-project-spotlight-object-record</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">02.07.2014 16:57:37 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>192.91.75.30</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>192.91.75.1syb3wg7jelzb</hopsession>
    <user>jkridner.wordpress.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">1929.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;h1&gt;Project Spotlight: Object Record&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you know that &lt;i&gt;The New York Times&lt;/i&gt; writes itself? No, not the newspaper-but objects 
at The New York Times R&amp;D Lab have &quot;thoughts&quot; of their own that they journal for 
our reading pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The New York Times&lt;/i&gt; R&amp;D Lab has created Object Record, a device that pairs objects 
with sensors that perceive environmental conditions around it through touch, motion 
and more. Object Record prints a constant monologue of its perceptions of and responses 
to the changing input. The text of this monologue is printed out in ticker form on 
a mini printer so that visitors can see not only the current &quot;thoughts&quot; of Object 
Record, but its &quot;memory&quot; as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: right; padding-left: 10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/AtkdGHr.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Object Record Ticker Tape&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot;  /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Object Record is part of &lt;i&gt;The New York Times&apos;&lt;/i&gt; effort to discover and explore the poetic 
and narrative potential of the Internet of Things (IoT). &quot;As more of our objects and 
environments become actuated, connected, and data-enabled, these enchanted objects 
are developing the capacity to contain their own stories. An object can remember its 
history, can understand how it&apos;s used, [and] can to talk to other objects around it 
to understand its environment. As these capabilities evolve, objects no longer become 
inert backdrops to our experiences, but active participants in our world that can 
share stories about themselves and us,&quot; said Alexis Lloyd, Creative Director of the 
R&amp;D Lab at &lt;i&gt;The New York Times&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ti.com/pro-arm-bborgblog-e2e-lp&quot;&gt;Sitara processor&lt;/a&gt;-based &lt;a href=&quot;http://beagleboard.org/Products/BeagleBone Black&quot;&gt;BeagleBone Black&lt;/a&gt; is the main system controller for Object 
Record. BeagleBone Black meets the lab&apos;s needs because of its low price, large feature 
set and ability to run the Linux operating system. The large feature set enables prototyping 
without worrying about network, memory and other constraints, and the ability to run 
the Linux operating system allows developers to program in the language that works 
best for them. Object Record code is written in Python, for example, and uses the 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/adafruit/adafruit-beaglebone-io-python&quot;&gt;Adafruit BBIO library&lt;/a&gt; to interface with the GPIOs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;float: left; padding-right: 10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/u9LOhbD.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Object Record on the job&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BeagleBone Black communicates information from various sensors on Object Record, including 
a photocell, a TMP102 temperature sensor and a VCNL4000 proximity and ambient light 
sensor, to a thermal printer via TTL serial, when sensor values cross a threshold 
or when a certain amount of time elapses without a threshold event. This causes the 
printer to issue a remark about its environment. Noah Feehan, Maker at The New York 
Times R&amp;D Lab, said, &quot;The thermal printers presented [a] challenge: between the first 
exploratory purchase many months ago and the purchases made for this installation, 
the manufacturer made a few small, undocumented changes that delayed progress for 
a few days.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noah added that the BeagleBoard.org community, the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adafruit.com/forums/viewforum.php?f=49&quot;&gt;Adafruit forums&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/alexanderhiam/PyBBIO/tree/master/bbio&quot;&gt;PyBBIO&lt;/a&gt; helped 
his team emerge unscathed from this and many other challenges they faced while developing 
Object Record.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who ever thought we&apos;d be getting our next The New York Times story from a BeagleBone 
Black computer!? According to the R&amp;D Lab, this is just one cool way we&apos;ll be engaging 
with objects and the world around us in the future. Head to NYT Lab&apos;s blog to &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.nytlabs.com/2013/10/17/object-record-technical-brief/&quot;&gt;read more about Object Record&lt;/a&gt; 
and the &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.nytlabs.com&quot;&gt;other cool things&lt;/a&gt; they are working on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Want to chat with us about this project? Tweet us at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/beagleboardorg&quot;&gt;@BeagleBoardOrg&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2014-07-02-beaglebone-black-project-spotlight-object-record/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
