<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3691" name="2014-07-22-beaglebone-black-project-kuyurix-bus-speakers" prototype="Page" created="1406047054744" lastModified="1452328700483">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/35.0.1916.153 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>2014-07-22-beaglebone-black-project-kuyurix-bus-speakers</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">22.07.2014 16:37:34 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>192.94.94.106</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>192.94.94.ytcdhzeybzzn</hopsession>
    <user>jkridner.wordpress.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">2254.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight blog post: Kuyurix Bus Speakers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commuting in a big city is a tough task, especially when public transit and traffic 
congestion make the process even more difficult. For someone who is blind, finding
 your way around the city on public transportation in these conditions can seem daunting, 
 or nearly impossible. Marcelo Gutierrez recognized this issue and wanted to do something 
 about it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcelo is a university professor teaching digital signal processing and Linux-embedded 
courses. He designed and developed the Kuyurix, an audio-based system to assist people 
who are blind on public bus transportation. It notifies passengers of upcoming main 
streets and approaching points of interests, such as a hospital, making public transportation 
much more comfortable for those with any visual impairment.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;div style=&quot;float: right; padding-left: 10px;&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ztqaK3P.jpg&quot; width=&quot;300px&quot; alt=&quot;Kuyurix&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The voice announcement system provides passenger information by an FM transmitter 
connected to two speakers that carry the message. Marcelo used the free samples service 
from Texas Instruments when constructing the first prototype. He integrated TI&apos;s 
TLV320AIC3106 audio codec, TPS73701 linear regulator, LM4871 audio power amplifier 
and LM22676 switching regulator. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&quot;At the university from which I graduated, there is a library service for blind and 
partially sighted people,&quot; said Marcelo, an electronic engineering alumnus from Universidad 
Tecnológica Nacional - Facultad Regional Haedo. &quot;So I thought [Kuyurix] might help 
to make their lives just a little bit easier.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BeagleBone Black was chosen to power the bus speakers. All signals are present on 
expansion headers, making cape development easy, and it incorporates an ARM® Cortex®-A8 core 
(within TI&apos;s Sitara AM335x processor) that runs with low power consumption. In comparison 
to similar products, BeagleBone Black provided the best performance for Marcelo&apos;s 
project.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;&quot;Two weeks on the bus and BeagleBone Black is solid as a rock,&quot; Marcelo says.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Marcelo faced some challenges during the creation of the Kuyurix bus speakers. The 
main challenge of this project was choosing the proper GPS module. The first GPS receiver 
integrated a built-in patch antenna, but it didn&apos;t have the reliability that Marcelo 
expected. He then tried another module that uses an active antenna, which significantly 
improved the performance of the device.&lt;/p&gt; 

&lt;p&gt;Marcelo is now working on developing a digital TV receiver box. He is doing this by 
connecting a USB ISBD-T TV stick on a BeagleBone Black. The product will be introduced 
on public bus transportation in just a few weeks. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&apos;d like to learn more about the Kuyurix bus speakers, feel free to contact Marcelo 
via Twitter (@efectomiller).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marcelo would like to give special thanks to the Department of Electronic Engineering 
(UTN/FRH), Ing. Carlos González, and the professor Ing. Fidel Santos, for their assistance 
and generosity in helping implement the Kuyurix speakers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Want to chat with us about this project? Tweet us at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/beagleboardorg&quot;&gt;@BeagleBoardOrg&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2014-07-22-beaglebone-black-project-kuyurix-bus-speakers/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
