<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3711" name="2014-08-06-project-spotlight-pocket-nc" prototype="Page" created="1407354035462" lastModified="1441309389193">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/36.0.1985.125 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>2014-08-06-project-spotlight-pocket-nc</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">12.08.2014 19:45:10 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>4.28.44.174</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>4.28.44.1s62zau22w435</hopsession>
    <user>nelms.natalie@gmail.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">6451.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt;Pocket NC P5&lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Natalie Nelms&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            Computer numerical control (CNC) milling machines  
            have been around for decades. Most are industrial-sized, 
            and are used create everything from the shaped trim on 
            a house to the mechanical components of a space shuttle. 
            Over the last decade, a large do-it-yourself community has 
            emerged giving a new market to CNC milling machines as personal, 
            rather than solely industrial applications. 
             &lt;/p&gt;
              &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/1eKfqI8.jpg&quot; WIDTH=375 HEIGHT=268 /&gt;
        &lt;/p&gt;
               &lt;p&gt;
           Matt, Michelle, Gary, Duane and Bannor from 
           &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pocketnc.com/&quot;&gt;Pocket NC&lt;/a&gt; have 
           always been tinkerers and enjoy pursuing projects from their 
           homes. After searching long and hard for a personal desktop mill, 
           Matt and his team turned to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ti.com/pro-arm-bborgblog-e2e-lp&quot;&gt;Sitara-processor-based&lt;/a&gt; 
           BeagleBone Black to design and build a milling machine for themselves. Thus, 
           the Pocket NC P5 was born!
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
            “We saw an amazing opportunity for creativity that could open up 
            if we had the ability to make real parts for projects and 
            prototyping from our house,” said Matt, the ‘inventor captain’ 
            from Pocket NC. “Three and a half years ago we embarked on the 
            journey to bring a sophisticated milling machine to the masses.”
        &lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;
            The Pocket NC P5’s subtractive manufacturing process starts with 
            a solid piece of material and carves out the desired part according 
            to computer generated tool paths. Compared to 3D printing, milling 
            offers a much wider variety of possible materials to use 
            (including metals and wood), which produces stronger finished parts. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Pocket NC P5 is driven by the LinuxCNC distribution Machine Kit 
            running on a BeagleBone Black. The 5-axis machine utilizes precision 
            linear and rotary bearings, stepper motors and an NSK spindle with 
            quick change capabilities and brushless servo direct drive.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/sP5YF82.jpg&quot; WIDTH=326.4 HEIGHT=224.8
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            “We chose the BeagleBone Black for its compact size and functionality,” 
            Matt said. “It’s powerful enough to drive all five axes of our machine; 
            and it offers many GPIO pins and fast PRU pins. The features on the 
            board gave us hope that we could bring desktop machining into 
            the 21st century.”
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Although the team’s strengths are predominantly mechanical skills, 
            they found engineers and hobbyists to assist with the project in the 
            electronics and software areas. The Pocket NC P5 project is fully 
            funded by the team, so challenges arose when looking for people to 
            contribute without an immediate payout. Finding the right people who 
            are passionate about the project ruled out the financial hardships 
            that came with the project. Funding the project themselves, the team 
            learned how to be creative in finding ways to prototype their machines.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The team took sixth months to develop the design of a 3-axis mill 
            but quickly realized many people would be more interested in a 5-axis 
            machine. After building and learning from three prototypes, they 
            built a fourth prototype that they took to World Maker Faire New 
            York in 2013. Today, the team is in the process of building and 
            testing five Beta machines before taking the product to market.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            “We want to continue developing our machine to bring down the cost, 
            while also adding more features to it,” Matt said. “We will either be 
            working on that, or developing a perpetual motion machine. We have 
            learned a lot through the process and are always thankful for the 
            encouragement and support we receive from the community.”  
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            If you&apos;d like to learn more about the Pocket NC P5, feel free to 
            visit &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.pocketnc.com/&quot;&gt;www.pocketnc.com&lt;/a&gt; or check it out on 
            &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.facebook.com/pocketnc&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, 
            &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/pocketnc&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; 
            and &lt;a href=&quot;http://instagram.com/pocket_nc&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Want to chat with us about this project? Tweet us at @BeagleBoardorg!
            &lt;/p&gt;
           
    
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2014-08-06-project-spotlight-pocket-nc/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
