<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3739" name="2014-08-25-project-spotlight-beaglerov" prototype="Page" created="1408987012327" lastModified="1447918379284">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/38.0.2125.111 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>2014-08-25-project-spotlight-beaglerov</uri>
    <http_host>127.0.0.1:8080</http_host>
    <time type="date">10.11.2014 15:40:43 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.gv9z58dyf55p</hopsession>
    <user>nelms.natalie@gmail.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">5628.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBone Black project spotlight:&lt;br&gt;BeagleROV &lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Natalie Nelms&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            You don’t have to be a child to play with remote-controlled cars. 
            The BeagleROV is an exciting toy that would bring any adult Maker 
            back to the good ole’ days – except this robot packs a bit more punch 
            than the classic Nascar minis. Powered by the TI &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ti.com/pro-arm-bborgblog-e2e-lp&quot;&gt;Sitara AM335x processor&lt;/a&gt;-based 
            BeagleBone Black, the BeagleROV has a multitude of capabilities 
            that are all controlled remotely via the robot’s web application. 
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           In addition to the vehicle’s remotely controlled technology, 
           the BeagleROV includes the following features:&lt;br&gt;
               •    Wi-Fi access to the web app with an adhoc Wi-Fi network&lt;br&gt;
•	Real-time video processing with OpenCV&lt;br&gt;
•	GPIO management to drive MOSFET actuators&lt;br&gt;
•	Ultrasonic distance sensor reading&lt;br&gt;
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           This car definitely isn’t your granddad’s model.
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;           
           &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Xd3xtYu.jpg&quot; HEIGHT=357 WIDTH=430&lt;/p&gt;
          
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
            When asked why he developed this machine, creator Fabio Balzano 
            explained that he wanted to create a dynamic robot. “My company 
            is working in this kind of research and development, and we are especially interested in autonomous UAVs and ROVs,” explained Balzano.  
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The development of this vehicle did not come without complications, 
            however. “The HUB USB power wires were cut to prevent USB host port 
            power down,” detailed Balzano on the challenges of building his robot. 
            “I was able to solve this problem, though, by soldering a custom cape to connect all of the I/O.”
          &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
          The BeagleROV’s technology also transcends the confines of the Earth’s 
          surface and has been utilized in underwater exploration. The marine 
          version of the robot is able to collect imaging and sample data from 
          depths of up to 1,000 meters below the surface, which has sufficiently 
          helped organizations like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.maregroup.org/the-beagle-rov.html&quot;&gt;Marine Applied Research and Exploration&lt;/a&gt; 
          gather the information that they need to learn more about the oceanic 
          habitat. The ability of &lt;a href=&quot;http://beagleboard.org/Products/BeagleBone%20Black&quot;&gt;BeagleBone Black&lt;/a&gt; to support OpenCV real-time 
          video processing really comes into play here as explorers look to 
          stream live footage of the ever-intriguing mystery that is the sea.
           &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Looking towards the future, Fabio and his team plan to develop a 
            more advanced and improved version of this robot. The BeagleROV has 
            proven to not only serve as a hobbyist project, but has also shown 
            to be beneficial in the exploration of our wondrous planet. It is an 
            exciting time for the BeagleROV team and we are eager to see what 
            future models will be capable of.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            For more information on the BeagleROV and for a detailed look 
            at the code that Fabio implemented in the vehicle, you can visit 
            the project’s site at: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitbucket.org/fabiodive/bsdcan2014&quot;&gt;https://bitbucket.org/fabiodive/bsdcan2014&lt;/a&gt;. 
            Want to collaborate or need help with your project? Feel free to 
            contact Fabio at: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:fabio.balzano@elfarolab.com&quot;&gt;fabio.balzano@elfarolab.com&lt;/a&gt;.
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Want to chat with us about this project? Tweet us at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/beagleboardorg&quot;&gt;@BeagleBoardOrg&lt;/a&gt;!
         &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
           
    
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2014-08-25-project-spotlight-beaglerov/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
