<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="3769" name="2014-09-08-project-spotlight-sleeptight" prototype="Page" created="1410189431803" lastModified="1445330506768">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/37.0.2062.103 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>2014-09-08-project-spotlight-sleeptight</uri>
    <http_host>127.0.0.1:8080</http_host>
    <time type="date">08.09.2014 15:17:12 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.1hxpjyhicoy7i</hopsession>
    <user>jkridner.wordpress.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">2119.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;div&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;float:left;width:100%;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;h1&gt;BeagleBoard-xM project spotlight:&lt;br&gt;Sleep Tight &lt;/h1&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;By Natalie Nelms&lt;/p&gt;
       &lt;p&gt;
            Picture this: You’re lying in bed, exhausted from a long day of 
            work; your eyelids are heavy, but you’re devoted to finishing the 
            last page of your favorite novel. You conclude the last page, set 
            the book down on your nightstand, get in the perfect sleeping position 
            and then regrettably realize that your bedroom lamp is still on. 
            With a sigh, you get out of your cozy bed and turn off the light, 
            but not after aggressively stubbing your toe on your nightstand on
            the way back to bed.
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           Now imagine avoiding this whole scenario by simply telling your 
           lamp or lights to turn off. With voice-controlled technology, Sleep 
           Tight can easily turn off your light from the comfort of your own bed. 
           Users will find themselves in sweet dreams immediately.
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;
           Electronic engineer, F.Can Akinci, hatched the idea after recognizing 
           the frustration of book-lovers at bedtime and the need for a convenient solution. 
           &lt;/p&gt;
           &lt;p&gt;           
            “Most people love to read in their beds at night to have a better
            night’s sleep,” said Akinici, the embedded electronics enthusiast. 
            “When you finish reading and are ready to sleep, you have to leave
            your warm bed and get up to reach the switch. Thanks 
            to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://beagleboard.org/beagleboard-xm&quot;&gt;BeagleBoard-xM&lt;/a&gt;-powered Sleep Tight, 
            you won’t even need to move your hand to switch off the lamps.”
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            The project components include a microphone with a 3.5 mm jack, 
            DSP capabilities of BeagleBoard and a relay for switching lights. 
            The team opted for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ti.com/pro-arm-bborgblog-e2e-lp&quot;&gt;Sitara-processor&lt;/a&gt;-based BeagleBoard-xM as the 
            direct board for the device as its DSP unit can handle the 
            voice recognition tasks. 
          &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
          Although now a graduate of Middle East Tech University, Akinici once
          dreamed of playing professional basketball and came extremely close 
          joining the pros. Now, he uses that athleticism and competitive edge to create! 
          He is currently in the beginning stages of the Sleep Tight project, 
          but hopes to finish in the coming weeks. Once complete, he plans to 
          continue on to his next venture: creating a gesture-controlled system. 
           &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Check out F. Can Akinci’s &lt;a href=&quot;http://wlbeagleboard.wordpress.com/&quot;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt; for updates on the ongoing project 
            and to learn more feel free to contact him via Twitter: @wholelottajam. 
            &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            Want to chat with us about this project? Tweet us at &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/beagleboardorg&quot;&gt;@BeagleBoardOrg&lt;/a&gt;!
         &lt;/p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;
            &lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
           
    
            
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2014-09-08-project-spotlight-sleeptight/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
