<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="4118" name="2015-09-29-microsoft-azure-certified-for-iot" prototype="Page" created="1443553019759" lastModified="1447368259683">
  <hop:parent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Macintosh; Intel Mac OS X 10_8_5) AppleWebKit/537.36 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/47.0.2526.8 Safari/537.36</http_browser>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <uri>2015-09-29-microsoft-azure-certified-for-iot</uri>
    <http_host>127.0.0.1:8080</http_host>
    <time type="date">14.10.2015 12:03:08 UTC</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="2912" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.jmhh70x0686t</hopsession>
    <user>jkridner.wordpress.com</user>
    <pvcount type="float">1723.0</pvcount>
    <body>&lt;h1 class=&quot;MsoTitle&quot;&gt;BeagleBoard.org collaborates with Microsoft to simplify Internet of Things (IoT) development&lt;br /&gt;&lt;small style=&quot;font-size: 12px;&quot;&gt;by Jason Kridner&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 class=&quot;MsoSubtitle&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Microsoft Azure Certified for IoT provides quick-start confidence to BeagleBoard.org BeagleBone Black and SeeedStudio BeagleBone Green with pre-tested software and hardware&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When developers of Internet-connected device (or “IoT”) solutions are prototyping and deploying their products, they frequently choose BeagleBoard.org BeagleBone Black and the new BeagleBoard-compatible SeeedStudio BeagleBone Green. By adding participation of these two devices in Microsoft Azure Certified for IoT, BeagleBoard.org is now extending the benefits of its proven open hardware and software ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/images/Microsoft_Azure_Certified_RGB.png&quot; alt=&quot;Microsoft Azure Certified for IoT&quot; width=&quot;200&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; style=&quot;float:right;padding:20px;&quot; /&gt;“Working with the open community around BeagleBoard.org and their partners is an inspiration,” said Barb Edson, General Manager for Data Platform and Internet of Things, Microsoft. &quot;Everyone in the community of professionals, students and hobbyists innovating around programmable electronics benefits from this collaboration to accelerate IoT prototypes and extend their creations to the world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; The proven BeagleBoard.org ecosystem is built on a high-performance Texas Instruments Sitara AM335x processor, typically with an open source GNU/Linux Debian distribution, an open hardware design, and with available add-on daughter boards (or “capes”) and enclosures. Get started learning by joining the on-line discussions and stay in touch by subscribing to the newsletter at &lt;a href=&quot;../../newsletter&quot;&gt;beagleboard.org/newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;!--EndFragment--&gt;    &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;MsoFooter&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;All product and company names herein may be trademarks of their registered owners.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</body>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <render_skin>blog</render_skin>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/blog/2015-10-29-microsoft-azure-certified-for-iot/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
