<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="535" name="Page" prototype="Page" created="1235070269509" lastModified="1235074932366">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows; U; Windows NT 5.1; en-US; rv:1.9.0.6) Gecko/2009011913 Firefox/3.0.6 (.NET CLR 3.5.30729)</http_browser>
    <lang></lang>
    <uri>pico</uri>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <time type="date">19.02.2009 14:22:12 CST</time>
    <pseudoparent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.192.94.94.1rr7eq4rfub1b</hopsession>
    <user>https://a0206359.myopenid.com</user>
    <body>Pico Projector Development Kit
Congratulations on your new DLP Pico Projector Development Kit. This is where you can find some demos to try it out with your Beagleboard.
Initializing an SD card from a Linux host
You&apos;ll need a 2GB or greater SD card and an adapter that works with your Linux host to configure Linux on your BeagleBoard.  The SD card needs to be formatted into a two-partition configuration and loaded with the images of preconfigured partitions.
If you already have a Linux host
Format the SD card, two alternative methods.  Both methods assume a 2GB SD card.  If you&apos;re using a larger SD card then you can proportion the partitions in a similar ratio as in the examples.
Gparted method
Fdisk method
Download the two SD partition images.
pico-sd-fat.tar.bz2. 
pico-sd-ext3.tar.bz2. 
With the SD formatted and mounted on your Linux host, extract the partition images to the SD card.  Assumes you&apos;re in the directory where the image files reside otherwise type the full path of the image file.  Replace /media/beagle_fat with your SD fat partition mount point, same for /media/beagle_ext3.
sudo tar xvjf pico-sd-fat.tar.bz2 -C /media/beagle_fat
sudo tar xvjf pico-sd-ext3.tar.bz2 -C /media/beagle_ext3

If you don&apos;t have a Linux host
Creating a Linux installation under Windows
If you&apos;d like to install Linux under a on your Windows PC, without disrupting your Windows setup consider installing Linux in a virtual machine with VMWare. The below video gives a description of how to get started:

Using &apos;dd&apos; from any operating system
A &apos;dd&apos; image can be created from Linux without access to an SD card, then written from any operating system where &apos;dd&apos; can be run.
Build the image using mkpicoimg.sh adjusting as necessary for the size of your SD card, location of your files, etc. --- or --- 
Simply download pico.img.gz. 
gzcat sd.img.gz | dd of= your device 

A video of the Pico Projector in action


An introduction to the Pico Projector</body>
    <http_language>en-us,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/pico/edit</http_referer>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
