<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="649" name="TUD:OS on the Beagleboard" prototype="Page" created="1245229261580" lastModified="1245229280910">
  <hop:parent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <pname>TUD:OS on the Beagleboard</pname>
    <registrant>https://www.google.com/accounts/o8/id?id=aitoawktajlyvpojl-zt8nc0fz71gryebjg2kse</registrant>
    <http_language>de-de,de;q=0.8,en-us;q=0.5,en;q=0.3</http_language>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (X11; U; Linux i686; de; rv:1.9.0.10) Gecko/2009042523 Ubuntu/8.10 (intrepid) Firefox/3.0.10</http_browser>
    <uri>TUD:OS on the Beagleboard</uri>
    <time type="date">17.06.2009 04:01:20 CDT</time>
    <updatetime type="date">17.06.2009 04:01:01 CDT</updatetime>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.141.76.48.tjaekyd9hjoq</hopsession>
    <body>The plan of this Project is port the TUD:OS operating system to the Beagleboard. The TUD:OS operating system is a L4 microkernel based operating system,  with good real-time and security properties, developed at the TU Dresden.



Microkernel based:

The microkernel approach allows it to to reduce the trusting computing base by running small trusted applications side by side with non-trusted           applications, all as unprivileged user mode applications. 
Further, it is possible to run real-time applications side-by side with non real-time applications. 
Also device driver run in user-mode and thus a crash of a device driver will not lead to an whole system crash and in the best case the driver can be     restarted and the system will keep on running.

Familiar Environment

While offering the above mentioned vantages, TUD:OS still offers a familiar environment by the possibility to run one or more instances of  L4Linux.      L4Linux is a Linux port the Fiasco microkernel which is binary compatible to native Linux but runs in deprivilieged usermode.

What do we get from this project?

Briefly:  A fundament to build embedded [realtime] systems [with a exceptionally small trusted computing base].
Further a possibility to run multiple virtualized linux instances on the beagleboard. A good documentation how to build such systems. And last but not    least a (hopefully cool ;) demo showing that it acutally works.

Note: this project is not an official project of the TU-Dresden.</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <rssfeed></rssfeed>
    <homepage></homepage>
    <render_skin>project</render_skin>
    <edit_skin>edit_project</edit_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/project/TUD:OS%20on%20the%20Beagleboard/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <errmsg></errmsg>
    <shortdesc>The plan of this Project is port the TUD:OS operating system to the Beagleboard. The TUD:OS operating system is a L4 microkernel based operating system,  with good real-time and security properties, developed at the TU Dresden.
</shortdesc>
    <user>https://www.google.com/accounts/o8/id?id=aitoawktajlyvpojl-zt8nc0fz71gryebjg2kse</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
