<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="7" name="brief" prototype="Page" created="1202805395331" lastModified="1365452549251">
  <hop:parent idref="0" prototyperef="Root"/>
    <ev0>dsps_arm_102109</ev0>
    <gpv_p9_o>%2Ftraining%2Farm%2Fall%20subtopics%2Fall%20types%2Fallregions%2Fallcountries%2Fallcities%2Fall%20types%20%20next%2030%20days%20-%20en</gpv_p9_o>
    <rembr549>uid=x0179354|securitylevel=1</rembr549>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>10.247.21.192</http_remotehost>
    <s_cc>true</s_cc>
    <http_language>en-US,en;q=0.8</http_language>
    <wbmain_flyout-products-webench>0</wbmain_flyout-products-webench>
    <uri>brief</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (Windows NT 6.1; WOW64) AppleWebKit/537.31 (KHTML, like Gecko) Chrome/26.0.1410.43 Safari/537.31</http_browser>
    <tipage>/training/arm/all subtopics/all types/allregions/allcountries/allcities/all types  next 30 days - en</tipage>
    <time type="date">08.04.2013 16:22:29 EDT</time>
    <wbmain_flyout-tools-webench>0</wbmain_flyout-tools-webench>
    <usertype>Anonymous</usertype>
    <s_sq>[[B]]</s_sq>
    <hopsession>10.247.21.1ry3hnmevb1u9</hopsession>
    <ticontent>/TIDN</ticontent>
    <body> &lt;h2&gt;The Original Question&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;h3&gt;What could you create with a board based on the highest performance ARM system-on-chip available today…&lt;/h3&gt; If it was small enough to fit in the palm of your hand, and powered via USB? This question inspired the creation of the original BeagleBoard and the subsequent Beagle generations: lean, open source development and education projects that enable innovators to collaborate on the latest silicon technology. As low-cost, fan-less computers with all the expandability of today&apos;s desktop machines but without the bulk, expense or noise, the Beagles are a platform on which versatile computer science solutions can be developed for almost any application.&lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;h2&gt;Doing More with Less&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;By eliminating all of the on-board peripherals not already among the numerous ones inherent in the digital and analog system-on-chip pair themselves, and by providing standard expansion buses (like high-speed USB 2.0, SDIO, and DVI-D) developers are empowered to add and combine their own peripherals of choice. Instead of a fixed, embedded LCD, the Beagles feature digital and analog LCD ports to add monitor/TV connections, so that any DVI-D enabled monitor or S-Video enabled TV is a possibility. The USB port can be utilized to add a high-speed hub for a keyboard, mouse, and WiFi connection, and the MMC/SD connector can be used to add multiple gigabytes of storage. Building a computer out of a Beagle is just the beginning.
 &lt;/p&gt;

 &lt;h2&gt;Collaborating on the Beagles&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;In keeping with the idea of supporting standard interfaces and allowing users to innovate , those who would like to collaborate on extending the Beagle platform are encouraged to do it in any way possible. Instead of controlling community activity by pushing a single collaboration portal, Beagle developers are encouraged to take their contributions directly to the communities already supporting the project they desire to port to the Beagles, or to create their own community collaboration tools using existing offerings at &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.google.com/&quot;&gt;code.google.com&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://sourceforge.net/&quot;&gt;sf.net&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.freedesktop.org/&quot;&gt;freedesktop.org&lt;/a&gt;, etc.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;It is certainly true that by encouraging Beagle collaboration in every direction, there will be fragmentation within the community. Participants are therefore encouraged to do three things:&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
   Register their project at
   &lt;a href=&quot;http://beagleboard.org/project&quot;&gt;BeagleBoard.org/project&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
   Provide information about their project using one of the
   &lt;a href=&quot;http://creativecommons.org&quot;&gt;Creative Commons&lt;/a&gt; licenses
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Publish RSS/Atom feeds that can be used to update their project status&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The web software required to aggregate information about these projects, including their release announcements, bug reports, and discussion links, are all built using widely-adopted standards (such as RSS and Atom) as an open source project of its own that is executed on the BeagleBoard.org server.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Developers are welcome and encouraged to take the server build script for Amazon EC2 servers and website source to improve upon the aggregation capabilities of the site.
&lt;h2&gt;What Can the Beagles Do?&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The general-purpose processor performance of the Beagle exceeds that of other low-cost computing platforms on the market today. Additionally, the processor contains 2D and 3D graphics acceleration capabilities as well as a DSP optimized for multimedia processing in the older generations. A typical configuration of a Beagle system draws power from a USB port on a standard laptop or desktop PC used for developing and downloading the low-level Beagle software, but additional peripherals allow the Beagles to operate as multimedia computers on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h3&gt;Possible Beagle Applications&lt;/h3&gt;
 &lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robotics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Low-cost Linux PC&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Network-Connected Digital Signage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3D User-Interface Development (Clutter, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Game Console&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LCD-to-Picture-Frame Conversion Kit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Talk Video Phone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gaming Platform Emulator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thin Client Terminal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vehicle Telematics and Automation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Software Defined Radio&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;GMobile Digital Television&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thin client terminal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web browser for the TV&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Multimedia codec and framework development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Home Networked Media (DLNA/XMPP) Server/Client&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and anything else that YOU can dream up...&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;/ul&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;Can I Get a Beagle?&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;h3&gt;
  Beagles are available for purchase at 
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://beagleboard.org/buy&quot;&gt;Beagleboard.org/buy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  If you’re an advanced user, you are invited to utilize all of the &lt;a href=&quot;http://beagleboard.org/hardware&quot;&gt;Beagle design materials&lt;/a&gt;. This includes electronic copies of the schematic, layout, and assembly designs. All of the Texas Instruments components utilized on the board are available for public purchase. Information on manufacturers capable of producing Beagles is provided on the third party page.
 &lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;h2&gt;Using Beagles for Fun, Education, Profit&lt;/h2&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Beagles are intended for learning about the construction of embedded systems and without the support or costs associated with commercial development platforms. After experimentation is finished, software compatible silicon evaluation platforms to develop a product are available.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;
  --
  &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.hangerhead.com/&quot;&gt;Jason Kridner&lt;/a&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
</body>
    <pathbytype>Anonymous:/training/arm/all subtopics/all types/allregions/allcountries/allcities/all types  next 30 days - en</pathbytype>
    <hqs>arm</hqs>
    <ev63>dsps_arm_102109</ev63>
    <s_ppv>/tidn/ti%20design%20network%20-%20en,83,83,933</s_ppv>
    <gpn>Non-Product</gpn>
    <http_referer>http://ims-mm01.am.dhcp.ti.com:5001/brief/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>ims-mm01.am.dhcp.ti.com:5001</http_host>
    <ap_cookie_en>computerId-C_EN_152046639&amp;expiryDate-1396730279926&amp;lastVisitedDate-1365194279926&amp;createdDate-1364997123797&amp;</ap_cookie_en>
    <lang>en-us</lang>
    <user>rachelmarionball@gmail.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
