<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="helma.xsl"?>
<xmlroot xmlns:hop="http://www.helma.org/docs/guide/features/database">
  <hopobject id="848" name="hbp" prototype="Page" created="1257353058285" lastModified="1443067482198">
  <hop:parent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <is_xhtml type="boolean">true</is_xhtml>
    <http_remotehost>127.0.0.1</http_remotehost>
    <pname>Home-Brew SmartPhone</pname>
    <registrant>lkcl.myopenid.com</registrant>
    <http_language>en-us,en;q=0.5</http_language>
    <uri>hbp</uri>
    <http_browser>Mozilla/5.0 (X11; U; Linux i686 (x86_64); en-US; rv:1.8.1.14) Gecko/20080404 Iceweasel/2.0.0.14 (Debian-2.0.0.14-2)</http_browser>
    <time type="date">04.11.2009 16:49:52 UTC</time>
    <updatetime type="date">04.11.2009 16:44:18 UTC</updatetime>
    <hopsession>127.0.0.217.147.94.1u3rtcawm1bdy</hopsession>
    <body>
 Beagleboards with 512mb of RAM and 600mhz CPUs are powerful enough to be Desktop PCs: they&apos;re also small enough to be portable.  With modular pre-certified cellphone components from Telit such as the GE862, the opencellphone project proved in 2006 that it is possible to create your own mobile phone.  The HBP/D aims to build on the prior success of that project and the success of the Hy Research MID project, to create a powerful and open smartphone project.
 &lt;p&gt;The Telit UC-864-G is the most likely candidate as the radio module, thanks to it supporting Quad-band GSM, Tri-band 3G/HSDPA, and having A-GPS all in the same compact space.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The fact that Telit&apos;s documentation is publicly available without requiring an NDA, including full application notes, full hardware and full software disclosure, including the &quot;Digital Voice&quot; Codec AT command-set, makes Telit&apos;s excellent products an easy choice.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;Learning the lessons from HTC smartphone and iPaq PDA reverse-engineering, the Trolltech Greenphone, the OpenMoko, the myPhone, the opencellphone and from a proprietary ARM+GPS+GPRS product, the HBP/D will be an open project from the ground up.&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;p&gt;The initial focus will be to get incoming and outgoing phone calls up-and-running as soon as practical, so that software developers can engage with the project at a very early stage.&lt;/p&gt;
</body>
    <pseudoparent idref="20" prototyperef="Page"/>
    <rssfeed></rssfeed>
    <pvcount type="float">3287.0</pvcount>
    <homepage>http://lkcl.net/projects/hbp</homepage>
    <render_skin>project</render_skin>
    <edit_skin>edit_project</edit_skin>
    <http_referer>http://beagleboard.org/project/hbp/edit</http_referer>
    <http_host>beagleboard.org</http_host>
    <errmsg></errmsg>
    <shortdesc>The HomeBrew SmartPhone is a project to create a community-buildable mobile phone that is powerful enough to also run as a Desktop PC.</shortdesc>
    <user>lkcl.myopenid.com</user>
  </hopobject>
</xmlroot>
